DM: technically and more sort of,
c00002
DM: I mean, mechanically I think you have.
c00003
Delwath: There's not... It's actually true, there's not-
c00004
Unknown: There's not a-
c00005
Delwath: ... a super clear sense of like-
c00006
Unknown: Yeah
c00007
Delwath: ... the actual relationships between our characters.
c00008
Delwath: Like what are they actually-
c00009
Kenzo: Well, so I kind of-
c00010
Seeker: Like a little rivalry.
c00011
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, that's what I was gonna say. I, I was gonna say, so one of the funnest shit was like when, uh, when Seeker and, and um, and Kenzo were, we were like throwing eggs at each other and like kind of fighting and having like little piece of chat like.
c00012
Unknown: Yeah.
c00013
Kenzo: Or even, or even like, uh, um, Kenzo-
c00014
DM: There's the little Kenzo, Ja-
c00015
Kenzo: The Kenzo, Delwath thing, which has also like been fun, like the whole-
c00016
Unknown: But I think it's-
c00017
Kenzo: But yeah, those aren't like-
c00018
Delwath: It's, it's lightly developed compared to many other aspects of the-
c00019
Unknown: Yeah.
c00020
DM: Yeah
c00021
Unknown: ... of the game.
c00022
Seeker: Yeah. So we could lean into that more if we want to, to get more of that.
c00023
DM: But partly, I, I think that's partly because of the epic scale, right?
c00024
DM: It's harder to do that when,
c00025
DM: when you're... When the adventures are-
c00026
Delwath: See, I think it's partly because we play-
c00027
Unknown: Yeah, that's true
c00028
Delwath: ... a huge amount of our game between 10:00 PM and midnight-
c00029
DM: That's also true
c00030
Seeker: ... on a weeknight.
c00031
Delwath: I just, I think it's, I find it a lot harder to-
c00032
Seeker: Oh, you're just more tired, it's hard for-
c00033
Unknown: Yeah.
c00034
DM: Everybody's tired.
c00035
Delwath: It's just, it's easier to think in...
c00036
Delwath: It's a lot easier to think as Mike as Delwath than as Delwath.
c00037
Seeker: Right.
c00038
DM: Yeah.
c00039
Delwath: And I find it harder to...
c00040
Unknown: It's more work.
c00041
DM: But that's, I mean, we don't have much choice.
c00042
Unknown: Yeah.
c00043
DM: I mean, at some point everybody's kids will be old enough that we can play at 6:00, but not for a campaign three, maybe campaign four.
c00044
Seeker: Yeah. [laughs] It's gonna be a while.
c00045
Kenzo: Man, dude, five kids, that's just gonna get all fucked up.
c00046
DM: Yeah.
c00047
Seeker: But we'll deal with it.
c00048
DM: Yeah.
c00049
Unknown: Yeah.
c00050
Seeker: I appreciate the flexibility, honestly.
c00051
Kenzo: No, that's great.
c00052
DM: Yeah.
c00053
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c00054
Delwath: Um, so I just think there's certain, there's certain things that are hard to achieve-
c00055
DM: Right
c00056
Delwath: ... just because of the
c00057
Unknown: nature of-
c00058
DM: The time, when we can play. Yeah
c00059
DM: ... when we play and who we are and just how it, right.
c00060
Seeker: Well, role playing feels quite different in person too.
c00061
Unknown: Also.
c00062
DM: Right. It's nicer in person, for one.
c00063
Unknown: Yeah.
c00064
c00065
Wellby: Uh, the combat is a lot more enjoyable in person.
c00066
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00067
DM: Mm-hmm.
c00068
Wellby: Yeah. I, like I, I feel like that's part of like me dropping last night.
c00069
Wellby: Like part of what felt so unpleasant to go down in combat online is like-
c00070
Seeker: You can't do anything
c00071
Wellby: ... you're just sitting there.
c00072
DM: Right.
c00073
Wellby: Like there's so little... Like I still felt so engaged in this.
c00074
DM: Yes.
c00075
DM: You're not as engaged.
c00076
Wellby: In a way that it just wasn't...
c00077
Delwath: It is true that in-person combat, I mean, that's part of what I think...
c00078
Delwath: I was thinking about
c00079
Delwath: our most, like almost all of our best combats have been on
c00080
Delwath: in person.
c00081
Seeker: Yeah.
c00082
Unknown: In our in person.
c00083
Seeker: I mean, it's partly 'cause Tim plans an even more epic thing than usual.
c00084
DM: Right. But it's also just,
c00085
DM: it's just a lot easier to run-
c00086
Unknown: Yeah
c00087
DM: ... in person because it's not as...
c00088
DM: I think there's just also something about having a physical battle map that's-
c00089
Delwath: Well, I also think there's something about seeing...
c00090
Delwath: There's a lot of like watching what other people roll.
c00091
Seeker: Right.
c00092
Unknown: Yeah.
c00093
Unknown: There's a lot of-
c00094
Seeker: That's exciting too, yeah
c00095
Delwath: ... like, like every time Seeker was rolling a concentration check.
c00096
Unknown: [laughs]
c00097
DM: [laughs]
c00098
Unknown: Oh yeah, that's fun.
c00099
Delwath: We're all like watching with bated breath.
c00100
Kenzo: Yeah, that's so fun.
c00101
DM: That was great.
c00102
Delwath: And you lose that.
c00103
Unknown: Yeah.
c00104
Delwath: You lose that when you're online.
c00105
Unknown: Yeah.
c00106
Delwath: Because you're not really...
c00107
Seeker: Yeah.
c00108
Wellby: I think it's also easier for like side conversations to happen.
c00109
DM: Right.
c00110
Unknown: Like online-
c00111
Seeker: You can't really
c00112
Wellby: ... only two people can be talking really.
c00113
DM: Right.
c00114
Seeker: Yeah. Right.
c00115
Wellby: Turn and DM.
c00116
Seeker: Yeah.
c00117
DM: Well,
c00118
DM: until we have...
c00119
Kenzo: Yeah. Until our neu- our, our neural links and the telepresence, you know.
c00120
Seeker: Yeah. When we're all playing Apple Vision Pro.
c00121
Seeker: [coughs] Actually, there is an AR platform for gaming.
c00122
Seeker: What's that thing called? Have you seen this?
c00123
Seeker: It's a former Media Lab person's startup thing.
c00124
Delwath: Do, do you know if there's any VTT that rolls dice visibly on the table?
c00125
DM: So you can do it in both D&...
c00126
DM: You can do it in Roll20. You can roll dice on the table in Roll20.
c00127
Kenzo: Oh, really? Where they just show up, where they visibly show up for everybody?
c00128
DM: Yeah.
c00129
Delwath: I actually think that would be worth trying.
c00130
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00131
DM: So I actually thought, I've considered, it's more work, but maybe I'll have time to do it.
c00132
DM: Kind...
c00133
DM: Looking at other virtual tabletops that might be more
c00134
DM: amenable to some of these things.
c00135
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00136
DM: Like, because part of the...
c00137
DM: One of the things that makes combat s- slow on l- it, what it...
c00138
DM: Less engaging because everything's, you know, you're not there, but also, like, there's like a second delay every time you click a button on-
c00139
Unknown: Right
c00140
DM: ... D&D Beyond before it shows up in Roll20.
c00141
DM: I mean, it's, the connection is nice, but it's not perfect, and the...
c00142
DM: You know, you just have to go so many places on your character sheet to click things.
c00143
Unknown: Yeah.
c00144
Seeker: Yeah.
c00145
DM: That it kind of slows things down.
c00146
Seeker: I kind of hate D&D Beyond.
c00147
Seeker: Um, I-
c00148
Unknown: I don't like it
c00149
Seeker: ... don't feel like I have an alternative, but.
c00150
Delwath: D&D Beyond is...
c00151
Seeker: It's just, it feels complicated, and it's probably 'cause it is complicated.
c00152
DM: Yeah.
c00153
Delwath: D&D Beyond's complicated.
c00154
Delwath: I actually looked at alternatives.
c00155
Delwath: I actually, for the game I'm running, I use something called Dice Cloud, which is a alternative.
c00156
DM: Hmm.
c00157
Delwath: But it's more complicated.
c00158
Delwath: It's, it's, it's-
c00159
Delwath: Dice Cloud, Dice Cloud is really, really good for home brewing.
c00160
DM: You can home brew anything-
c00161
Unknown: Mm.
c00162
DM: ... super, super easily.
c00163
Delwath: But the actual UI is actually worse than D&D Beyond.
c00164
Seeker: Right. That's, that's the issue for me is that, like, maybe it's just the nature of my character.
c00165
Seeker: There's so many interesting details, some of which are D&D things, some of which are made by Tim that I have to, like, keep track of or look up every-
c00166
Delwath: So, I mean, this is the nice thing about Dice Cloud.
c00167
Delwath: Dice Cloud is actually, uh, open.
c00168
Delwath: I mean, it's, you can run your own dice.
c00169
Unknown: Like, it's a JavaScript app.
c00170
Seeker: Oh, nice.
c00171
Delwath: At one point I was like, I should just fix it.
c00172
Delwath: I should just make it... 'Cause it, it does a terrible job of putting the information you want in one spot.
c00173
Seeker: Mm.
c00174
DM: So Roll20, I mean, Roll20 has a lot of potential for this because you can...
c00175
DM: It has a, it has an API.
c00176
DM: You can write arbitrary JavaScript code that runs.
c00177
Delwath: But, but see, I actually think what you want is something less.
c00178
Delwath: To me- What is cool about in person is that you're spending less time looking at your character sheet and more time looking at the combat.
c00179
DM: Yeah.
c00180
Delwath: D&D Be- like online, you're very encouraged to tune out when other people are-
c00181
DM: But what I'm-
c00182
Unknown: Yeah
c00183
DM: ... what I would try, the thing that is potentially possible to do is,
c00184
DM: um, Kate also hates this because it also is really, if you're only playing on one screen, it's really annoying to have Roll20, D&D Beyond, and DM-
c00185
Unknown: Yeah
c00186
DM: ... all up at once.
c00187
Unknown: Yeah.
c00188
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c00189
Unknown: Yep.
c00190
DM: So to the extent to which you could move everything to basically just be Roll20.
c00191
Seeker: Oh, because that has video conferencing?
c00192
DM: The video conferencing used to suck.
c00193
DM: It might be better now.
c00194
Unknown: Better.
c00195
DM: Um, Zo- I mean, Zoom is, the advantage of Zoom is you get the recording and the transcripts.
c00196
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00197
Seeker: Have you, have you...
c00198
Delwath: Is Discord not good for...?
c00199
DM: Well, Isaac uses Discord.
c00200
DM: Discord's fine,
c00201
DM: but you don't get a transcript.
c00202
Unknown: Right.
c00203
Seeker: Mm.
c00204
Delwath: But one thing you c- I mean, what you could do is actually do-
c00205
Delwath: Just 'cause Discord had DD bots built in.
c00206
DM: Right. You could do audio-
c00207
Unknown: Uh
c00208
DM: ... on Zoom and video on Roll20.
c00209
DM: And then you could just-
c00210
Seeker: And just run it in the background, yeah
c00211
DM: ... then you could just have Zoom minimized in the background.
c00212
DM: And
c00213
DM: if you could, if you could automate enough things so that it was easy for you to, like, if you had little buttons to, like, it's really annoying, like, to roll dice
c00214
DM: in Roll20 that are visual dice.
c00215
DM: You have to, like, click on the menu-
c00216
Unknown: Click, yeah
c00217
DM: ... and then select the dice you want to roll.
c00218
Unknown: Yeah.
c00219
DM: But if you had buttons that were just like D20 with advan- D- two D20, one D20,
c00220
DM: you know.
c00221
Seeker: Yeah, like favorite dice.
c00222
DM: Favorite dice, then you could just click the button and it would roll on the tabletop, and then you would just need,
c00223
DM: like, a way to...
c00224
DM: But if everybody just used, have your D&D Beyond character sheet on your
c00225
DM: phone, if you had to look stuff up.
c00226
Unknown: Ooh.
c00227
DM: The other option is, like, it's more money, but, like, if, you know, I spend 100 bucks or 120 bucks to buy the books in Roll20 in addition to on D&D Beyond,
c00228
DM: then you'd have, you could have all of the spells and stuff just show up as buttons in Roll20, so it would give you the
c00229
DM: spell information. You wouldn't have to reference it on your-
c00230
Delwath: I actually think the thing that would make
c00231
Delwath: combat online, the one thing that would make it more engaging would be to be rolling dice in public on the table.
c00232
DM: Right.
c00233
Delwath: Quickly. Like, w- ideally with not, like, some super long animation, but with a little bit of an animation.
c00234
DM: Yeah, so that-
c00235
Unknown: So that you can never really see-
c00236
DM: But that's the nice thing about Roll-
c00237
Unknown: Yeah
c00238
DM: ... Roll20 is, like, completely custom.
c00239
DM: You could, I could, I mean, ChatGPT or Claude or some agent mode could write a script that would generate buttons for common dice combos.
c00240
Seeker: Yeah.
c00241
DM: With animation tunes so that it-
c00242
Unknown: Right
c00243
DM: ... didn't take-
c00244
Unknown: Right
c00245
DM: ... 20 seconds to roll.
c00246
Unknown: [clears throat]
c00247
DM: It took two seconds to roll.
c00248
Seeker: That'd be good.
c00249
Kenzo: Eric, sorry, when you say, like, you hate D&D, uh, Beyond, are you talking about the UI or you talking about, like, the whole gaming system in general?
c00250
Seeker: D- so D&D Beyond as a user interface to access parts of your character sheet.
c00251
DM: Yeah.
c00252
Kenzo: I see, I see. Okay.
c00253
Wellby: Because everything relevant is in a tiny little tabbed window in a quarter of the screen.
c00254
DM: And it's also spread out all over the place.
c00255
Seeker: And I need to look, go back and forth between looking at two different things, which means, like, it's-
c00256
Unknown: Yep
c00257
Seeker: ... five or six clicks.
c00258
DM: Yep.
c00259
Unknown: Yeah.
c00260
Seeker: And so what I end up doing-
c00261
DM: Yes
c00262
Seeker: ... is, like, instead of looking at my spells inside D&D Beyond, I search for them on Google.
c00263
Unknown: Yep.
c00264
Seeker: Pull 'em up on some unrelated site, and then-
c00265
DM: Right
c00266
Seeker: ... open it in a tab, and maybe it's, like, the wrong version of the spell.
c00267
Unknown: Yeah.
c00268
Seeker: So it's, like, it's terrible.
c00269
DM: It is. It's really not great.
c00270
DM: Got it, got it, got it.
c00271
DM: 'Cause the way, I mean, the, the way the UI desi- is designed with all these, like, pop-ups that, you know, pop-outs from the edge.
c00272
DM: But there's, like, so many different tabs you have to click.
c00273
DM: You can't get...
c00274
Delwath: But it's also-
c00275
Seeker: Yeah
c00276
Delwath: ... it does a terrible job at...
c00277
Delwath: It, it's just, like, I find it impossible to use to keep track of stuff.
c00278
Unknown: Like, I always wind up ticking off-
c00279
Seeker: Yeah, like the one thing it should do-
c00280
Unknown: It should be-
c00281
Seeker: ... is help you temporarily check things off.
c00282
DM: Correct. [laughs]
c00283
Unknown: Yes.
c00284
Seeker: Quickly during a combat.
c00285
DM: Yeah.
c00286
Unknown: It is awful.
c00287
Seeker: And that's the hardest thing to do.
c00288
Unknown: Yes.
c00289
Seeker: And also it feels unreliable because there's, like, five different ways to cast a spell, and some of them t- check off the spell slots and some don't.
c00290
Seeker: And it's like, remember-
c00291
DM: Yeah, yeah. No, it's, I tried to-
c00292
Seeker: So it doesn't do that at all. [laughs]
c00293
DM: Yeah.
c00294
Delwath: Right. But then I forget how many sorcery points I've used.
c00295
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c00296
DM: Right. So that's the other thing about, so you could make buttons in D&D Beyond, I mean in Roll20, that you just click every time you use a key or every time you use a sorcery point, and it just, it just
c00297
DM: clicks and it just-
c00298
Seeker: Yeah
c00299
DM: ... DM-
c00300
Delwath: That's kind of what Dice Cloud is actually good at too.
c00301
Delwath: Like, I...
c00302
Delwath: The Dice Cloud UI is kind of crap.
c00303
Seeker: Right.
c00304
Delwath: But it's very good at automating.
c00305
Delwath: It's like a, a system that makes it easy to automate.
c00306
DM: Right. I mean, the one that everybody online says is the best for automation is Foundry.
c00307
DM: It's just, um,
c00308
DM: it's
c00309
DM: really difficult to set up because-
c00310
Unknown: Mm
c00311
DM: ... it's like Dice Cloud. It's like, it has a, it ha- it's a very flexible back end that you can design anything you want in, but
c00312
DM: you just have to spend a lot of time setting it up, and then you can automate things.
c00313
Seeker: Yeah.
c00314
DM: I mean, I do like, the thing I like on Roll20 is, like, the spell templates that let you immediately get the area of a spell-
c00315
Seeker: Right
c00316
DM: ... without having to spend a long time discussing, like-
c00317
Unknown: Mm
c00318
DM: ... what's in or out.
c00319
Wellby: Yeah. I feel like that, that was the one piece of combat that's trickier analog.
c00320
DM: Yes.
c00321
Seeker: Yeah.
c00322
Wellby: Is to be able to just draw up-
c00323
DM: Yes
c00324
Wellby: ... and reposition-
c00325
DM: Right
c00326
Unknown: ... radiuses and things.
c00327
Seeker: I do like drawing stuff on the map.
c00328
Unknown: Yeah.
c00329
Seeker: That's fun.
c00330
Unknown: Yeah.
c00331
DM: But I think I, I'm gonna, I'm gonna investigate this for-
c00332
Delwath: The, the other thing to think about, even the things that feel like, oh, you have to build that.
c00333
Delwath: Like, I was like, "Oh, Dice Cloud's gonna be a lot of work," 'cause I switched my game to Dice Cloud because I'd home-brewed.
c00334
Unknown: I had
c00335
Delwath: home-brewed a custom [coughs] subclass for basically everybody.
c00336
Seeker: Right.
c00337
Delwath: And like, I just couldn't...
c00338
Kenzo: The D&D Beyond home-brewing stuff is just too painful.
c00339
Delwath: I couldn't deal with it.
c00340
Unknown: So
c00341
Delwath: I was like, "Oh, but this is gonna be annoying. I'm gonna have to, like, im- create everything from scratch."
c00342
Delwath: But actually you only have to create the stuff from scratch for- ...
c00343
Delwath: the things you're actually using, right?
c00344
Unknown: So it's actually not that much work.
c00345
DM: Yeah, I mean, that's like when I made all the spells in D&D Beyond, it took me
c00346
DM: a couple of hours to do all the spells that you could use.
c00347
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00348
DM: It would've taken days to do all the spells-
c00349
Unknown: Right
c00350
DM: ... in the game.
c00351
Unknown: Right.
c00352
Unknown: Mm.
c00353
DM: But that's what I'm thinking, like if we go back to a, if we do some lower level stuff-
c00354
Unknown: If-
c00355
DM: ... I can start a fresh-
c00356
Unknown: Mm
c00357
DM: ... level 20 campaign and just build up the things that are actually-
c00358
Unknown: It's relevant
c00359
DM: ... needed for the low level campaign, and it's much easier than trying to switch when you're level 20.
c00360
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c00361
Unknown: Yeah, there's too many things.
c00362
DM: When you have 100 million things you can do.
c00363
Delwath: Right. No, no, for, for these characters-
c00364
DM: Yeah
c00365
Delwath: ... I wouldn't.
c00366
Seeker: How do you think of the role of Taelgarverse in all of this?
c00367
Seeker: It's kind of alongside the mechanical stuff.
c00368
Unknown: Dude, totally.
c00369
Seeker: But we use it all the time as part of the game, which is great.
c00370
Seeker: So it's essentially like just an archive of-
c00371
DM: [coughs]
c00372
Unknown: I mean-
c00373
Unknown: ... world
c00374
Delwath: ... I was gonna say earlier about the, about the other thing, my actual favorite thing in the game is world building.
c00375
Unknown: Mm.
c00376
DM: Right.
c00377
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c00378
Delwath: And even more, I love it when Tim uses my world building in this campaign.
c00379
Unknown: [laughs]
c00380
DM: Yeah.
c00381
Unknown: Yeah. Hmm.
c00382
Unknown: I think
c00383
Wellby: for me, like part of the reality is like s- some of the stuff...
c00384
Wellby: I remember, I mean, this is a long time ago now, us walking around in the woods talking about like halfling things in California, right?
c00385
Kenzo: Oh, shit, that was awesome.
c00386
Kenzo: Like three or four years ago now.
c00387
Kenzo: That, that's when we came up with the whole like, uh, like the halflings, they just have one song.
c00388
Unknown: Yeah.
c00389
Wellby: And like that whole... Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
c00390
Wellby: And like, and like that's
c00391
Wellby: so fun, but also the reality is like
c00392
Wellby: I don't set aside time to do that.
c00393
Wellby: Uh, like the sessions are sort of like-
c00394
Unknown: Right
c00395
Wellby: ... are my D&D time.
c00396
Unknown: Mm.
c00397
Unknown: Like-
c00398
Seeker: Right, right, right
c00399
Wellby: ... I wonder if there's a way within it to-
c00400
DM: So it's tricky.
c00401
Unknown: Hmm.
c00402
DM: So Mike's players like-
c00403
Unknown: Good question
c00404
DM: ... spend hours sending each other emails about world building.
c00405
DM: The problem with doing it during a session is what's nice about world building is being able to sort of test out ideas without having to commit to something, but it's...
c00406
DM: And like explore ideas, and then you figure out what makes sense-
c00407
Unknown: Yeah
c00408
DM: ... by talking about it. But-
c00409
Unknown: But the-
c00410
DM: ... in a session you feel a little bit of pressure to-
c00411
Wellby: Move the plot forward.
c00412
Seeker: Oh, there is that too.
c00413
DM: Well, not just move the plot forward, but to not like be constantly retconning things, right?
c00414
Unknown: Right.
c00415
DM: So if you, if I like say make up something about halflings, you're sort of on the spot to do something that actually seems perfect in that moment.
c00416
Wellby: Yeah. I, so I agree, like when it's, if it's right in, in the middle of like, "You open a door," and meet a halfling, like-
c00417
DM: Right
c00418
Wellby: ... tell me about the role of like bar keepers and [laughs] half-
c00419
DM: Yeah.
c00420
Unknown: Like,
c00421
Wellby: but there's gotta be other ways to do that.
c00422
Wellby: Like, what if that's the warm-up before the session starts?
c00423
Unknown: Mm.
c00424
Wellby: Like, we have like-
c00425
DM: Right
c00426
Wellby: ... 30 minutes of world building and three questions.
c00427
DM: I mean, that's great if you all would actually join the Zoom at 8:00.
c00428
Unknown: Yeah.
c00429
DM: It's just, we just have so...
c00430
DM: There's just not very much time, right?
c00431
Unknown: Yeah.
c00432
DM: So like already we often-
c00433
Seeker: But we could devote part of the time to that.
c00434
Wellby: But also, like if-
c00435
Unknown: If we want to do that
c00436
Wellby: ... if the goal is enjoying ourselves-
c00437
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah
c00438
Wellby: ... and this is as enjoyable as moving the thing forward, like we-
c00439
DM: I mean-
c00440
DM: No, no, no, I get that. I think-
c00441
Delwath: Making up the Maw or Sentient Ocean was also super fun.
c00442
DM: Was awesome. We were just driving around in the Tesla.
c00443
DM: We were driving around. Yeah.
c00444
Unknown: Making it up.
c00445
DM: You guys. So I think the challenge is when you, when se- when you get a session below about three hours, it's tricky because-
c00446
Unknown: Yeah
c00447
Delwath: ... you either, you basically either can't run a, a combat.
c00448
Unknown: Yeah.
c00449
DM: Or it's sort of like, it's hard to sort of have multiple scenes.
c00450
DM: And so if you...
c00451
Unknown: [coughs]
c00452
DM: Now, one thing we could explore is like playing more frequently, but for much shorter times, like two and a half hour sessions
c00453
DM: more frequently rather than trying to do three and a half hour sessions less frequently.
c00454
DM: Or we could alternate, right? You could have some short sessions and some...
c00455
DM: I mean, there's various things we could do.
c00456
Delwath: Well, 'cause what, would a, would a shorter session, you would just run one scene a session basically?
c00457
DM: You wouldn't, y- it wouldn't matter so much if a combat takes the whole session, right?
c00458
DM: It's kind of frustrating if-
c00459
Unknown: Hmm
c00460
DM: ... anything other than a boss fight, if combat takes the whole time.
c00461
Unknown: Yeah.
c00462
Unknown: Right.
c00463
DM: But if you're running short, if you're, if you have two hours of gameplay, you can basically run two encounters, or an encounter is a scene, right?
c00464
Unknown: Yeah.
c00465
DM: Like two scenes, right? So you can actually-
c00466
Seeker: Part of that's just about speeding up. I mean, I think-
c00467
DM: Part of it's speeding combat up
c00468
Delwath: ... lower level combat would be way faster, lower level.
c00469
Delwath: There's also, there's also work everybody could do.
c00470
DM: I know, but I'm not... Like I'm being realistic about the amount of work these Targos.
c00471
Delwath: Well, but I actually think there's tool...
c00472
Delwath: Like, again, if you look at the tooling, combat would be a lot faster if the mechanism by which everybody was presented with options was-
c00473
DM: Was not so-
c00474
DM: ... a lot more straightforward.
c00475
DM: Yeah. Kate hates that about D&D Beyond.
c00476
DM: It's like I can never figure out what I can do because it's on five different tabs.
c00477
Unknown: Exactly.
c00478
Unknown: This is in a way the same-
c00479
Unknown: Yeah
c00480
Unknown: ... concern I had.
c00481
Delwath: Right. And so if you knew what you can do in combat, right, in a much more condensed way, you would be much more likely to...
c00482
Delwath: 'Cause in the ideal situation in combat, it's like actually it moves pretty quickly.
c00483
DM: Yeah.
c00484
Unknown: Yeah.
c00485
Unknown: Right?
c00486
Kenzo: Combats are too long, man. Like, so some of the combats, like they dr- they like, I would gladly sacrifice like a big, a big chunk of like the combat time to do like the world building thing.
c00487
DM: Yeah.
c00488
Kenzo: I would gladly do that.
c00489
Unknown: Yeah.
c00490
Delwath: But part of the challenge is that D&D is very much structured as a combat system, and so a lot of your character abilities are actually only relevant in combat.
c00491
Unknown: Right.
c00492
DM: Well, I, I mean, this has not been a very high combat campaign.
c00493
Unknown: No.
c00494
DM: To me, it's sort of not like, I mean, the...
c00495
DM: Fundamentally, you're gonna go explore dungeons and fight dragons, right?
c00496
Unknown: [laughs]
c00497
DM: That's the name of the game. I mean-
c00498
Unknown: That is likely to be involved somewhere.
c00499
Delwath: And to me, there's an extent to which, you know, you level up and you get some cool new ability.
c00500
Unknown: You wanna use your ability.
c00501
DM: And you then wanna use it-
c00502
Unknown: Right
c00503
Delwath: ... 'cause it's, otherwise it's like...
c00504
DM: [laughs]
c00505
Unknown: Yeah.
c00506
c00507
DM: Right? Speaking of long combats, it's 1:00.
c00508
Unknown: Right.
c00509
Seeker: Oh, I gotta eat some lunch.
c00510
DM: Uh-
c00511
Delwath: Yeah, we should like-
c00512
DM: ... do like Who's to Kill?
c00513
Delwath: We should go play D&D instead of talking about this.
c00514
Unknown: Yeah.
c00515
Delwath: We can talk about it next time.
c00516
DM: We can revisit this while we're cooking dinner and-
c00517
Unknown: Yeah
c00518
DM: ... watching the sunset and a- you know, during and after the game as well.
c00519
Delwath: I mean, what I actually think is interesting, just one thought.
c00520
Delwath: What's interesting with this conversation and your desire to not start something, just actually why don't we just ex- like-
c00521
DM: We can try a whole bunch of things
c00522
Delwath: ... we can try all kinds of different things in the next year, right?
c00523
Unknown: Like-
c00524
Seeker: Well, the timeline building game, what was that?
c00525
DM: Oh, that was fun.
c00526
Unknown: Speaking of.
c00527
Kenzo: Oh, um, uh, Microscope?
c00528
DM: Microscope.
c00529
Unknown: Macroscope.
c00530
DM: Yeah. Mic- It was called Microscope.
c00531
Unknown: Oh.
c00532
Unknown: Yeah.
c00533
DM: [coughs]
c00534
Kenzo: Uh, and really quick just 'cause I- I was, I started recording this so later on we can like try to be like, "Hey, what were we talking about?
c00535
Unknown: The things we-"
c00536
Unknown: Yeah.
c00537
Kenzo: So, but, uh, so plot twists.
c00538
Kenzo: Uh, like unexpected plot twists are for satisfying-
c00539
Seeker: Storytelling mechanics.
c00540
Unknown: Stor-
c00541
DM: Mm-hmm
c00542
Kenzo: ... storytelling mechanics.
c00543
Unknown: Where like-
c00544
Seeker: Where like you make up things in order to solve problems.
c00545
DM: Right.
c00546
Kenzo: Right, right. What were the other bits?
c00547
Unknown: Does-
c00548
DM: Uh-
c00549
Wellby: Creepy fairy tale stuff instead of-
c00550
DM: Right
c00551
Unknown: ... dice stuff.
c00552
Delwath: And things where the wrong choice, not the wrong die roll.
c00553
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
c00554
Seeker: Mm-hmm. And generally world building is part of-
c00555
DM: And world building
c00556
Seeker: ... the experience.
c00557
Unknown: Right, right.
c00558
Seeker: We like. What else? Like
c00559
Seeker: fun role playing vignettes.
c00560
Kenzo: Yes, with the characters get to do-
c00561
Unknown: Yeah
c00562
Kenzo: ... like in a fun little-
c00563
DM: Yeah. I'm... So actually, I, thinking about, not to distract, but thinking about the warm-ups a little bit.
c00564
DM: I did at one point try that, like everybody describe-
c00565
Unknown: Oh, yeah
c00566
DM: ... their character warm-up.
c00567
DM: Which-
c00568
Delwath: It never really worked though
c00569
DM: ... well, you guys never really-
c00570
Unknown: Right
c00571
DM: ... people didn't really do it.
c00572
DM: And, and, um-
c00573
Wellby: For some reason it wasn't the right thing for us.
c00574
Unknown: Yeah.
c00575
Delwath: Like the first couple of times-
c00576
Unknown: They picked at you
c00577
Wellby: ... after... And after doing it once or twice, it's sort of like-
c00578
DM: But, but actually-
c00579
Unknown: It took a little something to get
c00580
DM: ... so this, I'm thinking about this, right?
c00581
DM: Like, I still don't... I mean, I can picture Wellby and Seeker pretty clearly.
c00582
DM: I still can't really picture Kenzo that clearly in my head.
c00583
DM: Delwath, I guess Delwath I can sort of fairly easily.
c00584
Delwath: Yeah. Well, just look at the mini fig.
c00585
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
c00586
Kenzo: Look, there he is.
c00587
Unknown: It's right there.
c00588
Kenzo: Nobody knew what-
c00589
Unknown: And it's like
c00590
Kenzo: ... no- nobody really knew what Kenzo's staff looked like until this trip.
c00591
DM: But, but- [laughs]
c00592
Unknown: Now we all really understand.
c00593
Unknown: [laughs]
c00594
DM: But what I wanted to say about that is, so I think Eric
c00595
DM: a- and Mike to a certain extent really sort of had, you could see how their characters appearance and equipment and stuff changes in the description.
c00596
Unknown: [laughs]
c00597
DM: Like when you got, Seeker got the glove and the red tolling cloak which became kind of-
c00598
Unknown: Iconic
c00599
DM: ... iconic.
c00600
Seeker: And it, his, his hair care.
c00601
DM: Exactly.
c00602
Seeker: He has the white streak in the hair.
c00603
DM: Right. Whereas, not shade on Calm and Schwartz, but like
c00604
DM: the pa- the part of the goal of that like describe your character was so that you could actually incorporate into your description how your character changes over time.
c00605
Unknown: Yeah.
c00606
DM: It doesn't feel so static.
c00607
DM: Right? And-
c00608
Unknown: Well it's true because-
c00609
DM: And Wellby, you had the thing with the hats
c00610
Wellby: ... with, with leopard armor it's just like I'm gonna be different every time.
c00611
Unknown: Right.
c00612
DM: But I also-
c00613
Wellby: Like, there wasn't a progression to it.
c00614
Delwath: There's also, it's just, I think there's-
c00615
DM: But there could be if you wanted there to be, right?
c00616
Delwath: I think there's a certain pressure of a warm-up that doesn't necessarily tie into...
c00617
Delwath: I, to me, there was times where I sort of felt like, well, I don't really know what Delwath is doing.
c00618
Wellby: Oh, also that warmup isn't collaborative.
c00619
Unknown: Right. Right.
c00620
Seeker: Ah. So what would be a collaborative warmup, which is like we riff on some world building question that's not part of our characters-
c00621
Unknown: Like y-
c00622
Seeker: ... or more loosely coupled to what we're doing right now.
c00623
Wellby: I mean, I think even with something like you're going into this random town, like, what's, what's it like?
c00624
Unknown: What's the vibe? What's the-
c00625
Unknown: Oh, that's great
c00626
Wellby: ... what's the main business in the town?
c00627
Unknown: That's great.
c00628
Seeker: Make up seven business names and find-
c00629
Unknown: Character.
c00630
Kenzo: That's great. I love that
c00631
Unknown: ... I guess, yeah.
c00632
Kenzo: I love that.
c00633
Unknown: I love-
c00634
Seeker: And then Tim could take or leave any part of it.
c00635
Unknown: But we're-
c00636
DM: So that was f- I mean, that was fun when we were developing Malar.
c00637
DM: You, I mean, you, everybody made up part of Malar and we sort of riffed on Homary.
c00638
DM: But
c00639
DM: it's a little bit tricky if that's
c00640
DM: from my prep point of view, if we're-
c00641
Unknown: Yeah
c00642
DM: ... we're going into a town, let's invent the town in the first 30 minutes of the session, and then I'm gonna run an adventure in the town.
c00643
DM: [laughs]
c00644
Seeker: So, so yeah, the, the task is to somehow bound it so that it fits within your plan.
c00645
Kenzo: [coughs] Or, or for two-
c00646
Seeker: Like, like on the train-
c00647
DM: ... 10 sessions
c00648
Seeker: ... in the Cyberpunk adventure where you had us make up the characters with a set of questions about them.
c00649
DM: Yeah. Oh yeah. That was really fun actually.
c00650
DM: I think... Was that only me and Eric who were there?
c00651
Wellby: I have no memory of this.
c00652
DM: The, the, the-
c00653
Unknown: That's funny.
c00654
DM: It was like the bottle episode-
c00655
Unknown: There was sequence
c00656
DM: ... where we were going on the train-
c00657
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
c00658
DM: ... to Minnesota-
c00659
Unknown: Yes
c00660
DM: ... or Montana or somewhere.
c00661
Seeker: And we weren't really on a train at all.
c00662
DM: We weren't actually on a train.
c00663
Unknown: That's right.
c00664
DM: We were like...
c00665
Unknown: No, of course not. [laughs]
c00666
Seeker: We're, we were being simulated.
c00667
Wellby: Yep. That sounds-
c00668
Seeker: That was fucked up. That's great.
c00669
Delwath: I mean, I, I do think a collaborative
c00670
Delwath: relevant world building riff that is not committed to be canonical would be really fun.
c00671
Unknown: That's also-
c00672
Seeker: But I mean, Tim could take or leave. Yeah.
c00673
Unknown: Yeah.
c00674
Wellby: But also, like, I mean, it,
c00675
Wellby: the riff that we're doing for that doesn't have to be related to the-
c00676
DM: Yeah
c00677
Kenzo: ... adventure that we're running.
c00678
Unknown: Exactly. Exactly.
c00679
Wellby: Like it could still be canonical 100 miles away, so that by the time we get there-
c00680
DM: Yeah. Yeah, yeah
c00681
Wellby: ... there's a built in to incorporate.
c00682
Seeker: But I'd love to talk about Dran- Drancor. We're not nowhere near there.
c00683
Unknown: Yeah.
c00684
Delwath: Or it could be about a character back...
c00685
Delwath: I mean, the other thing that's fun is like, well, okay, where was your character
c00686
Delwath: 10 years ago today? What was your character doing?
c00687
Seeker: Yeah. They never did all that much with Seeker's backstory.
c00688
Unknown: Right. And-
c00689
DM: Oh.
c00690
Unknown: Although-
c00691
Seeker: That was one... Franker even exists because of one session.
c00692
Unknown: Right. Because of that.
c00693
Seeker: What was the mechanic that led to that?
c00694
DM: That was-
c00695
Delwath: There was one session where Tim was like, "Tell me, just share something about your childhood."
c00696
DM: So that was a session where I had-
c00697
Unknown: Oh, yeah
c00698
DM: ... not really prepped anything, and it was like early on, it was like session 15 or something, and I needed...
c00699
DM: I just hadn't gotten around to figuring out what was next, and I didn't wanna just have an hour long session of you meandering around Kerela.
c00700
DM: So I, I looked online for like role-playing prompts.
c00701
Unknown: Right.
c00702
DM: And I was like, we s- as you start the session, you all think back to, I forget what it was, something about your childhood.
c00703
Seeker: This is the kind of thing Schw- that, you know, where it says-
c00704
Delwath: But I actually think Schwartz's point about collaborative is the key one.
c00705
DM: Right.
c00706
Delwath: 'Cause I feel like
c00707
Delwath: it feels very...
c00708
Delwath: The sort of everybody describe your character is very inward.
c00709
Unknown: Inward. Yeah.
c00710
Delwath: And kind of-
c00711
Unknown: Yeah, it's-
c00712
Delwath: It's almost like-
c00713
DM: It's hard to... It, it's not interactive.
c00714
Kenzo: Well, it's gen- it's generative when you can build off of everybody else's-
c00715
Unknown: Yeah.
c00716
Seeker: Yeah.
c00717
Unknown: Yeah.
c00718
Wellby: Let's make a thing together.
c00719
Unknown: Yeah.
c00720
Seeker: Yeah.
c00721
Unknown: I love that.
c00722
Unknown: Although-
c00723
Seeker: The bouncing off.
c00724
Unknown: Yeah
c00725
Seeker: ... the childhood stories one was-
c00726
Unknown: Yeah
c00727
Seeker: ... particularly fun.
c00728
Delwath: Childhood stories one was fun, but it would actually, to me, have been probably more fun if we had all made up one of Delwath's childhood stories.
c00729
Seeker: Something like that. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c00730
Unknown: Right.
c00731
Unknown: Oh, interesting.
c00732
Delwath: Instead of-
c00733
Seeker: So we each contribute to each other's characters.
c00734
DM: Exactly.
c00735
Seeker: 'Cause that's, that's another thing to, that strengthens it, is if we're sort of aware of-
c00736
Unknown: Yeah
c00737
Seeker: ... and involved with what the other characters are like.
c00738
Delwath: Right. Right, like-
c00739
Seeker: 'Cause it's easy to get focused on your own.
c00740
Delwath: Or if we had all made up a Delwath story and a Kenzo story-
c00741
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
c00742
Delwath: ... but not all four of them, right?
c00743
Unknown: Like-
c00744
Unknown: Right
c00745
Unknown: ... if-
c00746
Wellby: Like, I think it goes back to, like, what you were saying about, like, secrets from each other, too.
c00747
Wellby: Like, I remember in that high school campaign, there was so much that was known only to us [laughs] individually.
c00748
Delwath: Right. Did, did everybody-
c00749
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Sorry
c00750
DM: ... like, I'm gonna get coffee.
c00751
Delwath: Did everybody... Coffee, who wants new coffee?
c00752
Unknown: I love coffee.
c00753
Unknown: Uh, I'm gonna have some coffee.
c00754
Delwath: Okay. I just didn't want to take a second cup of-
c00755
Unknown: We-
c00756
Unknown: But I don't, let's, uh-
c00757
Wellby: I don't actually wanna do that anymore.
c00758
DM: I, yeah. Anybody who wants to have, make lunch should, like, get some coffee-
c00759
Unknown: Right. Yes
c00760
Unknown: ... so we can play.
c00761
Delwath: I mean, I do sometimes think that plot information distributed out to individual people and then our job is to integrate the knowledge
c00762
Delwath: can be fun.
c00763
Unknown: Yeah, that-
c00764
Unknown: But that's like-
c00765
Unknown: Yeah, so I tried to do that in your case-
c00766
Unknown: ... a little bit of a task
c00767
DM: ... but because of the...
c00768
DM: To, for that to really work, we'd all, everybody has to commit to reading something in advance-
c00769
Unknown: Yes
c00770
DM: ... which is hard to do.
c00771
Unknown: Yes.
c00772
Delwath: It also works better in person, I think.
c00773
Delwath: I've done it a few times successfully when
c00774
Delwath: we're gonna take half, when I don't have a lot prepped.
c00775
Unknown: Right.
c00776
Delwath: And you almost just have handouts, and if people read the handouts at the beginning and then everybody talks about it.
c00777
Unknown: Right.
c00778
Seeker: I think I saved my-
c00779
Delwath: But it's easy for it to be generating, why don't I just forward you the email?
c00780
Unknown: Yeah.
c00781
Unknown: Right.
c00782
Unknown: And then-
c00783
Seeker: I saved my, my ooze-based lunch for the perfect moment.
c00784
Unknown: [laughs]
c00785
Seeker: I'm gonna have mac and cheese, which will be nice and gooey.
c00786
Delwath: Um, I think I'm gonna make...
c00787
Delwath: Oh, right, I got mozzarella.
c00788
DM: Yeah. I'm not...
c00789
DM: We might, we might end up having to do the final moment of this after dinner.
c00790
Unknown: [laughs]
c00791
Unknown: Yeah.
c00792
Unknown: It's already one.
c00793
Delwath: Well, we had a whole long...
c00794
Unknown: I mean,
c00795
Delwath: I think we should-
c00796
Wellby: Well, I mean, now that we know we should be efficient in our combat, it'll go much-
c00797
Unknown: Maybe I'll be very efficient.
c00798
Delwath: Yeah. Well, we...
c00799
Delwath: Actually, I think we were pretty efficient in combat last night.
c00800
Unknown: We did great last night.
c00801
Unknown: Yeah.
c00802
Unknown: Great. Um.
c00803
Unknown: [dishes clanking]
c00804
Unknown: [clears throat] [objects clanking]
c00805
DM: So Oren, does Wellby want to be a dragon in the next combat?
c00806
Wellby: [laughs]
c00807
Unknown: Speaking of.
c00808
Wellby: Who wants to be a dragon just like to see what's that like?
c00809
Delwath: I mean, do, do we have an extra day?
c00810
Unknown: What do you mean?
c00811
Delwath: Delwath, I took as my next level spell True Polymorph.
c00812
Delwath: I can turn anything into a dragon.
c00813
Unknown: Yeah. Well, I think, I think just-
c00814
Delwath: As long as they're a 20th level character.
c00815
Unknown: [laughs] I can turn anything-
c00816
Kenzo: I think be- I think before the campaign ends-
c00817
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, definitely
c00818
Kenzo: ... yeah, we should all experience being a dragon.
c00819
Wellby: Yeah.
c00820
Kenzo: Like, that's like pretty sick, you know?
c00821
Wellby: The potential for practical jokes really increases with True Polymorph.
c00822
Unknown: Right. [laughs]
c00823
Unknown: [laughs]
c00824
Seeker: Like, "Oh, sorry, something went wrong."
c00825
Delwath: Or, "Oh, shit, what has happened?"
c00826
Unknown: [laughs]
c00827
DM: Kong, do you wanna record a backup race menu too?
c00828
Unknown: Yeah.
c00829
DM: In case mine doesn't catch everything too.
c00830
Unknown: For sure.
c00831
DM: Oh, and where did... Where did the speakers go?
c00832
Unknown: I
c00833
Unknown: don't know.
c00834
Delwath: Actually, that's making me think. Is there any dragon that is resistant to-
c00835
Unknown: Ooze
c00836
Delwath: ... or immune to ooze, immune to acid damage?
c00837
Wellby: Uh, black dragons.
c00838
DM: Black dragons and possibly
c00839
DM: copper or bronze.
c00840
Delwath: I mean, but black dragons also do acid damage.
c00841
DM: Yeah. That's, that's the downside to dragons is-
c00842
Unknown: Mm
c00843
DM: ... they all are resistant to the damage they do.
c00844
DM: So if you wanna be resistant to...
c00845
DM: Which actually,
c00846
DM: theoretically pretty good for Seeker
c00847
DM: because you could... Seeker could turn into a dragon resistant to acid damage and then just cast spells instead of-
c00848
Unknown: Oh
c00849
DM: ... using the breath weapon.
c00850
Seeker: That makes sense.
c00851
Seeker: So what's a dragon resistant to acid damage?
c00852
Delwath: Um, a copper dragon is not only resistant to acid damage, it's immune to acid damage.
c00853
Seeker: That's even better.
c00854
Delwath: It's only challenge 14, but...
c00855
DM: But if you're just gonna be casting spells, that's
c00856
DM: better.
c00857
Delwath: It, it has a...
c00858
Delwath: It can replace one, it, it has a slowing breath.
c00859
Seeker: Like, what are the, Ooze's minions gonna look like?
c00860
Seeker: We have no idea what we're walking into, as always.
c00861
Delwath: I mean, a copper dragon is not crazy.
c00862
Unknown: What's the-
c00863
Delwath: Oh, man. An ancient copper dragon is one-
c00864
Unknown: It's CR 21.
c00865
Delwath: It's CR 21. It's one too high.
c00866
Wellby: Yeah.
c00867
Seeker: Seeker is, like, not interested in very many-
c00868
DM: Yeah, Seeker's done the dragon thing and...
c00869
Unknown: Seeker's not.
c00870
Kenzo: So give me some tra- dragon, uh, trauma bonding, Seeker.
c00871
Wellby: Seeker's full name is actually-
c00872
Delwath: But, but like, Kenzo had very successful-
c00873
DM: Kenzo, it wasn't traumatic at all
c00874
Kenzo: ... Oh, I know. Kenzo loved that shit.
c00875
Unknown: ... Kenzo was successful.
c00876
Wellby: Novelty Seekers.
c00877
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. What's up?
c00878
Wellby: No, T- T is short for something.
c00879
Wellby: It's a middle name.
c00880
Kenzo: Little T Seeker. [laughs] Um, somebody had, like, a USB-C charger over here.
c00881
DM: That, that was mine.
c00882
Unknown: I know.
c00883
DM: Oh, here. Here.
c00884
Delwath: Do you need a USB-C?
c00885
DM: My, my computer is fully charged.
c00886
Delwath: I also, I have one that I'm not using if you guys need more.
c00887
Kenzo: Yeah, maybe just a half and half to charge random things.
c00888
Delwath: Uh, I think I have one.
c00889
Seeker: Are any of the dairy products known good, like milks or cream?
c00890
DM: All of the dairy products should be known good.
c00891
Wellby: The half & half I just opened this morning.
c00892
Wellby: That's terrible.
c00893
Unknown: It's the purple one here?
c00894
Wellby: Yeah.
c00895
Seeker: I'm just trying to maximize my energy.
c00896
Kenzo: Mike, Mike, do you have a, do you have a USB-C charger?
c00897
Unknown: Um,
c00898
Delwath: I might actually not. Now that I'm thinking about it, I might not.
c00899
Delwath: Oh, no worries about it. Oh, no, don't worry
c00900
Kenzo: about it. No big deal.
c00901
Unknown: Ugh.
c00902
Unknown: Uh.
c00903
Kenzo: Man, this is so awesome.
c00904
Kenzo: I love that we do this every year.
c00905
Wellby: Yeah.
c00906
Unknown: It is
c00907
Kenzo: really, it's really,
c00908
Kenzo: it's super fantastic. Oh, perfect.
c00909
Unknown: Thank you.
c00910
Unknown: Oh, wow.
c00911
Delwath: It's my fancy little travel charger.
c00912
Unknown: Oh.
c00913
Unknown: I got sick of-
c00914
Unknown: I think there's a plug...
c00915
Delwath: I got sick of hotel rooms that did not have enough plugs to charge my...
c00916
Unknown: Here.
c00917
Unknown: Sweet.
c00918
Delwath: I mean, a copper dragon, its breath weapon's, it has a slowing breath
c00919
DM: which recharges. [package rustling] Its rend does acid damage,
c00920
Delwath: but that's... Who cares?
c00921
DM: Copper dragon?
c00922
Delwath: Copper dragon.
c00923
Seeker: Sounds pretty cool.
c00924
Unknown: And-
c00925
Seeker: Is there anything that's not a copper dragon or not a dragon that is also immune to acid damage?
c00926
Unknown: Um,
c00927
Delwath: let's see. Could I search [package rustling]
c00928
DM: Yeah, you can search for that
c00929
Delwath: ... damage immunity acid?
c00930
Unknown: Challenge.
c00931
Seeker: Oh, like that poison troll or whatever
c00932
Wellby: that we trapped one time.
c00933
Unknown: Oh, yeah. Is that still in the Mirror, Mirror-
c00934
DM: No, the poison troll destroyed...
c00935
Unknown: We defeated it.
c00936
Unknown: The vampires.
c00937
Wellby: We defeated it.
c00938
Unknown: The vampires.
c00939
Wellby: The vampires, yeah.
c00940
DM: We destroyed the vampires.
c00941
Delwath: Um, let's see. A black dragon is also
c00942
Delwath: immune to acid.
c00943
Kenzo: Eric, did you do this with your mind?
c00944
DM: [laughs]
c00945
Seeker: I did it unintentionally with my mind.
c00946
Delwath: It's, um... The black dragon is not as good as a copper dragon, I don't think.
c00947
Unknown: Um,
c00948
Delwath: let's see. Hold on. I got a filter on.
c00949
DM: A leviathan.
c00950
Seeker: I'm down for that.
c00951
Unknown: Gargantuan elemental.
c00952
Unknown: Ooh, a, a leviathan.
c00953
Unknown: Gigantic serpent.
c00954
Unknown: A roar.
c00955
DM: Immune to acid and poison.
c00956
Seeker: Yeah, this is the one.
c00957
DM: Your, but your d- your attacks do am- acid damage too.
c00958
Unknown: Oh.
c00959
DM: But, I mean-
c00960
Seeker: I fucking ca- spell cast.
c00961
DM: You can cast spells, yeah.
c00962
Delwath: And a tidal wave.
c00963
Seeker: Has that got a compatible CR?
c00964
DM: Yeah, it's CR20. [coughs] Three legendary resistances.
c00965
DM: If you take 50 or more cold damage in a single turn, you partially freeze.
c00966
Unknown: Mm.
c00967
DM: And your attacks-
c00968
Delwath: Actually has resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing.
c00969
Delwath: Immunity to acid and poison.
c00970
DM: But from non-magical sources.
c00971
Delwath: Yeah, that's true. That will be meaningless.
c00972
Unknown: Uh, ex-
c00973
DM: Oh
c00974
Delwath: ... immune to exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, and stunned.
c00975
Delwath: It's pretty good.
c00976
DM: Yeah, that is pretty good.
c00977
Delwath: It's like a giant...
c00978
Delwath: It's basically a giant water elemental.
c00979
DM: Giant sea serpent.
c00980
Delwath: No, it's like a water elemental, right?
c00981
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c00982
Unknown: A sea slug?
c00983
DM: A sea serpent.
c00984
Wellby: Oh. [laughs] Transforming into it on land, it just looks [laughs] sloppier.
c00985
DM: Well, it's, it's...
c00986
DM: Yeah, it has a move speed of 40.
c00987
DM: It has a swim speed of 120.
c00988
Unknown: Mm.
c00989
DM: But 40 isn't terrible.
c00990
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c00991
Delwath: 14 to hit, reach 20, one target.
c00992
Seeker: How, wait, how big is gargantuan?
c00993
Delwath: Gargantuan is-
c00994
DM: 20 foot by 20 foot.
c00995
Unknown: Yeah.
c00996
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah, I think that's-
c00997
DM: Oh. [laughs]
c00998
Unknown: I have an idea.
c00999
Seeker: Okay, if you turn into that... Yeah, I'm, I'm, I'm heading that direction.
c01000
Unknown: [laughs] That's, that
c01001
Delwath: is a pretty good... I don't see...
c01002
Delwath: I don't see m- I mean, a copper dragon also has a lot of
c01003
Delwath: things that might be good.
c01004
Seeker: Remember, I'll do this so long as nobody hits it.
c01005
DM: We can giant spin.
c01006
Seeker: Oh, perfect. [laughs] That is approximately the right size.
c01007
DM: Yeah, that's close enough for the right size.
c01008
Seeker: On the diagonal, it's a four by four.
c01009
DM: Yeah. [coughs]
c01010
Delwath: Yeah, that's pretty much...
c01011
Delwath: Co- a copper dragon or a leviathan are your pretty much your...
c01012
Unknown: [items clattering] Yeah, that's perfect.
c01013
Unknown: [items clattering] [clears throat] Oh, yeah, of course.
c01014
Seeker: If you make something that we can pose this all on, that would be great.
c01015
Unknown: So everything on...
c01016
Wellby: Yeah, I think I'm gonna do it with, like, a, like, a meeting table in the middle and then a little pool and, like, a living wall of, like, trees and plants and stuff coming out of it.
c01017
Delwath: Oh my God. Oh, you know what's pretty good?
c01018
Delwath: An ancient brass dragon.
c01019
Wellby: Mm.
c01020
Delwath: CR20.
c01021
Delwath: It makes... It has a sleep breath.
c01022
Unknown: That
c01023
Delwath: each creature in a 90-foot cone, failure of the target has the incapacitated condition until the end of its next turn, at which point it repeats the save.
c01024
Unknown: Second failure, it's unconscious for 10 minutes.
c01025
Delwath: It wakes up if you do damage, but it has fire breath.
c01026
Unknown: So Schwartz, you like visualize the whole thing-
c01027
Wellby: Yep
c01028
Seeker: ... get like 30 parts to make it-
c01029
DM: Oh, thank you
c01030
Seeker: ... and then build it, and then do that again?
c01031
DM: I'll take two.
c01032
Seeker: Yeah. I'm just watching you and thinking, like, how did you just-
c01033
Wellby: I don't know.
c01034
Unknown: Love that.
c01035
Wellby: Hm? Schwartz?
c01036
Wellby: Oh, no thanks.
c01037
DM: All right.
c01038
Wellby: Yeah, it's visualizing, but it's not,
c01039
Wellby: it's not actually visualizing the end product.
c01040
Wellby: It's more like
c01041
Wellby: visualizing the concept of the end product.
c01042
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c01043
Wellby: And then, like, building towards it, and in the building towards it, you're actually creating the thing, like...
c01044
Unknown: [laughs]
c01045
Unknown: Huh.
c01046
Wellby: It feels more like I'm visuali- like-
c01047
Seeker: You have like a little sketch or like one-
c01048
Wellby: ... visualizing. Yeah, or almost like a heuristic for how to go about-
c01049
Unknown: Oh
c01050
Wellby: ... moving through the process.
c01051
Seeker: Huh.
c01052
Wellby: Like, I know I'm gonna use these kind of studs to build on, to attach greens, and then-
c01053
Seeker: Oh, it's techniques that you're combining.
c01054
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
c01055
Wellby: Yeah.
c01056
Unknown: Ah.
c01057
Wellby: And then I'm gonna layer.
c01058
Wellby: So...
c01059
Unknown: But cool.
c01060
Wellby: Yeah. It's not actually visualizing the,
c01061
Wellby: like, the final thing in all its detail.
c01062
Seeker: I'm just trying to... Like I- I have
c01063
Seeker: Technic stuff out.
c01064
Seeker: Izzy and I played with it a little bit. I'm like,
c01065
Seeker: it's, it helps you see like, wow, there's a lot of implicit knowledge [laughs] that goes into this.
c01066
Wellby: Yeah.
c01067
Seeker: Like you, she puts axles in things and then they fall out again.
c01068
Seeker: Oh, it needs to be secured on both ends.
c01069
Unknown: Like there's a-
c01070
Wellby: Yep
c01071
Seeker: ... way of thinking about-
c01072
Wellby: Right
c01073
Unknown: ... cutting parts.
c01074
Wellby: Yes. Yes.
c01075
DM: Did everybody level up to level 20?
c01076
Unknown: Learn that. No.
c01077
Unknown: Oh.
c01078
DM: I just did you, Colin.
c01079
Unknown: Oh, thank you.
c01080
Wellby: Yeah, and like, do you have to learn that actively?
c01081
Wellby: Like, do you,
c01082
Wellby: can you only learn that by doing, maybe?
c01083
DM: Wow.
c01084
Unknown: I learned it.
c01085
DM: That's pretty strong. Your, your dex is now 25.
c01086
DM: You have a plus seven dexterity.
c01087
DM: Your wisdom is 22.
c01088
DM: You have a plus six.
c01089
Delwath: That makes your base AC is 24 plus dex.
c01090
DM: Your AC is 24.
c01091
Wellby: Whoa.
c01092
Unknown: Oh my God.
c01093
Unknown: Wow.
c01094
Unknown: Unhittable.
c01095
DM: You d- you have plus 15 to hit with the staff and plus 13 with your fists.
c01096
Wellby: Holy shit.
c01097
Delwath: You know what's a pretty good-
c01098
DM: And your save DC for your aura strikes is now 20
c01099
Wellby: Why did that jump up so much?
c01100
DM: 'Cause your level 20 monk ability-
c01101
Unknown: Yeah, plus four
c01102
DM: ... is a plus four to wisdom and plus four to dex.
c01103
Wellby: All right.
c01104
Seeker: Holy butt.
c01105
Delwath: That's what I see. You know what's a good creature?
c01106
Unknown: I set myself to 20.
c01107
Delwath: I might, I might ex- I might shape-shift.
c01108
Delwath: An animal lord.
c01109
Wellby: Animal lord?
c01110
Delwath: An animal lord. It's a celestial.
c01111
Delwath: It has four legendary resistances.
c01112
Kenzo: So imagine if it was like you build some shit, you try it, you take it apart.
c01113
Unknown: Um-
c01114
Unknown: Yeah.
c01115
Delwath: It makes two attacks plus-
c01116
Unknown: It's like hard work
c01117
Delwath: ... its attack isn't amazing.
c01118
Wellby: Which is not, like... Oh. It's not super efficient.
c01119
Unknown: 46.
c01120
Unknown: Um-
c01121
Wellby: Just gotta figure out what's going on. The process
c01122
Delwath: ... but it can summon an animal spirit.
c01123
Kenzo: You should give a guest lecture in, uh, Eric's, uh, learning, creative learning class.
c01124
Seeker: About Lego building?
c01125
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs] Or just how you...
c01126
Unknown: Yeah, I don't know.
c01127
Wellby: I feel like my lecture would be like, "Well, try some stuff.
c01128
Wellby: See how it goes."
c01129
Wellby: That's literally the whole point.
c01130
Wellby: Do something different.
c01131
Unknown: That's like literally-
c01132
Unknown: If it doesn't work
c01133
Kenzo: ... that's like literally the whole point.
c01134
Unknown: It is.
c01135
Kenzo: Like, every conversation I have with Mitch is like, "This is really cool, but how can you tinker with it?"
c01136
Unknown: [laughs]
c01137
DM: Yeah. It's like I mean, its attacks do less damage than your attacks.
c01138
Unknown: Yeah.
c01139
Delwath: Yeah, but it has legendary resistance.
c01140
Wellby: Do something different.
c01141
Kenzo: It does say magical effects. Too worried.
c01142
Delwath: Right. It's a lot more durable.
c01143
Unknown: Yep
c01144
Unknown: And
c01145
Delwath: it, um...
c01146
DM: Okay.
c01147
Unknown: Leviathan.
c01148
Seeker: Let me get my Leviathan stat block on up here.
c01149
Seeker: But then it's like...
c01150
Seeker: This is some given page.
c01151
Seeker: Where am I looking? [paper rustling]
c01152
Unknown: Anvil.
c01153
DM: Oh, you got one more spell too.
c01154
Unknown: Oh. [paper rustling]
c01155
DM: Uh, what's a good one?
c01156
Delwath: Can be any level? Yeah.
c01157
Delwath: Although you're... You might want something that's not 9th level, because your 9th level slot's pretty tapped.
c01158
Unknown: Yeah.
c01159
DM: Honestly, Hero's Feast is not a bad choice.
c01160
DM: That was always very useful to us.
c01161
Unknown: What's that do? Is it a bunch of like temporary hit points or what is that?
c01162
Delwath: No, actually, a good, a good buffing spell is a good idea.
c01163
Unknown: Very
c01164
DM: Okay. Or you could just take Force Cage.
c01165
DM: Although Force Cage is gonna do literally nothing against a 100-foot long- Yeah ...
c01166
Unknown: size ooze.
c01167
Unknown: I'll take Hero's Feast.
c01168
Delwath: Uh. But is there a better buff spell?
c01169
DM: No.
c01170
Delwath: What does Hero's Feast give you?
c01171
DM: Uh, resistance to poison damage, immunity to frightened and poisoned conditions, increases your hit point maximum by 2d10.
c01172
Unknown: But it lasts for 24 hours, right?
c01173
DM: It lasts for 24 hours-
c01174
Unknown: That's what's good
c01175
DM: ... so it's key 'cause you can cast it before-
c01176
Delwath: Right
c01177
DM: the night before and then rest and get your slot back.
c01178
Delwath: All the other good buffs probably take your concentration, which you can't.
c01179
Unknown: [paper rustling]
c01180
Seeker: Okay, I think I added Heroes' Feast.
c01181
Seeker: What level is that one?
c01182
Unknown: Six.
c01183
Seeker: Oh, and I can long rest if
c01184
Delwath: But what's the point of Hero's Feast?
c01185
Unknown: Why wouldn't you just cast it with Wish?
c01186
Seeker: So I can save my Wish.
c01187
Unknown: Oh, and then rest. Then you rest.
c01188
DM: Right. Yeah, that's true. Maybe Hero's Feast isn't that useful.
c01189
Delwath: Because the, the point of Hero's Feast is it's 24 hours, so you can cast it the night before.
c01190
DM: Mm-hmm.
c01191
Delwath: But you can do it with Wish the night before.
c01192
Unknown: Oh.
c01193
Delwath: There's no upside to knowing it.
c01194
Delwath: How m- wait, how many 6th level slots do you have?
c01195
Delwath: Two. 'Cause it has to be any spell in the game, right?
c01196
Seeker: Yep. It's really helpful to have a magic consultant on your team.
c01197
Unknown: [laughs] Yes.
c01198
Kenzo: It's helpful to have a DM on your team too.
c01199
DM: [laughs] Well, yeah, exactly.
c01200
DM: [water running]
c01201
Unknown: Um..
c01202
Wellby: Magic consultant would be a great job title.
c01203
Delwath: That would be. [coughs] You want, you want...
c01204
Unknown: What does Seeker...
c01205
Delwath: Seeker needs a better... I think you need better ways of dealing damage.
c01206
DM: Although Chain Lightning- Well, Chain Lightning, that's why we added Chain Lightning.
c01207
DM: Yeah. It's a really strong damage dealing spell.
c01208
Delwath: It's... Chain Lightning's 6th level?
c01209
DM: It's 6th level.
c01210
Delwath: I mean, there's an argument for something like,
c01211
Unknown: um...
c01212
Unknown: What I would, I would pick an 8th level.
c01213
DM: I- what about Demiplane? I mean, it's not gonna be useful in the next three hours, but it's this very Seeker-ish spell.
c01214
Seeker: What does that one do?
c01215
DM: It creates a demiplane that you can-
c01216
Unknown: Oh, yeah
c01217
Unknown: ... like, stash stuff in.
c01218
Unknown: Yeah.
c01219
Seeker: I'm into it. I feel like I've seen reference to that somewhere on my own character sheet.
c01220
Seeker: Is it, like, the wand or
c01221
Seeker: binding stones?
c01222
DM: The binding stones might have a demiplane-ish, 'cause y- you only have one 8th level spell, and Animal Shapes is very, very useful, but not every, not all the time.
c01223
Seeker: No, binding stones don't have it.
c01224
Seeker: Hmm. All right.
c01225
Seeker: That was the Demiplane idea.
c01226
DM: I mean, the other potential useful 8th level spell is Mind Blank, which is also a 24-hour buff that gives you immunity to psychic damage and the
c01227
DM: charmed condition.
c01228
Wellby: Don't you have a ring that does that?
c01229
DM: Yeah, but...
c01230
Seeker: I don't know if I'm attuned to it right now.
c01231
DM: You're not... I don't think you're attuned to it, 'cause- And also it's not exactly what the ring is.
c01232
DM: It just gives you, it gives you advantage against charm.
c01233
Delwath: I mean, actually, Demiplane's pretty useful, 'cause we could, you...
c01234
Delwath: We could go to a demiplane. It lasts for an hour, so we could short rest in the demiplane and then come back out.
c01235
Unknown: Hmm.
c01236
DM: Yeah. I would probably just take Demiplane. I, I would...
c01237
Delwath: Yeah. Demiplane's actually a good ch- It, it, it is actually a really useful, "Hey, we need to, we need, we need 15...
c01238
Delwath: We need to go somewhere safe for a half hour to, like-
c01239
DM: Okay, so everybody's leveled up.
c01240
Unknown: All right.
c01241
Seeker: Go to demiplane.
c01242
DM: [sighs] Everybody long rest.
c01243
Unknown: Mm. Mm-hmm.
c01244
Kenzo: We don't get the ma- the temp edge HP things, right?
c01245
Kenzo: Why do we sometimes get that? Is that 'cause of something Delwath is doing?
c01246
DM: Yeah.
c01247
Unknown: Heroic Feast.
c01248
Delwath: Which temporary HP thing?
c01249
Kenzo: Like a bunch... Sometimes you're like, "You have 28 HP, 28."
c01250
Delwath: Oh. Yeah, 'cause I cast Aid.
c01251
Unknown: Oh.
c01252
Delwath: But I generally cast Aid every morning.
c01253
DM: Right
c01254
Delwath: Because Aid asks, lasts for eight hours.
c01255
Unknown: Yeah.
c01256
Delwath: And I can
c01257
Delwath: cast it and then make breakfast and short rest again to get my spell slots back.
c01258
Unknown: Oh.
c01259
Delwath: So usually-
c01260
Unknown: You get 20.
c01261
Unknown: Yeah.
c01262
DM: Okay. So let's, let's begin.
c01263
DM: As you wake up
c01264
DM: the morning after
c01265
DM: you left,
c01266
DM: having returned from Limbo and immediately collapsed in exhaustion.
c01267
DM: As you awake,
c01268
DM: uh, the sun is rising over Orenlas on Vindasharna,
c01269
DM: and you are left now only with the mission to
c01270
DM: return to Isengai
c01271
DM: and find the ooze that once attempted to destroy your ship,
c01272
DM: destroy it, and cleanse the river so the Heartroot can be
c01273
DM: replanted.
c01274
DM: So [sighs] what, what is your...
c01275
DM: What do you want to do? I mean,
c01276
DM: you could just teleport straight there.
c01277
DM: You could fly the ship.
c01278
Seeker: How far are we up?
c01279
Delwath: Do we, do we know anything about the-
c01280
DM: You don't know anything that's happening in Isengai right now.
c01281
DM: You have many
c01282
DM: ways to figure that out.
c01283
Kenzo: [clears throat] Do some clairvoyance, send a-
c01284
Unknown: Scry.
c01285
Kenzo: Yeah. Scry. Let's do that.
c01286
Unknown: Yeah.
c01287
Wellby: See what's going on.
c01288
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo's gonna, um,
c01289
Kenzo: uh, go hang out with the Heartroot and
c01290
Unknown: tell us-
c01291
DM: Well, the Heartroot's still back in...
c01292
Delwath: We're in the Elven Forest.
c01293
DM: You're in the Elven Forest.
c01294
Delwath: Not the-
c01295
Kenzo: Oh, we have to go back and get the Heartroot.
c01296
Unknown: Or we're gonna-
c01297
DM: Or send a message to the rangers and say, "Bring the Heartroot."
c01298
Unknown: They'll have the... Okay.
c01299
Delwath: But we should probably make the space.
c01300
Delwath: Like, let's not bring the Heartroot until the ooze is dead, right?
c01301
Unknown: Yeah.
c01302
Unknown: Like...
c01303
DM: That might be risky.
c01304
Unknown: Could end badly. Yeah.
c01305
Delwath: Could end badly, right?
c01306
Unknown: True that.
c01307
DM: So-
c01308
Seeker: Uh, transplantation we wanna do as quickly as possible, you know.
c01309
Unknown: It's like, um,
c01310
Seeker: repotting a plant.
c01311
DM: Right.
c01312
Seeker: Planting something, you wanna keep it out of the ground.
c01313
DM: I mean, Seeker has two seventh level slots now.
c01314
DM: You probably wanna teleport to Arbe's and then teleport to Isengai instantaneously with the Heartroot.
c01315
Unknown: Cool.
c01316
Seeker: Oh, I can take it in a teleport?
c01317
Seeker: It counts as a creature?
c01318
DM: Yeah.
c01319
Unknown: Okay.
c01320
DM: I mean, it's 10 foot by 10... I mean, it's big, but, like, you could, you know,
c01321
DM: pick it up.
c01322
Unknown: Yeah. That makes sense.
c01323
DM: Oh, but also you can teleport objects, can't you?
c01324
Unknown: I don't know.
c01325
Seeker: That seems like a real easy...
c01326
Unknown: Okay.
c01327
Delwath: I think we-
c01328
DM: It, it's 600 miles from here, so it's about three days on, on, two and a half days on Vindasharna.
c01329
Kenzo: We should bring the ship, yeah?
c01330
Unknown: Yeah.
c01331
Wellby: I think so, right? I think we just- There's no reason-
c01332
Unknown: We, we set out
c01333
Unknown: ... not.
c01334
Delwath: I mean, we'll, we'll-
c01335
Unknown: Gosh
c01336
Seeker: ... a single object.
c01337
DM: Yeah.
c01338
Delwath: We'll set out on Vindasharna towards Isengai.
c01339
Unknown: Use the levitation spell
c01340
Unknown: Yeah.
c01341
Unknown: Um...
c01342
Unknown: Scry.
c01343
DM: Yeah.
c01344
DM: Okay, so as the, you leave the monks here
c01345
DM: to
c01346
DM: either return and bring them back to Dunmar, to make their way to Dunmar, they all need a bit of time to recover before they're gonna do anything in the Elven Forest.
c01347
Unknown: Right.
c01348
DM: It's as good a place as any.
c01349
Unknown: Yeah.
c01350
DM: And begin
c01351
DM: your trip.
c01352
DM: Uh, as you start to sail on Vindasharna, Delweth takes out his silver bowl and begins to scry on,
c01353
DM: I guess, Isengai.
c01354
Delwath: The, yeah, basically to start with where we were.
c01355
Delwath: I mean, basically the spot where Vindasharna was attacked last.
c01356
Unknown: Yeah.
c01357
DM: Okay.
c01358
Unknown: Yeah.
c01359
DM: So, um, you are looking down into a maelstrom of ash.
c01360
Unknown: Eh.
c01361
DM: You cannot see the city at all beneath you.
c01362
DM: It's like a, it's like a hurricane that seems to be growing and spreading out from the city.
c01363
DM: It now seems to be stretching about 15 miles in every direction
c01364
DM: from your scry.
c01365
Unknown: Of what?
c01366
DM: And the
c01367
DM: storm is growing bigger.
c01368
DM: [paper rustling]
c01369
Unknown: Ow. Huh.
c01370
Seeker: Huh. 15 miles in every direction.
c01371
Unknown: It's-
c01372
Wellby: And it's getting bigger?
c01373
DM: Yeah.
c01374
Wellby: All right, so maybe there's a little urgency.
c01375
Seeker: What, is it drawing power from Limbo still or something else?
c01376
DM: You can't see. All that Delwath can see in the scrying mirror is-
c01377
Delwath: [laughs] You know, you know everything I know, Seeker.
c01378
Kenzo: Ah, yeah.
c01379
DM: [clears throat] A maelstrom of ash swirling below him.
c01380
Unknown: Hmm.
c01381
Unknown: Um,
c01382
Delwath: okay. And it's, like, 600 miles away?
c01383
DM: Yeah.
c01384
Unknown: Um...
c01385
Seeker: hmm. There was the question of the effect of the
c01386
Unknown: explosion we saw inside Limbo-
c01387
Unknown: Yep
c01388
Unknown: ... on this world.
c01389
Unknown: Um...
c01390
Unknown: Maybe it's a backlash.
c01391
Unknown: [instrumental music] Let's see.
c01392
Unknown: Um,
c01393
Delwath: I, I think the faster
c01394
Kenzo: we can get there, the better.
c01395
Unknown: Um, but I think-
c01396
Seeker: Well, we don't want to teleport into a hurricane.
c01397
Unknown: No, I think we probably don't want to teleport into a hurricane.
c01398
Unknown: I think that's true.
c01399
Unknown: Um...
c01400
Seeker: Well, what kind of approach even is there to fight something that's so big?
c01401
Unknown: I...
c01402
Unknown: Yeah.
c01403
Seeker: Um, Arcana about
c01404
Seeker: giant oozes? Was there anything, any precedent for...
c01405
Unknown: [laughs]
c01406
Unknown: Wait, the oozes is from Limbo, right?
c01407
Kenzo: It's a Limbo ooze.
c01408
Delwath: We don't know. We don't know at all
c01409
Delwath: anything about the ooze.
c01410
Wellby: Arcana about oozes, what's our-
c01411
Delwath: Literally all we know about the ooze- Yeah ...
c01412
Unknown: is we saw it from above, right?
c01413
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c01414
Delwath: When we flew over Isengai before, we saw this giant ooze like thing-
c01415
Unknown: And we-
c01416
Delwath: ... covering like half the city.
c01417
Delwath: And we flew down towards it to investigate, and then it flung a tendril off like-
c01418
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Remember, yeah, yeah.
c01419
Seeker: Like we know like what color it was and w- that the fact that it-
c01420
Unknown: Yeah, but
c01421
Seeker: ... was able to use acid to damage the stone of the ship.
c01422
Kenzo: Yeah. No, but, but my qu- It's just...
c01423
Kenzo: 'Cause Rai and the monks went to Isengai 'cause that's where the...
c01424
Unknown: Right?
c01425
DM: That's where the Limbo... Yes, that was where the Limbo
c01426
Unknown: Where the ooze was
c01427
Delwath: woo walked. Wait, but they didn't go to Isengai.
c01428
Delwath: Did they go to Isengai?
c01429
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c01430
Delwath: Oh, okay. They went to Isengai.
c01431
Kenzo: Yeah. So, the, the... So I'm saying the ooze is related to Limbo, right?
c01432
Kenzo: It's not like the ooze is-
c01433
Unknown: Yeah.
c01434
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c01435
DM: The ooze was not there when Rai and the monks went there, and then-
c01436
Unknown: Yeah.
c01437
Delwath: Oh, it wasn't there when Rai and the monks went there?
c01438
Unknown: No.
c01439
c01440
Unknown: Oh, I didn't realize that.
c01441
Kenzo: That's the whole thing. It was like a consequence of them like trying to close the vortex or some shit like that.
c01442
Kenzo: Either the ooze leaked out-
c01443
Unknown: Yeah
c01444
Kenzo: ... or it's like, it's like some Limbo ooze or something.
c01445
Seeker: So maybe we can use Limbo tricks on it.
c01446
Seeker: [thud] Like transmute it with our minds.
c01447
Unknown: Maybe.
c01448
Seeker: From inside Limbo?
c01449
Wellby: I don't know if we wanna go back to Limbo, though.
c01450
Unknown: I don't-
c01451
Delwath: No, Limbo's... Let's stay out of Limbo for right now.
c01452
Seeker: But then can we banish it then?
c01453
Kenzo: Ah, that's an interesting question.
c01454
Kenzo: Does it count as... I feel like that might be a little too easy.
c01455
Seeker: Is it a creature?
c01456
DM: It is definitely a creature, yes.
c01457
Wellby: Is it... How do we find out if it's native to a different plane?
c01458
Kenzo: Uh, did I s- I mean, I must have soul sighted it or like kind of- Ah.
c01459
Delwath: Oh ... contact other planes. I'm gonna ask the Tonchi.
c01460
Unknown: Okay.
c01461
Delwath: Is the ooze a
c01462
Delwath: native to Limbo?
c01463
Delwath: A creature of Limbo?
c01464
Unknown: Sort of. [clears throat]
c01465
Kenzo: This is like us fighting the sentient ocean, basically.
c01466
Delwath: Hold on. I have five questions.
c01467
Seeker: Oh, keep going. Yeah.
c01468
Unknown: It's sort of native to Limbo.
c01469
Unknown: Um,
c01470
Delwath: uh, it um...
c01471
Unknown: Is it,
c01472
Delwath: is it [coughs] um, does it have goals?
c01473
Unknown: Oh,
c01474
Unknown: interesting.
c01475
Unknown: No. Um...
c01476
Kenzo: Great question.
c01477
Delwath: Does it, uh,
c01478
Unknown: um...
c01479
Delwath: Does it have...
c01480
Unknown: [coughs]
c01481
Seeker: I've got an idea here.
c01482
Unknown: Um,
c01483
Unknown: d- does it,
c01484
Unknown: [thud] Um,
c01485
Delwath: I'm trying to think of how to ask this. Can, can...
c01486
Delwath: This is quite, not quite the right phrasing.
c01487
Delwath: Can it be killed by stabbing?
c01488
Delwath: But I don't mean exactly that. Like,
c01489
Delwath: can we, can we destroy it with the tools and capabilities that we would use against sort of a normal creature?
c01490
Seeker: A normal magical creature?
c01491
Unknown: Yeah.
c01492
Unknown: Sort of. [laughs]
c01493
Unknown: Um,
c01494
Delwath: is it growing?
c01495
Unknown: Hmm.
c01496
Unknown: Yes.
c01497
Delwath: Um, one more.
c01498
Unknown: Uh,
c01499
Unknown: does it have allies?
c01500
Unknown: Ooh.
c01501
Unknown: That's a good one.
c01502
Seeker: Good question.
c01503
Unknown: No. Okay.
c01504
Delwath: So it's growing, so I think
c01505
Delwath: maybe a leisurely flight to the ooze could backfire.
c01506
Kenzo: No, I mean, we should get close, but not...
c01507
Delwath: I'm wondering if we could just teleport, but we can't really tele-
c01508
DM: can we... Do we have... We don't really have any spells. Remember you also took Wind Walk,
c01509
Unknown: Eric.
c01510
Seeker: That can make us gaseous.
c01511
DM: And you can, you gain a fly speed of 300-
c01512
Unknown: Oh. Oh, wow. That's fast
c01513
DM: ... feet. So.
c01514
Delwath: How long does that last?
c01515
Unknown: Eight hours. Oh.
c01516
DM: 300 feet
c01517
DM: per six seconds.
c01518
Unknown: That seems useful.
c01519
DM: Is 35 miles per hour.
c01520
DM: No, sorry, it's 600 feet per six seconds 'cause you can dash.
c01521
DM: 68 miles per hour.
c01522
Unknown: And-
c01523
Delwath: Way faster than the ship And we have 600 miles to go.
c01524
DM: Well, no, 'cause you've been flying for a couple of hours, so you have- Well, we can go 544 miles.
c01525
Delwath: So do we have about 500 miles and 50 miles to go?
c01526
DM: You have like 580 miles to go.
c01527
Delwath: So Wind Walk would get us almost all the way there.
c01528
Delwath: ... in a day
c01529
Seeker: But do we wanna still have it up when we're encountering the thing?
c01530
DM: No, because the only actions you can take in wind form are-
c01531
Unknown: Ah
c01532
Unknown: ... dash or revert to your normal form.
c01533
Wellby: Why would we not just teleport if we need it quick?
c01534
Delwath: We... What would we teleport to?
c01535
Unknown: Yeah.
c01536
Seeker: 'Cause we wanna be, like, not inside of it, but at the edge of it.
c01537
Seeker: We wanna approach it, I think.
c01538
Wellby: We've s... Yeah, we, uh-
c01539
Seeker: We have seen it
c01540
Wellby: ... can we tele- We don't have to teleport...
c01541
Wellby: Do we have to teleport to the ground? Can we teleport to the location above Isengai where we last passed over it?
c01542
Seeker: That seems too dangerous.
c01543
Kenzo: When we got attacked by the tendrils.
c01544
Unknown: Yeah, well, yeah.
c01545
Unknown: I s-
c01546
Delwath: Wait, Seeker just said teleport seems too dangerous?
c01547
Seeker: No, being right above it.
c01548
Unknown: Are, are you okay, Seeker? [laughs]
c01549
Seeker: It's not about the accuracy, which I can guarantee.
c01550
DM: [laughs]
c01551
Unknown: [laughs]
c01552
Seeker: It's about the acid tendrils.
c01553
Delwath: But we could be wind walking.
c01554
Delwath: We could wind walk.
c01555
Seeker: Which really affect my ability to do my job.
c01556
Delwath: And then teleport as wind form and then scatter.
c01557
DM: No, because the only actions you can take are dash or revert.
c01558
Kenzo: Well, I, it feels like we just need to do some reconnaissance, right?
c01559
DM: Yeah.
c01560
Kenzo: So why don't we, why don't we get Vinresharna, like, close-ish?
c01561
DM: It'll take a long time.
c01562
Seeker: Yeah. We'll d- but, well, we'll take it in bursts.
c01563
Seeker: We'll go, we'll go a little ways and then-
c01564
DM: 'Cause the ooze is growing
c01565
Unknown: ... huh?
c01566
DM: The ooze is growing.
c01567
Unknown: How fast?
c01568
Delwath: I didn't think to ask that, but also that's not a yes or no question.
c01569
Seeker: Let's get close enough to Vinresharna that Wind Walk gets us within-
c01570
Unknown: That's what I'm saying
c01571
Seeker: ... a few miles.
c01572
Unknown: Yeah.
c01573
DM: That... You're right now.
c01574
Seeker: Oh.
c01575
Delwath: Oh, let's do it right now then, yeah. If we wind walk now, in eight hours we'd be, like, 10 miles from it.
c01576
DM: You'd be 10 miles away.
c01577
Seeker: Yeah, let's just do that
c01578
DM: ... or 15 miles away.
c01579
Seeker: This is the fastest way for us to get there and-
c01580
Unknown: Yeah
c01581
Kenzo: ... to be able to teleport right on top of it.
c01582
Seeker: Yeah. Great.
c01583
Unknown: Perfect.
c01584
Unknown: Let's do it.
c01585
Unknown: Done.
c01586
DM: So you set Faldric to keep r-
c01587
Unknown: That's actually great
c01588
DM: ... following along behind as he's gotten used to by now.
c01589
DM: Seeker casts Wind Walk, and you fly-
c01590
Delwath: Is that 7th level or 8th level?
c01591
DM: 6th.
c01592
Unknown: 6th level.
c01593
Delwath: Oh, good. So you can still cast Demiplane if we gotta hide.
c01594
DM: Right.
c01595
Unknown: Oh, there you go.
c01596
Seeker: I was looking at the binding stones spells
c01597
Seeker: because I think it's... There's a chance we could guess the proper combination of three stones to bind this creature.
c01598
Delwath: Ooh. I mean, I like Seeker's chances here.
c01599
Unknown: Use-
c01600
Unknown: There's a chan- I mean-
c01601
Seeker: The, the question is-
c01602
Delwath: You mean 100% chance, right, Seeker?
c01603
Unknown: [laughs]
c01604
Seeker: We're talking about my intelligence here.
c01605
Delwath: Right. Yeah, so [laughs] I have full faith in Seeker's ch- magical chances.
c01606
Unknown: But
c01607
Seeker: the question is what
c01608
Seeker: the spell attack this looks like.
c01609
Unknown: Um.
c01610
Seeker: The following spells are rumored to be part of the abilities of the stones.
c01611
Delwath: Imprisonment, is that one of them?
c01612
Seeker: Snare, Web, Watery Sphere, Magic Circle, Planar Binding, and Imprisonment, which I was just looking at.
c01613
Delwath: Imprisonment's pretty good.
c01614
Seeker: But it's not permanent. Or is it?
c01615
Unknown: Wait.
c01616
Delwath: I thought Imprisonment was semi-permanent.
c01617
Wellby: Well, could we show the ooze the mirror?
c01618
Wellby: It probably doesn't have a soul that can [laughs] be trapped that way.
c01619
Unknown: [laughs]
c01620
Wellby: That'd be pretty amazing though.
c01621
Seeker: Oh my God. That's a funny idea.
c01622
Seeker: Where are its eyes though? You know?
c01623
DM: The downside to imprisonment is there's a save.
c01624
Unknown: Right.
c01625
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c01626
Seeker: And this thing, like, probably has legendary resistance to the mirror.
c01627
Unknown: Yes.
c01628
Unknown: Yeah.
c01629
Kenzo: So you can... The, the mirror would never work on anything with a legendary resistance.
c01630
Delwath: I mean, Imprisonment lasts until it's dispelled.
c01631
DM: Right.
c01632
Delwath: But honestly, it feels a little bit like...
c01633
Delwath: That's kind of like-
c01634
Seeker: Shortcutting the whole thing
c01635
Delwath: ... it's shoving the problem down to somebody else, right?
c01636
Delwath: Like, you know [laughs] when somebody comes along and dispels Imprisonment, the ooze'll just come back.
c01637
Kenzo: Well, this is like what I was saying before.
c01638
Kenzo: If we did, like, a, a before, uh, before Talgar our time thing.
c01639
Kenzo: Like, we just, we end the campaign by imprisoning some crazy big ooze.
c01640
Delwath: We imprisoned the ooze at the end of the last campaign [laughs]
c01641
Kenzo: Oh, ex- exactly. Exactly, and then we release it now, you know?
c01642
Seeker: We will use minimus containment.
c01643
Seeker: The target becomes one inch tall and is trapped inside an indestructible gemstone or similar object.
c01644
Delwath: Yeah, but we did that in the previous campaign and it was a little gemstone in limbo that was t- it was trapped and then when Rai tried to pull limbo, the gemstone broke, the spell was
c01645
Delwath: dispelled, and then the ooze came out.
c01646
Unknown: Yeah.
c01647
Unknown: [laughs]
c01648
c01649
Kenzo: That's how the next campaign ends.
c01650
Unknown: Oh.
c01651
Delwath: The next campaign.
c01652
Unknown: [laughs]
c01653
c01654
Unknown: Imprisoning the ooze.
c01655
Unknown: Just an endless series of pushing the problem into the future.
c01656
Unknown: [laughs]
c01657
c01658
Delwath: [laughs] 'Cause it can be dispelled is the point.
c01659
Delwath: Imprisonment's not permanent, it's just until it's dispelled.
c01660
Seeker: Well, we'll just carry it with us in the, in the portal hole.
c01661
Wellby: [laughs] Too big for the hole.
c01662
Seeker: No, it's one inch tall.
c01663
DM: No, no. M- the, the minimus containment is, makes it tiny
c01664
Delwath: ... it's like, you know, it's like the little-
c01665
DM: You trap it in a little gemstone
c01666
Delwath: ... little demon, demon trapped in a gemstone.
c01667
Wellby: Would be crazy enough.
c01668
Delwath: The real problem is it's guaranteed to fail because the ooze is guaranteed to have at least one legendary resistance.
c01669
DM: You'd have to burn all of its legendary resistance first.
c01670
Unknown: We'd have to burn, we'd have to burn all of it.
c01671
Seeker: Yeah. We, we need a variety of tactics here in our pocket.
c01672
Unknown: Now-
c01673
Seeker: This is one option.
c01674
Delwath: The a- Wait, the answer was can we kill it was sort of?
c01675
DM: Can you,
c01676
DM: can you kill it? It was
c01677
DM: y- yeah. Well, it was mostly.
c01678
Unknown: Right. Okay.
c01679
Delwath: So I mean, it is an idea to, to be like, wow, if we, if we wear it down and it's, it's like vulnerable to a spell, then
c01680
Delwath: that's a possibility.
c01681
Seeker: I'd say I'll keep the binding stones in my pocket 'cause they're always in my pocket.
c01682
Unknown: Right.
c01683
Unknown: [laughs]
c01684
Delwath: I mean, nothing could possibly go wrong using them for the very first time in a high stakes combat situation, right?
c01685
Seeker: That's what they've been there for, waiting eternal.
c01686
Kenzo: You need to use the binding... How do you not use the binding stones yet?
c01687
Unknown: That's right.
c01688
Kenzo: You gotta use those.
c01689
Seeker: It's... I've looked at them as an option many times.
c01690
Seeker: It's like, huh.
c01691
Delwath: Th- it's not super clear how they work.
c01692
Delwath: Like, do you have specific th- You don't actually know what they can do, right?
c01693
Seeker: None of the abilities are combat things 'cause, like-
c01694
Unknown: Right
c01695
Seeker: ... imprisonment is one minute, so.
c01696
DM: Right.
c01697
Unknown: Right.
c01698
Seeker: That's really the issue.
c01699
Unknown: Right
c01700
Unknown: Okay, so we are...
c01701
DM: So you now, you fly as
c01702
DM: gaseous clouds,
c01703
DM: 70 miles an hour racing across the landscape of, landscape of the Plaguelands, following the river from,
c01704
DM: that just goes down from the Orenlas Forest to join the Istaros right near Isengai.
c01705
DM: Um, you pass over a
c01706
DM: huge extance- expanse of,
c01707
DM: uh,
c01708
DM: completely
c01709
DM: burned forest with the trees still standing, but blackened and burned.
c01710
Seeker: That's weird.
c01711
DM: Um, you pass over a open,
c01712
DM: um,
c01713
DM: uh-
c01714
Delwath: Wait, that's just south of Orenlas?
c01715
DM: That's, uh, halfway between Orenlas and
c01716
DM: Isengai, roughly.
c01717
Delwath: Do you know what's th- just out of game-
c01718
Unknown: ... do you know what's there? Okay. Wait, I might talk to you about that separately.
c01719
DM: Yeah
c01720
DM: Okay. Um- You pass over
c01721
DM: a,
c01722
DM: um, large expanse of rolling hills, um, and piles of ash and slag that swirl and blow in the wind.
c01723
Wellby: You don't think we did this, right?
c01724
Wellby: You know, this is not related to what happened in Limbo.
c01725
Seeker: Almost certainly there are side effects here of the-
c01726
DM: No, this predates what happened in Limbo.
c01727
Wellby: Okay.
c01728
DM: This is the Plaguelands.
c01729
Wellby: Oh.
c01730
Delwath: I mean, we did it by not stopping Sha'mutte from-
c01731
Wellby: Okay, okay
c01732
Delwath: ... creating the great plague, but-
c01733
Wellby: But this is not related to the, like the ash explosion.
c01734
Unknown: No.
c01735
DM: No.
c01736
Wellby: Okay.
c01737
Unknown: So.
c01738
Wellby: Yeah. Okay.
c01739
DM: And then you, um, cross
c01740
Wellby: Feel better
c01741
DM: a slow meandering ash clogged river,
c01742
DM: and follow it until you can see the edge of this...
c01743
DM: In fact, where wis- where Windwalk ends is basically at the edge of this growing ash storm, which is about 15 miles away from the, from Isengai.
c01744
Seeker: Oh my God.
c01745
DM: And you're standing on a hill,
c01746
DM: a low hill. Actually, as you settle out of wind form your feet sink about six inches into ash,
c01747
DM: and
c01748
DM: you're walking across. It's like a lunar landscape.
c01749
DM: Everything is just coated in
c01750
DM: dust and ash. You're looking-
c01751
Unknown: This might be because of what we did in
c01752
Unknown: Limbo.
c01753
DM: ... you're looking across-
c01754
Kenzo: Ash is a triggering word.
c01755
DM: Yeah. [laughs] You're looking across this growing storm that looks like
c01756
DM: a, almost like a hurricane with winds blowing up to make, that's picking up the ash on the ground and making a, a
c01757
DM: obscured wall
c01758
DM: beyond which you can't see.
c01759
Seeker: So we don't even know if there's news here at all.
c01760
DM: I mean,
c01761
Wellby: Huh
c01762
DM: that's true.
c01763
Seeker: We shouldn't make too many assumptions.
c01764
Seeker: Well, how do we find out what's going on here?
c01765
Seeker: I could clairvoyance inside it-
c01766
Seeker: ... but I'll just see ash.
c01767
DM: Um.
c01768
Delwath: Yep. How far away is it?
c01769
DM: Isengai is about 15 miles from here.
c01770
DM: You're at the edge of the ash storm, and it's creeping towards you.
c01771
Kenzo: Wellby, should you send some animals into this?
c01772
Wellby: Uh, I mean, they, they'll die.
c01773
Wellby: ... we already know what the result will be [laughs].
c01774
Wellby: [laughs]
c01775
Delwath: I mean, I have an i- uh, hold on.
c01776
Unknown: Um.
c01777
Kenzo: How can we recon without-
c01778
Delwath: I have an idea. Can we get a little closer?
c01779
Delwath: Let's go a little closer.
c01780
Unknown: Yeah.
c01781
DM: I mean, you can walk.
c01782
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c01783
Unknown: Walking.
c01784
DM: But you're gonna walk into the storm if you go more than about two miles.
c01785
Delwath: Okay. Let's go to the edge of the storm.
c01786
Delwath: Right. So like, let's, I wanna stop like 500 feet from the edge of the storm.
c01787
DM: Okay. Well, it's not, it's, as you get closer, it's not, it's not like a sharp edge.
c01788
Unknown: Okay.
c01789
DM: It's like there's winds blowing, and you can see maybe 200 yards into the storm as you get closer.
c01790
DM: Just from a distance, it looks
c01791
DM: like, it looks like the edge of a thunderstorm or something, right?
c01792
DM: So there's like, you can see an edge, but there's winds blowing and it's picking up the ash.
c01793
DM: Um, the winds just get more intense as you go in, and so the ash on the ground is being lifted and tossed.
c01794
Delwath: Um, hold on one second.
c01795
Unknown: Uh, there's 10 rounds in a minute.
c01796
Delwath: Wow, this is actually, this can go a long way.
c01797
Delwath: Wait, is that right?
c01798
Delwath: So if something can move,
c01799
Delwath: if something can move
c01800
Delwath: 120 feet and it can m- take two moves in a turn, right, that, if it's running, something that, that can move 120, it could go 240 feet every six seconds, right?
c01801
DM: Yep.
c01802
Delwath: Okay, so 240 feet every six seconds is like half a mile every minute,
c01803
Delwath: right? So in an hour...
c01804
DM: Well, you can't, unless you're in wind form, I mean, you can't dash every round for an hour.
c01805
Delwath: What if you're an intangible creature?
c01806
DM: Possibly then you could, yes.
c01807
Unknown: Um,
c01808
Delwath: oh, no. It can only move...
c01809
Unknown: Yeah, you can up to twice...
c01810
Delwath: Oh, no, no, no, no. It can't.
c01811
Delwath: Never mind, I c- it's only half that speed.
c01812
Delwath: That's okay. It only needs to be half that speed.
c01813
Delwath: Um, 14 miles.
c01814
Unknown: So
c01815
Delwath: 14 miles, I mean, the heart of Isengai is, the, the distance from here to the ooze is probably only
c01816
Delwath: 10 miles, right, we think?
c01817
DM: Somewhere between 10 and 15 miles.
c01818
Delwath: Okay. So when we get close, Delwath will disappear, and an identical copy of Delwath appears right next to Delwath.
c01819
Unknown: Delwath.
c01820
Delwath: And Delwath says, "It's okay, don't, I'm still here, invisible,"
c01821
Delwath: and sends his copy running into the...
c01822
Delwath: This is mislead.
c01823
Wellby: Delwath two.
c01824
Delwath: Yeah, Delwath two. The first new...
c01825
Delwath: Yes. So-
c01826
Unknown: What?
c01827
Unknown: This-
c01828
Seeker: Well, strictly speaking, three, 'cause there was a semi-chron Delwath.
c01829
Unknown: That's true. Um-
c01830
Wellby: Oh, yeah
c01831
Delwath: So it's an illusory double, right?
c01832
Delwath: The double lasts for the duration.
c01833
Delwath: You can move the double up to twice your speed- You can see through its eyes and hear through its air, ears as if you were looking where it was.
c01834
DM: Okay.
c01835
Delwath: That's awesome. That's perfect. So- Wow
c01836
Seeker: ... it can- Run right into the ash. Yeah ...
c01837
Delwath: it just runs right into the ash. It's, it's a,
c01838
Delwath: it's intangible and invulnerable.
c01839
Wellby: That's perfect.
c01840
Kenzo: That's amazing. So perfect.
c01841
DM: Perfect.
c01842
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c01843
Wellby: That's exactly what we need.
c01844
Delwath: So like since my speed is, is 60, it can move 120 each turn.
c01845
Delwath: Then I can take attack, magic action.
c01846
Delwath: So-
c01847
Unknown: One Delwath prime
c01848
Unknown: ... um-
c01849
DM: Very good
c01850
Delwath: ... so it's 120 feet, so every minute it moves 200, it moves 100 and, 1,200 feet.
c01851
DM: It's s- it's 120 feet per round, right?
c01852
Delwath: Yeah. So it can move 14 miles in an hour.
c01853
DM: Okay.
c01854
Delwath: And the spell lasts for an hour, which is why the hour matters.
c01855
DM: Okay.
c01856
Delwath: But I'm just gonna send it...
c01857
Delwath: But it uses my senses, so it has true sight, it has dark vision.
c01858
DM: [sighs]
c01859
Delwath: I mean, I can see through it with my senses as if I-
c01860
DM: As if you were looking
c01861
Seeker: ... as if I'm in its position. What do you see?
c01862
DM: Uh, oh, wait, hold on.
c01863
Unknown: Hmm.
c01864
Kenzo: Didn't think we'd just run right through the ash, did you, Tim?
c01865
DM: Uh, no, I was just calculating, um,
c01866
DM: when it's gonna get to where it, where you see.
c01867
DM: So you run,
c01868
DM: um,
c01869
DM: through
c01870
DM: a growing storm of wind.
c01871
DM: Um, the first couple of miles, uh, is maybe lightly obscured as you're crossing across these sort of rolling hills that were once pleasant agricultural
c01872
DM: valleys. Um, there is no structures remaining here whatsoever.
c01873
DM: Any villages or towns or anything have long since been destroyed.
c01874
DM: Over the course of the next six miles or so, so eight miles total, you,
c01875
DM: ash gets denser and denser until, um, about, I don't know, two thirds of the way into the spell.
c01876
DM: It's, the visibility is something like only about 30 feet in front of you.
c01877
DM: You can see hardly anything.
c01878
DM: Um,
c01879
DM: true sight is irrelevant here 'cause you're, it's ash.
c01880
DM: Um-
c01881
Unknown: Yeah.
c01882
DM: You keep running.
c01883
DM: Uh, slightly further, you, uh, after about 50 minutes, um, or no, it's a little bit before that, um, 45 minutes, you start to
c01884
DM: pass through the...
c01885
DM: Uh, I mean, no, maybe about 50 minutes, the outskirts of what might have been Isengai.
c01886
DM: You can see just every now and then, like mostly it's completely destroyed, but every now and then you'll see a,
c01887
DM: you know, a part of a wall standing or like a little stretch of, um, buildings that kind of make a little bit of a, of a bit of a road,
c01888
DM: pillars standing like that.
c01889
DM: Um,
c01890
DM: at,
c01891
DM: uh,
c01892
DM: 59 minutes and, uh-
c01893
Seeker: Oh, it lasts an hour?
c01894
DM: ... it lasts an hour, and-
c01895
Delwath: Oh, you know what? Hold on.
c01896
Delwath: It lasts two hours.
c01897
Delwath: I'm gonna metamagic it.
c01898
DM: Okay.
c01899
Delwath: It's why, why it's better to double the duration.
c01900
DM: Uh-
c01901
Delwath: It's more useful.
c01902
DM: Okay. Well, at 59 minutes and 24 seconds, um,
c01903
DM: it comes to a,
c01904
DM: like the eye of a hurricane style, like very intense wind tunnel.
c01905
Delwath: No, hold on. I might not be able to do it. Hold on.
c01906
Delwath: I can't rem- Hold on. Keep talking.
c01907
Delwath: A, a- an eye, okay. Yeah.
c01908
DM: And you stumble through into a clear open space.
c01909
Unknown: Ooh.
c01910
DM: Um, about 600 feet across, um, still lightly obscured as m- mist and ash sort of drift in through the center
c01911
DM: of this storm. Um,
c01912
DM: there is,
c01913
DM: uh,
c01914
DM: there's a, there's a dome overhead, so it's like there's a, the clouds, the ash clouds are sort of sitting on top, so you can't see the sky from here.
c01915
DM: Got it. I can only double range, not duration.
c01916
DM: Okay. Well, you have, uh-
c01917
Unknown: 30 seconds
c01918
DM: ... 36 seconds
c01919
DM: of it inside the clear spot.
c01920
DM: Um, three things that you quickly notice from inside the clear spot.
c01921
DM: Uh,
c01922
DM: first, um,
c01923
DM: you can see this is, this is, at the very edge of the clear spot, um, maybe just be- like just beyond the wall, like you can see it sloping down towards the river.
c01924
DM: You can't actually see the river.
c01925
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c01926
DM: It's on the other side of the, of the ash.
c01927
DM: Um, but you can see the docks, like where the, the river port would've started.
c01928
DM: There's a, a few little buildings that suggest.
c01929
DM: Um, there is a, um, in the center here, there's what might have used to have been a plaza or something, or a city well or something like that,
c01930
DM: and you can see like a, a big well like this that's cracked and split.
c01931
DM: And stretching out from the well, you see a one like long pseudopod of some kind of ooze-like creature.
c01932
Delwath: So it's stretching from the well into the ash?
c01933
DM: No, no, into the clear spot.
c01934
DM: It's like-
c01935
Seeker: Mostly it's in the well
c01936
DM: ... mostly it's in the well.
c01937
Unknown: Ah.
c01938
DM: And there's like one pseudopod that comes out of the well and is just like-
c01939
Unknown: Okay
c01940
DM: ... um-
c01941
Unknown: Feeling around
c01942
DM: ... feeling around.
c01943
Seeker: I wonder if it went there to hide from the ash storm.
c01944
Unknown: Maybe.
c01945
Unknown: Yeah. Does this, does it look like it's hiding?
c01946
Kenzo: Does, does it look like it doesn't like the ash?
c01947
Unknown: Does it react to somebody walking up to it?
c01948
DM: Um-
c01949
Delwath: I mean, it looks like Delweth. You don't know it's an illusion unless it-
c01950
DM: Uh, yeah, like three more pseudopods shoot out of the well and start...
c01951
DM: something-
c01952
Delwath: I mean, Delwath
c01953
DM: ... start pulling and crawling, and you start to see like this bubbling mass start to ooze up out of the well-
c01954
Unknown: But I'm sure Delwath would love a sword
c01955
DM: ... and start to rush towards you.
c01956
Delwath: And charge it.
c01957
DM: Okay.
c01958
Unknown: What does it do?
c01959
DM: Uh, it's, um [paper crumpling]
c01960
Unknown: Wait, let me see.
c01961
Unknown: Hm?
c01962
DM: It is going to-
c01963
Unknown: Let me see
c01964
DM: ... three, three pseudopods come flying [whooshing] all three straight towards Delweth once, when you hit about 60 feet away from it.
c01965
DM: Like three of these acidic pods, pseudopods just like shoot out across the plaza to strike at you.
c01966
DM: But nothing happens because you're invulnerable and illusory.
c01967
DM: And now you have about six seconds left.
c01968
DM: [laughs]
c01969
Seeker: So wait, what about Kong's question?
c01970
Unknown: Is it-
c01971
DM: Sorry, what was your question?
c01972
Seeker: Is it harmed by the ash?
c01973
Unknown: The ooze.
c01974
DM: It doesn't,
c01975
DM: it doesn't seem to care about the ash particularly.
c01976
Unknown: Okay.
c01977
Seeker: Huh. Like it doesn't stay inside the eye?
c01978
DM: Well, the, the area's like 600 feet across.
c01979
Unknown: 600, 600.
c01980
DM: It's in the middle.
c01981
DM: What it looks like is that it like lives in the sewers.
c01982
Unknown: Oh.
c01983
DM: [coughs] And it is now crawl...
c01984
DM: It's like was looking at, poked out of this well and is looking around.
c01985
DM: Maybe it's simultaneously looking out of every well in the city.
c01986
DM: [coughs]
c01987
Kenzo: Ah, collective consciousness ooze.
c01988
DM: [clears throat]
c01989
Delwath: Well, double Delweth will charge and disappear.
c01990
DM: Okay.
c01991
Delwath: And then I'll cast Scrying at that spot.
c01992
Unknown: Nice.
c01993
DM: [laughs]
c01994
Delwath: Oh, very good. 'Cause now I've seen it.
c01995
DM: Yep.
c01996
Delwath: So now we can, it, we have in a more leisurely fashion take 10 minutes to look around and see what we see.
c01997
DM: So the... You see now spreading out-
c01998
Delwath: And then we can teleport there
c01999
DM: ... about 100-
c02000
Unknown: [laughs] That's exactly
c02001
Unknown: what it was, yeah
c02002
DM: ... 100 feet.
c02003
Unknown: But-
c02004
DM: Stretching about 100 feet wide, you can see now this like bubbling mass that seems to be searching around the edges of the plaza with these pseudopods, like trying
c02005
DM: to figure out what happened to this creature that vanished.
c02006
Unknown: Is it like-
c02007
Seeker: Not very smart
c02008
Delwath: ... filling up the whole-
c02009
DM: No, it's like 100 f-...
c02010
DM: The, the center of the mass is like maybe only 80 or 100 feet across, but it ha-
c02011
Unknown: Yeah
c02012
DM: ... but these pseudopods extend.
c02013
Delwath: Are there any like buildings or places to hide in this clearing?
c02014
DM: Um, there's,
c02015
DM: uh, all that sur- Like most of this has been,
c02016
DM: it seems actually possibly, um, s- partially consumed by the ooze because as it's bubbling out, you see like little bits of stone and stuff like floating and decaying in this body.
c02017
DM: But there is what might have once been a,
c02018
DM: a, like a, a covered market or something.
c02019
DM: There's a row of columns that are each about 10 feet tall, and then the roof has cracked and fallen down, and there's like a line, a diagonal line that goes about 40 feet long
c02020
DM: of piled rubble.
c02021
Delwath: And did you say before this, the river runs right past this, like the bank of the river?
c02022
DM: The river is like, so I'll just...
c02023
DM: It's not, this is not a to scale sketch, but the basic-
c02024
Unknown: Yeah
c02025
DM: ... to the well, there's like a big plaza like this.
c02026
DM: Somewhere like here is the river, but you can't see it 'cause the ash goes like that.
c02027
DM: But you can see like docks and infrastructure that suggests the river is that way.
c02028
Delwath: Okay, so this was probably a riverside plaza.
c02029
DM: Yeah, and then there's a, what once was a market here where all that remains is the front row of columns.
c02030
Unknown: Excellent.
c02031
DM: But there's a roof that fell and, um, f- forms a line of rubble.
c02032
Delwath: I'm just trying to think about why this would be- So- ...
c02033
Delwath: an eye of a storm.
c02034
Seeker: I was wondering the same thing. Why is it here?
c02035
Kenzo: Okay, so one, one thing.
c02036
Kenzo: Do we have ways, 'cause like it feels like- Water back ...
c02037
Kenzo: it feels like we're gonna have to end up in the sewer.
c02038
Kenzo: Like, like wherever the ooze, the ooze is like down.
c02039
Kenzo: Yeah. It's down there someplace, so.
c02040
Delwath: Or we draw it out. Yeah.
c02041
Kenzo: Draw it out. Or we draw it out, but I'll, I'll...
c02042
Kenzo: Like again, it, it feels like however we're gonna defeat this thing, it's not gonna be like, like chopping off some pseudopod tendrils.
c02043
Kenzo: Right. You know what I mean? There must be like some core or something- There's like a- ...
c02044
Kenzo: or brain or something ... exactly, exactly, exactly. There's, there's gotta be s- And that's likely deep underground.
c02045
Seeker: The ooze nugget. What's that? The ooze nugget.
c02046
Kenzo: Yeah, whatever. The ooze, yeah.
c02047
Kenzo: The ooze, the ooze central nervous system brain thing.
c02048
Kenzo: It's like a super giant thing. Is there a way for us to like explore in the sewers, like without going there?
c02049
Kenzo: Like can we like, uh, you know, drone map it or something?
c02050
Kenzo: Like how do we, uh...
c02051
Seeker: Oh, 'cause your thing that you can send out can't go very far, but we can send a bat to Del- The thing I can send out can go super far.
c02052
Seeker: It's just- Oh, the one you just did. Yeah. Can you do that again?
c02053
Delwath: Yeah, but we have to be...
c02054
Delwath: The problem is we're 50 miles from- But we're at the r- we're at range.
c02055
Delwath: We're 50 miles from here. Yeah.
c02056
Delwath: So I can create an illusory double of myself that lasts for an hour.
c02057
Delwath: Huh. But, and it can move twice my speed,
c02058
Delwath: but otherwise it's the same as Delweth.
c02059
Delwath: So like it doesn't have-
c02060
Kenzo: We can't like cast spells and fight and stuff.
c02061
Delwath: No.
c02062
Kenzo: Yeah. No, but for, for, this is perfect.
c02063
Kenzo: For, for the reconnaissance it's perfect.
c02064
Kenzo: We, so we wanna go... Yeah. Like, right?
c02065
Delwath: Like is there a good way to map the sewer?
c02066
Delwath: I mean- Or go check out the sewer without going in there ...
c02067
Seeker: can we animal shape to, you fly out above the eye of the storm, briefly turn into Delweth while falling, cast your double,
c02068
Delwath: and then you can-
c02069
Unknown: And then die [laughs]
c02070
Seeker: ... re animal shape and then fly back.
c02071
Delwath: No, you have to re-animal shape me.
c02072
Seeker: I can't from this distance.
c02073
Seeker: Exactly. Can you switch... I think you can go back and forth, right?
c02074
Delwath: Can you switch yourself with animal shape?
c02075
Seeker: I think so. Okay.
c02076
Kenzo: Tim, is the sewer, is the ooze just like clogging up a sewer entirely or is it, or the, like the well- Why don't you, why don't you...
c02077
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Yeah, uh, Tim, fucking, uh, commune with nature.
c02078
Kenzo: What the hell's going on? Yeah, yeah.
c02079
DM: Ah.
c02080
Unknown: Oh, oh my God. Oh my God.
c02081
DM: So many things are going on.
c02082
Kenzo: Yeah. Can you... So, oh my God, what the fuck do I do?
c02083
Kenzo: [laughs] Commune with nature and then also, yeah, dude, like, like the ooze like, like 'cause it's, it's an, it's an entity, right?
c02084
Kenzo: It's got consciousness. Like- Can't you get like a radar map?
c02085
Kenzo: That's what I'm saying. Yeah, well also to...
c02086
Kenzo: And, and if it is, like it, this is actually really interesting.
c02087
Kenzo: Is the consciousness like uniformly, um, exhibited throughout the physical system of the ooze?
c02088
Unknown: Mm.
c02089
DM: Mm.
c02090
Kenzo: Or is it centralized into like a, you know, like the core, the brain of the consciousness is like, you know, deep down.
c02091
Kenzo: Anyways, what's going on?
c02092
DM: Ah, okay.
c02093
Unknown: Commune with nature first.
c02094
DM: Uh, yes.
c02095
DM: Um, actually for this one I'm gonna say make a insight check.
c02096
Unknown: Okay.
c02097
DM: Um, it has to be Seeker that turns, that turns back in.
c02098
DM: It's the spell cast that brings her back.
c02099
Seeker: That's what I thought. I was just looking it up and found that out too.
c02100
Kenzo: What's my, is my insight like plus a billion now?
c02101
Unknown: [die thuds]
c02102
DM: Your insight is gonna be like, it's gonna be plus high now 'cause you've got better wisdom.
c02103
DM: Plus 12 or 13 or something like that.
c02104
DM: [die thuds]
c02105
Seeker: Yeah. [paper rustles] Plus 12, that's nice.
c02106
Unknown: [paper rustles] [upbeat music]
c02107
DM: It's sick.
c02108
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Wow. Oh my God.
c02109
Kenzo: Oh, this is so cool. All my things are so much more awesome now.
c02110
Kenzo: This is great. All right. [paper rustles] Plus 12.
c02111
Unknown: [paper rustles]
c02112
DM: Okay.
c02113
Unknown: Wait.
c02114
DM: So Kenzo goes into his trance and reaches out your consciousness for, you can now stretch something like 40 miles or something like that.
c02115
DM: Um.
c02116
Kenzo: Wow. [upbeat music] I could do 39 before, so it's gotta be more than that.
c02117
DM: Oh, yeah. It's-
c02118
Unknown: Whatever
c02119
DM: ... yeah, yeah. Whatever. It doesn't matter.
c02120
DM: It's plenty long enough to, to get a sense of this place.
c02121
DM: Um,
c02122
DM: there are...
c02123
DM: The first, the first thing you notice is that there is,
c02124
DM: um,
c02125
DM: there is not a single, there's not like one...
c02126
DM: You don't sense any like single consciousness.
c02127
Unknown: Mm.
c02128
DM: In fact, it's hard to describe this as a consciousness at all.
c02129
DM: What you sense is a,
c02130
DM: a
c02131
DM: like just a disordering of...
c02132
DM: It's actually like, it reminds you of the Heartroot, but completely inverted by chaos.
c02133
Kenzo: Ooh, Chaosroot.
c02134
DM: And it's stre- like you can see actually the n- you actually suspect that what you're seeing in your mind as you stretch through is like a map of the sewers-
c02135
Unknown: Mm.
c02136
DM: ... and tunnels underneath the city where you see like lines of this.
c02137
DM: It's almost like the filamentous like-
c02138
Kenzo: Yeah, mycelial
c02139
DM: ... mycelial of the Heartroot.
c02140
Unknown: Yeah
c02141
DM: But all like Limbo Ooze network instead.
c02142
DM: [paper rustles]
c02143
Delwath: So it's the anti Heartroot.
c02144
Wellby: Yeah.
c02145
DM: But it is concentrated most strongly in,
c02146
DM: uh, it is densest, the like structure is densest in three places.
c02147
Unknown: Okay.
c02148
Wellby: Three places.
c02149
DM: Um,
c02150
DM: one is in the river.
c02151
Unknown: Mm.
c02152
DM: The second is, um,
c02153
DM: what you guess is this pl- like it, what it feels like is...
c02154
DM: So you're doing this while Delwath is scrying and you're sort of layering on your like radar consciousness map of what Delwath is seeing, and it feels like it's dr- like
c02155
DM: it's condensing.
c02156
DM: So around the s- the center of this plaza, the consciousness is very thin and it's all like pulled together into a, it's almost like it extract, it pulled bits of itself
c02157
DM: from all the sewers around here to emerge out and search for Delwath.
c02158
DM: Right? So it's like the density is higher here.
c02159
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
c02160
DM: It's condensed here.
c02161
DM: [coughs]
c02162
Unknown: That's just nice. Wait, there's a third.
c02163
DM: The third is at this, there is something else at this location that doesn't feel like a consciousness.
c02164
DM: It feels like,
c02165
DM: um,
c02166
DM: so-
c02167
Wellby: Hang on. Something else, like not the Ooze whatsoever at all?
c02168
DM: Maybe it's related to the ooze.
c02169
DM: It's hard to say.
c02170
DM: It's...
c02171
DM: So when you were, when you were attempt- when you were like vibing with the tree in-
c02172
Unknown: Yeah
c02173
DM: ... Limbo, right, and you got your little chaos key,
c02174
DM: uh,
c02175
DM: there's a,
c02176
DM: there's like a flavor of the plane that you sensed and there's like a scar, like a nodule or some kind of,
c02177
DM: um,
c02178
DM: something like that that has the same taste in your mind.
c02179
DM: Some like little bit of Limbo at the bottom of this well.
c02180
Kenzo: The bottom of this well. So the bottom of the well, the riverbank, and where's the third place again?
c02181
DM: The plaza.
c02182
Kenzo: The plaza in general. Okay.
c02183
Kenzo: [paper rustles] Okay. All right. Communicate that to all the friends.
c02184
Unknown: Um,
c02185
Kenzo: so, but j- just to, you know, 'cause c- communication, like, uh, is what's the, what's the deal with like other, other kind of like life forms?
c02186
DM: So there's v- there's nothing else alive in this.
c02187
DM: There's nothing that's not part, somehow part of the ooze that's alive in this, okay?
c02188
Unknown: Yeah.
c02189
DM: The storm is clearly unnatural.
c02190
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c02191
DM: And you can sense that it's growing as well.
c02192
Unknown: The storm is unnatural.
c02193
DM: And it is centered on this like little nodule of Limbo.
c02194
Delwath: Oh. Which, the one in...?
c02195
DM: At the bottom of the well.
c02196
Unknown: Right. Okay. [paper rustles]
c02197
Kenzo: The bottom of the well, plaza, and river.
c02198
Wellby: Those are the three-
c02199
Unknown: Wait
c02200
Wellby: ... those are the three-
c02201
Delwath: The bottom of the well and the plaza are two different...
c02202
Unknown: They're the same.
c02203
DM: Well, they're just...
c02204
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
c02205
Wellby: Bottom of the well, like but-
c02206
DM: Plaza top, bottom of the well bottom.
c02207
Delwath: Okay. But like the, the-
c02208
DM: That well, yes, yes, yes
c02209
Delwath: ... the eye of the storm is where two of the nodules are effectively.
c02210
DM: Well, the, the concentration of ooze matter is on top of the plaza, and then the nodule of Limbo is at the bottom of the well.
c02211
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
c02212
Unknown: [die thuds]
c02213
DM: And then the river is also the, another high concentration of ooze matter.
c02214
Kenzo: Uh, well, last,
c02215
Unknown: we have to come-
c02216
Kenzo: I feel like we have to fight our way, better fight our way down there.
c02217
DM: Not first and just-
c02218
Kenzo: Just c- just, just do it
c02219
Wellby: ... get it over with?
c02220
Kenzo: I mean, I mean we could teleport and just see what happens.
c02221
Wellby: Like brain, right?
c02222
DM: Uh. [laughs]
c02223
Kenzo: I know approximately where the nodule is.
c02224
Wellby: We could st- are there any of them where there's an easier exit than the other that we could go in and sort of do our exploratory expedition first?
c02225
Seeker: Right. Map a route through the sewers for us.
c02226
Wellby: Yeah.
c02227
Seeker: ... not from the plaza, but from somewhere else.
c02228
Delwath: I mean, when did the, when did my double start getting into the...
c02229
Delwath: Like how big is the city? Like how far is it from here to the edge of the city?
c02230
DM: Uh, that was about... The city, Isingue is never, was never a big city, right?
c02231
DM: So it's, I don't know, a-
c02232
Unknown: A mile?
c02233
DM: Yeah, something like that, right? It's like not a large...
c02234
DM: And this, this is, this, the docks are close to the center of the city.
c02235
Delwath: Right. So maybe not even. Maybe it's a mile.
c02236
DM: Less than a mile.
c02237
Delwath: Like a half a mile.
c02238
DM: So it's probably half a mile from the edge of the city.
c02239
Unknown: [coughs]
c02240
DM: The sewers don't extend...
c02241
DM: Right, like the storm, Kenzo, which says the s- the storm extends way beyond the edge of the city itself.
c02242
Unknown: Right. Right.
c02243
DM: And the ooze, the ooze is just concentrated in the city, in the sewers of the city.
c02244
Delwath: But the, the ooze didn't seem to react to my...
c02245
Delwath: I mean, there was no reaction to my...
c02246
Delwath: Do we have any reason to think we would be in danger sneaking into the ash?
c02247
Delwath: I mean, other than the fact that the ash might have all kinds of bad...
c02248
Delwath: I just, if we get closer, we have a lot more options.
c02249
DM: Yeah.
c02250
Seeker: Did we learn anything from defeating the crazy ash centipede
c02251
DM: goblin army thing?
c02252
DM: Like the chaos key.
c02253
Wellby: That would be relevant here?
c02254
DM: Yeah. 'Cause-
c02255
Seeker: Didn't we end up using radiant damage against it?
c02256
Delwath: No, it was resistant to radiant.
c02257
DM: It was resistant to radiant.
c02258
Delwath: Can you soul sight the ooze from here?
c02259
Unknown: Well, I was gonna say, yeah.
c02260
Delwath: No, probably not.
c02261
Kenzo: Not, not from here, but, um, but Tim, I-
c02262
DM: From an edge of, from the edge of the sewer you could.
c02263
Kenzo: Tim, Kenzo will, uh, um, kind of engage the ooze consciousness.
c02264
Kenzo: Like I'm gonna, um...
c02265
Seeker: Just let it know we're here.
c02266
Kenzo: Well, um, so basically what I'm kind of curious about is like i- i- 'cause you kind of asked it does it have goals?
c02267
Unknown: Yeah.
c02268
Unknown: Right? And it doesn't.
c02269
Unknown: No.
c02270
Unknown: It did not. Right?
c02271
Unknown: Yeah.
c02272
Seeker: But it might want to go home.
c02273
Kenzo: Yeah. So that, that's what... It's like, it's like does it, is it, is it just, um...
c02274
Kenzo: Yeah, I kind of reach out to the ooze consciousness and...
c02275
Kenzo: This is sort of like when animals try to like kind of...
c02276
Kenzo: Like I, I get close so that like the, the ooze consciousness maybe-
c02277
Seeker: It can sniff your hand, yeah.
c02278
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. It's kind of like aware that there's like something else there.
c02279
Delwath: Do we know, do we know it is... No.
c02280
Delwath: Oh, sorry. Finish.
c02281
Kenzo: So i- is there like a sensation that the ooze is just like,
c02282
Kenzo: is just like kind of reacting and like lashing out and just like...
c02283
Kenzo: Or, or is it like,
c02284
Kenzo: Yeah. Is there something there? Is it soothable?
c02285
Unknown: Is it like-
c02286
DM: So you don't have any sense that it has a...
c02287
Unknown: Agency or-
c02288
DM: Yeah, it's not, um...
c02289
DM: It's not, it doesn't react to your mind as if ev- as if it has like conscious will.
c02290
Delwath: So like a Limbo slime mold?
c02291
DM: It's basically a... Yeah.
c02292
Unknown: Yeah.
c02293
DM: It's a Limbo slime mold.
c02294
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
c02295
DM: Right?
c02296
Unknown: Got it. Got it. And then-
c02297
Seeker: I was thinking about slime mold, yeah
c02298
Kenzo: And then the three, the three nodules, like you know, like there's like kind of more density.
c02299
Kenzo: Like is there a sense that at the more dense nodules, like maybe the consciousness is a little different?
c02300
Kenzo: Like is it more intelligent at the nodules, or is it just the whole thing is kind of...
c02301
DM: No. It's not.
c02302
DM: It just seems... It al- I mean, it's almost seemed like it was...
c02303
DM: Like a slime mold is, is really the best way to think about it, right?
c02304
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
c02305
DM: It's
c02306
DM: not, um...
c02307
DM: It doesn't have the, it doesn't have anything like the sort of sentience and, and sort of will that the Heartroot does, right?
c02308
Unknown: Okay.
c02309
DM: It's like... But it is like the anti-Heartroot in that it's like a network of these-
c02310
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah
c02311
DM: ... slime tendrils, but it seems to operate like entirely on instinct.
c02312
DM: And instinct is just make everything Limbo.
c02313
Unknown: Got it.
c02314
Unknown: Um.
c02315
Unknown: the quest- the answer to did it have allies was sort of?
c02316
DM: No, the answer to allies was no.
c02317
Delwath: Oh, no. Okay.
c02318
DM: But that's just because it's all part of the same thing.
c02319
Kenzo: Well, this i- this is like cancer. You just need to like chemotherapy it and just like-
c02320
Unknown: Right.
c02321
Kenzo: How do we, how do we like nuke the whole thing?
c02322
Unknown: Water.
c02323
Delwath: magic damage,
c02324
Unknown: Fire.
c02325
Kenzo: Let's go try to destroy one of the nodules and see what, how it goes.
c02326
Unknown: We'll learn a lot.
c02327
Wellby: Yeah. We'll start with one.
c02328
Kenzo: We'll learn a lot by trying to like-
c02329
Unknown: Exactly
c02330
Kenzo: ... you know.
c02331
Seeker: I, I'm wondering if we can send it back to Limbo somehow.
c02332
Unknown: But is it...
c02333
Delwath: Hmm. The answer of was it from Limbo was sort of.
c02334
Unknown: Hmm.
c02335
Kenzo: Cool if we could like, talk to it or something, but...
c02336
Kenzo: Can we show it to the mirror?
c02337
Unknown: [laughs] That's interesting.
c02338
Unknown: The ooze.
c02339
Seeker: In principle, yes.
c02340
Delwath: I mean, possibly we could go...
c02341
Delwath: We could do a reconnaissance mission to get a piece of it,
c02342
Unknown: right?
c02343
Seeker: Oh, that's a fun idea.
c02344
Delwath: And then like retreat.
c02345
Kenzo: I kind of like that. I want to learn about this thing 'cause I thought it was like, you know, it's like a little like...
c02346
Seeker: How... Okay. How are we gonna get some?
c02347
Unknown: Hmm.
c02348
Delwath: Well, we want to go to the edge of the city and like enter a sewer or something like that where-
c02349
Kenzo: Well, it's, it's super reactive.
c02350
Kenzo: It'll come. It'll, it's gonna-
c02351
Unknown: Yeah
c02352
Kenzo: ... it's gonna come try to attack us.
c02353
Wellby: Yeah. Let's just pick one place and go for it.
c02354
Seeker: What is the hazard of walking through the ash?
c02355
Unknown: Let's find out.
c02356
Kenzo: Uh, can we send something to gauge?
c02357
Unknown: [laughs] Kenzo.
c02358
Seeker: Someone goes first into the ash to find out what it's like.
c02359
Unknown: Yeah.
c02360
Unknown: I mean, I have an astral project.
c02361
Unknown: You can be astral. Yeah.
c02362
Kenzo: Yeah. I'll, I'll, okay, that's fine. Yeah, I'll, I'll, I'll, uh, I'll be an astral, uh...
c02363
DM: Just astral project and go as a...
c02364
DM: Yeah, okay.
c02365
Kenzo: I'll just step into it and see what happens.
c02366
DM: Um.
c02367
Seeker: Oh, oh, oh, we forgot to do Seeker Seven overnight.
c02368
Seeker: I mean, we were very tired.
c02369
Unknown: Oh, wow.
c02370
Seeker: Did we do that? Should we have done that?
c02371
Delwath: Wait, and weren't we talking about doing Hero's Feast?
c02372
Seeker: We also forgot to do that.
c02373
Unknown: Um.
c02374
Delwath: But we could...
c02375
Delwath: Uh, it's the end of... I mean, I think it's reasonable.
c02376
Delwath: I, here's, here's my suggestion on the plan.
c02377
Delwath: We do a reconnaissance. We get a piece of it, right?
c02378
Seeker: We can take our time after this.
c02379
Delwath: We study it, right?
c02380
Delwath: We... There's a few things we can do with the piece of it, right?
c02381
Delwath: Like in theory, reconnaissance, Kenzo can s- soul sight it.
c02382
Delwath: We can-
c02383
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c02384
Delwath: And then long-
c02385
Unknown: Show the mirror. Show the mirror
c02386
Delwath: ... and then we'll long rest.
c02387
Seeker: Okay. Let's, let's do all that.
c02388
Delwath: Right? Before we actually enter, we'll like retreat to somewhere a little bit safe.
c02389
Delwath: We'll camp.
c02390
Unknown: Right.
c02391
Delwath: We'll do a long rest so we can pick one, either Hero's Feast or Seeker Seven.
c02392
Seeker: Yeah. Okay.
c02393
Unknown: Right.
c02394
Seeker: Great. Good idea.
c02395
Seeker: Thank you, Tim. Thank you.
c02396
Unknown: We do all that.
c02397
DM: Okay. So who's... Wait, who's going into the ash first?
c02398
Unknown: So-
c02399
DM: Ken's our astral projection.
c02400
DM: Make-
c02401
Kenzo: I, well, it's, I'm like, I'm like, I astral...
c02402
Kenzo: And then, and then like I stick my pinky in.
c02403
DM: Well, nothing happens when you stick your-
c02404
Unknown: [laughs]
c02405
DM: Nothing happens when you stick your pinky in.
c02406
Unknown: There's not like a clear edge.
c02407
DM: And it's not a sharp boundary, right?
c02408
DM: It just, on the edge it-
c02409
Unknown: Yeah
c02410
DM: ... it just gets increasingly...
c02411
DM: [machine beeping] What was that?
c02412
Unknown: Dishwasher?
c02413
DM: Is the fridge open or is the coffee, or is that the coffee pot?
c02414
DM: No, that was the coffee pot turning off.
c02415
Wellby: Coffee powering her.
c02416
Unknown: The coffee pot is off.
c02417
Kenzo: Okay. All right. Kenzo will just walk.
c02418
Unknown: Just...
c02419
DM: Make a constitution saving throw.
c02420
Unknown: Damn it.
c02421
Seeker: So there is some hazard of the ash.
c02422
Kenzo: When, when, when did, when did, when did I have to make it?
c02423
Kenzo: Like, what ha- at what point did I get to something that triggers a constitution-
c02424
DM: Um, you go in maybe...
c02425
DM: Uh, it's... Actually, sorry, actually, don't make a constitution saving throw 'cause the first bit of the...
c02426
DM: For a while, the ash is fairly thin, right?
c02427
DM: So it's just... Like you can see it's, it's like lightly obscured.
c02428
DM: You can still see a few hundred feet.
c02429
DM: You can feel the sort of ash blowing against you.
c02430
DM: The winds are sort of very variable, like blowing in all sorts of directions and, um...
c02431
DM: but it's like, I mean, like you're...
c02432
DM: It's hard to breathe.
c02433
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c02434
DM: And as you go deeper, as it gets more and more obscured...
c02435
Kenzo: So how far have I walked now?
c02436
DM: Like maybe a mile.
c02437
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Okay.
c02438
Kenzo: So I, I'm c- I can still tell that and communicate with the team.
c02439
Unknown: Yeah.
c02440
Kenzo: I'm giving them a, a full update.
c02441
Unknown: Yeah.
c02442
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
c02443
DM: So about a mile in, make a constitution saving throw
c02444
Kenzo: Uh-oh. 12.
c02445
DM: You are poisoned.
c02446
Kenzo: Bardic. No, I'm not. I'm immune to poison.
c02447
DM: Oh, you are not poisoned.
c02448
Kenzo: [laughs] I tell everybody, "I would've been poisoned if I, if I could be."
c02449
DM: You're just choking on the ash, right?
c02450
Unknown: Yeah, ash.
c02451
DM: It's like toxic.
c02452
Kenzo: This sucks. Okay.
c02453
Unknown: I come back.
c02454
DM: Okay.
c02455
Wellby: What did we learn?
c02456
Kenzo: Uh, it's poisonous ash. Like you guys will probably choke on it.
c02457
Kenzo: I'm immune to poison, but you guys will probably, uh...
c02458
Kenzo: So you know, the, the, the, uh, the eye of the storm place where there's no ash, that's a good place to be.
c02459
Wellby: Maybe let's go there.
c02460
Unknown: Yeah.
c02461
Wellby: Yeah.
c02462
DM: Um,
c02463
Delwath: right. But then the ooze will attack us.
c02464
Kenzo: So but if our goal is just to do like a little reconnaissance, then we could just like teleport there,
c02465
Kenzo: grab a little ooze.
c02466
Delwath: Let it attack us, like cut off a piece of it and flee?
c02467
Unknown: Yeah.
c02468
Seeker: Do we all need to go?
c02469
Wellby: [laughs]
c02470
Unknown: [laughs]
c02471
Delwath: Well, we need Seeker. He has teleport.
c02472
Unknown: Yeah.
c02473
Wellby: [laughs] Do we all need to go?
c02474
Seeker: 'Cause I have like some other shit to do, so...
c02475
Unknown: Oh, no.
c02476
Wellby: Doctor's appointment. [laughs] Oh my God, is it Tuesday?
c02477
Unknown: [laughs]
c02478
Unknown: [laughs] Um, I mean...
c02479
Unknown: [laughs]
c02480
Delwath: The other option is to-
c02481
Wellby: Do people.
c02482
Unknown: [laughs]
c02483
Delwath: The, there's another option here which is to, to, to, um...
c02484
Unknown: I was gonna take a nap today.
c02485
Wellby: [laughs]
c02486
Unknown: How about
c02487
Unknown: nah.
c02488
DM: Seeker's really ready to settle down.
c02489
Unknown: Yeah, this is like-
c02490
DM: This adventuring thing is getting him.
c02491
Kenzo: It's like this reluctant golden dragon.
c02492
Unknown: [laughs]
c02493
Delwath: Like this is like... [laughs]
c02494
Seeker: I've just had my, my cloak dry cleaned again.
c02495
Unknown: [laughs] I know.
c02496
Wellby: You just had a vision of like the entire multiverse.
c02497
Wellby: Like you just had the most intense trip of your life.
c02498
Wellby: That's so true. Right. That's so true.
c02499
Wellby: You know? Like-
c02500
Unknown: You saw the whole multiverse
c02501
Wellby: ... guys, none of this is real, man.
c02502
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs] Um,
c02503
Delwath: it's poison is the problem?
c02504
DM: Yes.
c02505
Wellby: It's all self-transforming machine elves.
c02506
Unknown: So-
c02507
c02508
Delwath: Uh, green dragons are immune to poison.
c02509
Unknown: Interesting.
c02510
Wellby: How many of us could be green dragons?
c02511
Unknown: Two.
c02512
DM: Well, Hero of Ceas makes you immune to poison.
c02513
Unknown: Oh.
c02514
Wellby: Maybe we could have Hero-
c02515
Delwath: Well, so- Hey, hey.
c02516
Delwath: That's something ... so, but here's...
c02517
Unknown: So
c02518
Delwath: we could um,
c02519
Delwath: we could do a
c02520
Delwath: Kenzo and Delwath.
c02521
Delwath: I could turn into a green dragon, Kenzo could ride my back.
c02522
Delwath: We could fly in, get a piece of the ooze, and get out.
c02523
Kenzo: That's cool. I can still soul sight it.
c02524
Seeker: And Wellby and I do really important work back here in the meantime.
c02525
Delwath: Like your dentist appointment.
c02526
Unknown: Yeah.
c02527
Unknown: That sounds like a plan.
c02528
Wellby: And some laundry.
c02529
Delwath: [laughs] I mean, that's an immune to poison strategy that works pretty well.
c02530
Kenzo: That's true. Yeah, we're both immune to poison.
c02531
Kenzo: We roll up, fly through the ash,
c02532
Kenzo: go and... Look, I just want to soul sight it.
c02533
Delwath: Soul sighting it would be very useful. Yeah, and I think if we can like swoop down and like take a piece of it
c02534
Delwath: somehow. Yeah. We wanna like bring back a piece of the ooze.
c02535
Kenzo: That would be cool. Right? And then you could run some tests on it.
c02536
Delwath: And we could run some tests.
c02537
Unknown: Mm. Love it.
c02538
Kenzo: Right?
c02539
Unknown: Love it. And then, then show it to the mirror.
c02540
Unknown: Yeah.
c02541
Kenzo: I wanna show the fucking ooze to the mirror.
c02542
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c02543
Kenzo: Like that's gotta... That's gonna be fun.
c02544
Delwath: Because actually, we could...
c02545
Delwath: Why are we not just...
c02546
Delwath: Well, hold on. Here's an even better idea.
c02547
Unknown: Um,
c02548
Delwath: teleport back to Vintasharna.
c02549
Delwath: We'll r- take a piece of dirt from right here,
c02550
Delwath: right? Ah. Then teleport back to Ventasharna.
c02551
DM: You can't rainbow bridge. It takes seven days to recharge.
c02552
Delwath: Oh, we already used our rainbow bridge.
c02553
Delwath: Never mind. It's not gonna work.
c02554
Delwath: Forget it. Mm-hmm.
c02555
Delwath: Nah, it's fine. We'll just fly. Let's take- Okay.
c02556
Seeker: Let's do it. Let's do it ... the fly. Yeah.
c02557
DM: Okay, green dragon and Kenzo.
c02558
DM: The poison-
c02559
Delwath: Delwath turns into a dragon
c02560
DM: ... and the dragon.
c02561
Unknown: Yes. [laughs] Now only, only Wellby needs to become a dragon.
c02562
Delwath: Are you sure you don't wanna be a dragon sometime?
c02563
Wellby: I mean, I would love to be.
c02564
Kenzo: Th- this is actually kind of a cool thing to be a dragon for is this.
c02565
Wellby: Yeah, that's pretty cool.
c02566
Unknown: You know?
c02567
DM: But only one of you.
c02568
Wellby: I would burn that...
c02569
Wellby: Oh, yeah.
c02570
Delwath: I can only tel- t- polymorph one person at a time.
c02571
Delwath: Okay. But tomorrow. There's no way a dragon.
c02572
Wellby: Is it, uh, is it concentration?
c02573
DM: No. No.
c02574
Kenzo: No, no, no. I'm riding the dragon. Yeah.
c02575
Wellby: Polymorph?
c02576
Unknown: Oh, oh, oh, okay, cool. Don't worry. Delwath can do it.
c02577
Wellby: I mean, that's just so me and you.
c02578
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c02579
Wellby: I'm gonna have better perception-
c02580
Unknown: We're, we're gonna be social this episode
c02581
Wellby: ... and things too.
c02582
Unknown: I'm sure every-
c02583
Wellby: If we run into a fight-
c02584
Delwath: That's a good idea
c02585
Wellby: ... and you wanna polymorph the dragon.
c02586
Delwath: No, no, no, no, no. You know what? I should...
c02587
Delwath: I'm... No. Change of plan.
c02588
Delwath: Sorry. Uh, Wellby's gonna be the dragon.
c02589
Delwath: Yes. Right?
c02590
Delwath: Because then Delwath won't take any...
c02591
Delwath: Like I can maintain concentration.
c02592
Delwath: Perfect. Right? Now, here's another question.
c02593
Seeker: Um- And you can do
c02594
DM: How fast can a dragon fly?
c02595
Unknown: Well,
c02596
Unknown: uh-
c02597
Wellby: So fast.
c02598
Seeker: [laughs] Um, the- It's really fast ...
c02599
Delwath: the other question here is...
c02600
Delwath: Okay, hold on. I'm gonna ask you.
c02601
Delwath: A dragon can fly... A green dragon can fly 80.
c02602
Delwath: Right? So is that close? Are we gonna...
c02603
Delwath: But you don't have to go to-
c02604
Wellby: Uh, I lose items in polymorph?
c02605
Wellby: Do I retain class abilities like-
c02606
Delwath: No. You retain no abilities.
c02607
Delwath: You attain your personality alignment.
c02608
Wellby: All right.
c02609
Unknown: That's it.
c02610
Wellby: But I have wings.
c02611
Delwath: Um, but you can fly-
c02612
Delwath: 'Cause you're a fucking dragon.
c02613
Wellby: Sweet.
c02614
Delwath: Um, but the...
c02615
Delwath: We don't have to go to the center.
c02616
Wellby: [laughs]
c02617
Delwath: They're just trying to find a point where there is ooze.
c02618
Unknown: Yeah. They're just trying to get to the surface.
c02619
DM: Right, but you have to get, you have to go 14 miles into the storm to get to the edge of the city.
c02620
Wellby: That's right.
c02621
Unknown: Ah.
c02622
DM: Or it's not quite that. It's-
c02623
Unknown: So-
c02624
DM: ... 13 and a half to the center. You have to go 13 miles into the storm.
c02625
Delwath: So let's figure out how far.
c02626
DM: So you can go 800 feet a minute.
c02627
DM: [dice rolling]
c02628
Delwath: So let's figure out how, and then there's a, I have a question about, um-
c02629
Wellby: Wait. Why is the time a problem though?
c02630
Unknown: 'Cause-
c02631
DM: So that's nine miles per hour.
c02632
DM: You're not gonna make it.
c02633
Unknown: It's one hour.
c02634
Unknown: I mean, you'll be permanently a dragon.
c02635
DM: [laughs]
c02636
Wellby: How many times can you cast it?
c02637
Delwath: Just once, but h- but hold on.
c02638
Delwath: You can't... Isn't it until dispelled?
c02639
DM: Yeah, you, somebody, Seeker could dispel it.
c02640
Delwath: Can I just dispel it?
c02641
DM: No, y- you need to-
c02642
Wellby: You need to dispel magic
c02643
DM: ... dispel means somebody needs to cast dispel magic.
c02644
Delwath: No, I know, I know, but can I just cast dispel magic-
c02645
DM: Yeah, yeah
c02646
Unknown: ... and it's a dispel?
c02647
DM: But you don't auto succeed.
c02648
DM: It's a ninth level spell, so you have to beat the ability check.
c02649
DM: Unless you cast it with a ninth level slot, which you don't have.
c02650
Unknown: Right.
c02651
DM: Seeker could cast dispel magic with a ninth level slot.
c02652
DM: Or I could cast it with this and then I would auto succeed with dispel magic.
c02653
Wellby: That's like bardic inspiration.
c02654
DM: [laughs]
c02655
Wellby: Like we, you know this a-
c02656
Delwath: Are you okay with this, like [laughs] are you okay with this?
c02657
Seeker: This is the risk of permanent dragon.
c02658
Unknown: [laughs]
c02659
Wellby: The question is, am I okay with permanently being a giant green dragon?
c02660
Unknown: Yeah.
c02661
Wellby: Yes. [laughs]
c02662
DM: [laughs]
c02663
Unknown: Okay.
c02664
Unknown: Oh my God.
c02665
Wellby: You should be asking am I okay changing back to a halfling again.
c02666
Wellby: [laughs]
c02667
DM: I mean, um-
c02668
Seeker: I mean, I can, I can attest it's an issue.
c02669
DM: A-
c02670
Seeker: The changes are jarring, yeah
c02671
Delwath: ... as we, I believe gre- I mean, can't green dragons shapeshift?
c02672
DM: But you'll never, you, you have to dispel it in order to get your class abilities back.
c02673
Unknown: Yes.
c02674
DM: You could shapeshift into a human, but you'd just be a human.
c02675
DM: You would never be-
c02676
Wellby: Well, I can be, I could shapeshift to a halfling.
c02677
DM: You can be a halfling.
c02678
Unknown: Yes.
c02679
DM: Yes.
c02680
Delwath: Okay. Anyway, if you're okay being a dragon, right, we could just dispel it when you're back.
c02681
Delwath: It's fine. No big deal.
c02682
Wellby: You don't say that in a way that gives me a great deal of confidence.
c02683
Wellby: [laughs]
c02684
DM: [laughs]
c02685
Delwath: No, you just... Look, it's fine.
c02686
Unknown: It'll work.
c02687
Delwath: No, no, it'll definitely work.
c02688
Wellby: Huh. Look, it's fine. Okay.
c02689
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Let's do it.
c02690
Kenzo: All right, let's do it.
c02691
Wellby: Let's do it.
c02692
DM: Okay. So Wellby turns into a dragon.
c02693
Unknown: Yes.
c02694
DM: Kenzo mounts on the back of the dragon.
c02695
Kenzo: Yes. All Merfolk are coming through.
c02696
Unknown: And you begin flying into the ash.
c02697
Unknown: [laughs] Yes.
c02698
Unknown: Astral-
c02699
Wellby: Kenzo, I've, I've had this dream so many times, Kenzo.
c02700
Wellby: [laughs]
c02701
Unknown: [laughs] Faster.
c02702
DM: K- both of you immune to poison.
c02703
Kenzo: Well, I'm an astral, I'm an astral monk on you.
c02704
DM: Well, that only lasts an hour.
c02705
Unknown: Okay.
c02706
DM: The astral form.
c02707
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c02708
DM: Right? As, and it's gonna take you an hour and a half to get to the edge of the city.
c02709
Kenzo: All right. I'll, I'll wait till we get closer to-
c02710
DM: So wait till you're a little closer
c02711
Unknown: ... yeah.
c02712
DM: Um, the sun is also setting, so you can see the, the like
c02713
DM: lines of the sunset stretching across, um, the ash cloud from the outside, which is now...
c02714
DM: I mean, you guys, you two s- um, Delwath and Seeker are, like, you have the, you have to retreat a bit 'cause the ash is growing stronger, so.
c02715
Unknown: Right.
c02716
Wellby: Mm.
c02717
DM: Um,
c02718
DM: you fly 13 miles, an hour and a half into the storm until you get to the, like
c02719
DM: r- roughly the edge of the city.
c02720
DM: There's no, there's no real marker.
c02721
DM: And now this is where the storm is super intense.
c02722
DM: Neither of you, I forgot that you're immune to poison, so neither of you have to make con saves because you're both immune to poison.
c02723
DM: Um,
c02724
DM: and the,
c02725
DM: uh, so as you, so as you get, like, there's no obvious marker that this is the edge of the city or anything.
c02726
DM: Um-
c02727
Wellby: But I... No, like I can read the terrain.
c02728
DM: Okay. Yeah.
c02729
Wellby: Like the sweep of the-
c02730
DM: Well, right. I mean, your visibility is only-
c02731
Kenzo: Kenzo knows where the, Kenzo knows where the consciousness even is
c02732
DM: ... any, only 30 feet. Kenzo has a sense, has a memory at least of where the consciousness is, and so you begin flying
c02733
DM: around. Like, what are you looking for specifically?
c02734
Kenzo: Uh, we're, we're, we're trying to find the edge of the, uh, uh, the river bank, like that area.
c02735
Kenzo: We, we want to chop off a little bit of ooze, so we want to go, kind of go to the edge where the con- the, the edge of the, um,
c02736
Unknown: the, the eye.
c02737
DM: Sewer outlet?
c02738
Kenzo: The eye.
c02739
DM: Oh, you want to go all the way to the eye?
c02740
Kenzo: Well, just where, wherever the ooze is, the edge of the ooze.
c02741
DM: Well, there's lots of places you could find, potentially find the ooze.
c02742
Unknown: Okay.
c02743
DM: 'Cause it stretch, remember it stretches all underneath the city.
c02744
Unknown: Yeah.
c02745
DM: So that's why I know... I mean, the,
c02746
DM: the plaza in the middle is the easiest place, but I just want to know what you want to look for specifically.
c02747
Unknown: I mean, I think, I-
c02748
DM: Like, are you looking for a different well?
c02749
DM: Are you looking for a sewer outlet into the river?
c02750
DM: Are you just going to the plaza?
c02751
Kenzo: I, I think, I think as we're flying, we're headed...
c02752
Kenzo: Well, let's head towards the plaza.
c02753
DM: Okay.
c02754
Kenzo: But as we're going, if there's any other, like, little thing where it looks like there's a bit of ooze that's coming out-
c02755
Unknown: Yeah
c02756
Kenzo: ... then we, we can stop there. We're, our, this is mission collect ooze.
c02757
DM: Okay.
c02758
Kenzo: That's, that, that's our mission right here.
c02759
Unknown: Yeah.
c02760
DM: So-
c02761
Unknown: Look for wells
c02762
DM: ... make a, make a perception check with disadvantage because you're, it's heavily s- it's obscured.
c02763
Wellby: Uh, do I have advantage from the bow-
c02764
Delwath: You have blind sense though.
c02765
Wellby: That cancels the disadvantage?
c02766
DM: No, 'cause you can't use equipment in dragon form.
c02767
Delwath: Ah, but, but you have... Does blind sense help?
c02768
Delwath: Blind sense can see through obscured things.
c02769
DM: Oh, does the dragon have blind sense?
c02770
Delwath: Dragon has 60 foot blind sense and 120 foot-
c02771
DM: Okay, so-
c02772
Wellby: It's still above 25
c02773
DM: ... straight roll. Yeah.
c02774
DM: Um,
c02775
DM: right, I guess, well,
c02776
DM: yeah, yeah. Well, right.
c02777
DM: You get your dragon's bonus, not the...
c02778
DM: You don't have reliable talent or your-
c02779
Wellby: Yes.
c02780
DM: Oh, that would be-
c02781
Wellby: Do I add my proficiency bonus?
c02782
DM: Nope.
c02783
Delwath: Uh, you add the dragon's, which is the same as yours.
c02784
Wellby: Does someone have that h-
c02785
Delwath: Yeah, I got it. I got it. Perception plus 12.
c02786
Wellby: Uh, that's a 23 was the worst of the two rolls.
c02787
DM: Okay. So as you're, as you're approaching,
c02788
DM: um, you do see, like, you sense with your blind sense because you can sort of, um, sense the layout of the ground below you as you're, you're approaching.
c02789
DM: There's not, there's not a well that you pass, but you see like a, there's like a collapsed well basically that once was a well but that's fallen in-
c02790
Unknown: Mm
c02791
DM: ... and there's a ring of rubble around the outside.
c02792
DM: So theoretically you could
c02793
DM: try there or you could just keep going.
c02794
Wellby: What do you think?
c02795
Unknown: Just try there.
c02796
Wellby: Let's do it.
c02797
Unknown: Yeah.
c02798
DM: Okay.
c02799
DM: So you land.
c02800
Wellby: Yes.
c02801
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo senses where the ooze, touch this.
c02802
DM: It's, it's right below you.
c02803
Unknown: Okay.
c02804
DM: Doesn't seem to have sensed you yet
c02805
Kenzo: There, there is a well here
c02806
DM: W- uh, yeah
c02807
Unknown: Seems like a-
c02808
DM: It's like partially full of rubble
c02809
Wellby: Is it that we're gonna like sneak in and chop off a piece of the ooze and-
c02810
Unknown: Yeah
c02811
Wellby: ... bring it back.
c02812
Kenzo: Yeah. Basically, yeah.
c02813
Kenzo: Uh, okay. Well, if it's, there's rubble, that's fine.
c02814
Kenzo: K- uh, Kenzo passes through it.
c02815
DM: Okay. So Kenzo begins dropping down through the, through the rubble in the well.
c02816
Wellby: If I shape shift, do I retain my poison immunity or do I take on the, um-
c02817
Unknown: Oh, good question
c02818
Wellby: ...
c02819
Wellby: whatever I shift into?
c02820
Unknown: Uh-
c02821
DM: Uh, dragon-
c02822
Unknown: Can you-
c02823
DM: Wait, adult green dragon doesn't have shape shift
c02824
Delwath: Yeah, except we fought a green dragon and he had shape shift, which is...
c02825
Delwath: I never, I didn't actually look at the stats.
c02826
DM: Oh.
c02827
Delwath: I just assumed the dragon could shape shift.
c02828
DM: Yeah, yeah. No, no, no, because the o- the,
c02829
DM: the, the old green... Yeah, yeah, fine.
c02830
DM: Dragon can shape shift.
c02831
Delwath: I, I only assumed it could shape shift because we fought a shape shifting green dragon.
c02832
DM: The...
c02833
Unknown: So m- I mean, maybe we can't.
c02834
Delwath: I just, I just was operating on the
c02835
Delwath: in world rather than stat block.
c02836
DM: Right, but not every dream dragon has the same abilities.
c02837
Unknown: Yeah, no, that's-
c02838
DM: No, that's fair
c02839
Delwath: ... yeah, it's fair.
c02840
DM: Yeah.
c02841
Delwath: Totally fair.
c02842
DM: Yep.
c02843
Delwath: I, I just... That's why I said it could shape shift.
c02844
Unknown: I, I-
c02845
Wellby: Yeah, I think there's something exciting to Kenzo going alone.
c02846
Unknown: [laughs]
c02847
DM: Kenzo-
c02848
Unknown: [laughs]
c02849
DM: Kenzo drops down through the,
c02850
DM: um, through the-
c02851
Unknown: [laughs]
c02852
DM: ... through the rubble, and you s- you come to what looks like,
c02853
DM: um, a
c02854
DM: p- a,
c02855
DM: a partially collapsed
c02856
DM: cistern, right? Like, it seems like there was, um...
c02857
DM: What is that? There's that place in
c02858
DM: Istanbul I wanna see, that say there's that-
c02859
Unknown: Oh, look.
c02860
Seeker: It's the, um, Medusa heads. It's up, there's like an upside down Medusa head inside the Basilica Cistern.
c02861
Unknown: It's called the-
c02862
DM: Yeah, yeah. The Basilica Cistern
c02863
Seeker: ... crazy fucking place.
c02864
DM: That's what I'm,
c02865
DM: that's what I'm, uh...
c02866
DM: So I don't know if you guys know this.
c02867
Wellby: I don't know it. Describe it.
c02868
DM: So the Basilica Cistern-
c02869
Seeker: I've been, yeah
c02870
DM: ... is a massive cistern, um,
c02871
DM: that was built in
c02872
DM: Constantinople-
c02873
Unknown: A thousand years ago
c02874
DM: ... in the, in the third to fourth century, and was like a huge...
c02875
DM: It's like a giant underwater, underground cistern-
c02876
Unknown: It is
c02877
DM: ... that's like has all sorts of rows of, um, like columns and pillars and, um, it l- it looks super cool from the pictures.
c02878
DM: Um, and that's basically what is beneath Isengai,
c02879
DM: or at least this part of Isengai.
c02880
DM: It's this massive underground
c02881
DM: cistern with wells that go to, that drop down into it from different parts of the city,
c02882
DM: and f- clearly fed by the river.
c02883
Unknown: Mm.
c02884
DM: Um,
c02885
DM: and you see that...
c02886
DM: But it's, but it, like a lot of it has collapsed.
c02887
DM: So while once in the heyday of Isengai it would've been this massive open space, now like there's just c- collapsed ceilings and limes.
c02888
DM: So it's not actually a sewer system that the ooze lives in.
c02889
DM: It's the, the network that's created by the piles of rubble that now block large parts of the cistern-
c02890
Unknown: Ooh, wow
c02891
DM: ... creating a maze.
c02892
DM: But you see below you, um, two small, two like tendrils of greenish purple, um,
c02893
DM: ooze like substance
c02894
DM: that turn and see you, and leap to attack.
c02895
Unknown: Nice.
c02896
Wellby: How's it going down there, Kenzo?
c02897
Kenzo: Uh, so far so good. Initiative?
c02898
DM: Yep.
c02899
Unknown: 24.
c02900
DM: Yeah, you beat them.
c02901
Seeker: Um, Kenzo will, uh...
c02902
Kenzo: Yeah, Kenzo will, 'cause this is, this is m- mission capture ooze, so, um,
c02903
Kenzo: he's gonna try to, um,
c02904
Kenzo: like literally just go and, I don't know if it's grappling or what it would be, but like he literally wants to go and just with magic hands like tear some of these off.
c02905
DM: So,
c02906
DM: so grapple, I mean, if you stun one you could just like grab it.
c02907
Unknown: Okay.
c02908
DM: Um, you could try grappling and then use a, like an object interaction to try and rip a piece off.
c02909
DM: Um-
c02910
Delwath: Soul sight it first?
c02911
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Soul sight. Thank you.
c02912
Kenzo: Soul sight first then.
c02913
DM: Um-
c02914
Unknown: Soul sight first.
c02915
DM: [laughs] Okay. So-
c02916
Unknown: [laughs] Is it friendly?
c02917
DM: No, it's not friendly. Um, the-
c02918
Unknown: Okay
c02919
DM: ... the ooze is...
c02920
DM: Um, I don't know how to-
c02921
Seeker: I can take a look at some pictures there, but
c02922
DM: ... we're trying to figure out the best way to actually-
c02923
Seeker: This is, this is my picture of the upside down Medusa head.
c02924
Kenzo: What?
c02925
Seeker: And there is this, like interior cistern.
c02926
Unknown: Oh, I can imagine.
c02927
Seeker: Yeah. It's just a crazy place.
c02928
Unknown: Those things are so cool.
c02929
Seeker: It's all dark. There's just like an exten- expansive puddle, so like a football field-
c02930
Seeker: And there's just ancient columns in rows- Wow ...
c02931
DM: Yeah
c02932
Seeker: going on forever. [laughs] I feel like- It's crazy [laughs] ...
c02933
Wellby: ... ancient civil engineering is amazing.
c02934
Unknown: Yeah.
c02935
DM: So,
c02936
DM: um,
c02937
DM: the...
c02938
DM: So here, here's how soul sight's gonna work, because each part of the ooze is also, has different stat blocks.
c02939
Unknown: Oh, my gosh.
c02940
DM: So you're gonna get-
c02941
Unknown: Okay
c02942
DM: ... a little bit of information about this part of ooze and a little bit of information about the whole, the basic ooze.
c02943
DM: Um, so you, so this, this, uh,
c02944
DM: um,
c02945
DM: purple pseudopod
c02946
DM: is CR 9.
c02947
Unknown: Oh.
c02948
DM: Resistant to acid,
c02949
DM: immune to blinded, charmed, deafened, exhausted, pranked, and prone, prone.
c02950
DM: Um,
c02951
DM: bad at charisma, good at strength.
c02952
Unknown: Well.
c02953
DM: Um, this is a small piece of the actual ooze itself, and you get just like one piece of information about the full ooze from soul sighting
c02954
DM: a segment. So what do you want to know about the full ooze?
c02955
DM: One of the things. Resistances, immunities, strongest save, weakest save, or CR.
c02956
Unknown: Right.
c02957
DM: You can pick one.
c02958
Unknown: Immunities.
c02959
Seeker: Weakest save.
c02960
DM: Well, pick one.
c02961
Unknown: Hmm.
c02962
Unknown: Life story.
c02963
Kenzo: Well, we're gonna get that once we, uh, show it to Mir.
c02964
Wellby: Closest friends.
c02965
Wellby: Deepest fear.
c02966
Wellby: [laughs]
c02967
Unknown: Favorite movies.
c02968
Wellby: [laughs]
c02969
Unknown: [laughs] Um, yeah, I'll go with, I'll go with immunities.
c02970
Wellby: Favorite date.
c02971
DM: Acid, necrotic, poison damage.
c02972
DM: Charmed, exhausted, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, stunned, and unconscious.
c02973
Kenzo: That sounds like one of those, like, uh, it's like a Joseph's multicolored coat or something.
c02974
Unknown: Yeah.
c02975
Wellby: Th- those are all of its immunities?
c02976
DM: Yeah.
c02977
Seeker: Read them again. Are there things that it's not immune to, jeez.
c02978
Wellby: Uh, would that be quicker? [laughs]
c02979
DM: ... yeah, actually, I don't think there's any conditions it's not immune to.
c02980
Wellby: Oh, it's immune to all the conditions.
c02981
DM: Uh, incapac- It's not immune to incapacitated.
c02982
Kenzo: It can't be blind, it can't be tripped.
c02983
DM: It's immune to prone.
c02984
Wellby: It's too big to be tripped
c02985
DM: It's immune to charmed, exhaustion, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, stunned, unconscious.
c02986
Delwath: So yeah, it's basically immune to all conditions.
c02987
Unknown: Wow.
c02988
DM: And-
c02989
Delwath: What kind of damage? Acid
c02990
DM: ... acid, necrotic, and poison damage.
c02991
Kenzo: Okay, cool. I, uh, I, uh, attack it and take a bit of it.
c02992
DM: Okay, make an attack roll.
c02993
Seeker: Just wanna, like, smack a piece of it off with their staff.
c02994
Kenzo: Uh, I've got magic hands. Let's try to, like, break a, break a piece off.
c02995
Seeker: Just scoop out a chunk.
c02996
Unknown: Plus 13.
c02997
Kenzo: Oh, actually maybe I'll, maybe I'll hit it with my staff first.
c02998
Unknown: I'll try to break a-
c02999
DM: Okay
c03000
Kenzo: ... piece off with my staff. It's a plus 15.
c03001
Unknown: Uh, 27.
c03002
DM: Yeah, that hits.
c03003
Kenzo: Now what do I do? Can I... How can I, like-
c03004
DM: So, well, if you wanna, if you wanna actually break a piece off, you have to first grapple it and then rip it in, rip the piece in half.
c03005
DM: I was just suggesting earlier, if you stun it, it will automatically fail.
c03006
Unknown: You'll automatically be able to grapple it.
c03007
Kenzo: All right. So then I, then I, uh, I, I stun it.
c03008
Kenzo: I try to stun it
c03009
DM: Okay. So it needs to make a DC 20 con save.
c03010
DM: That is a 16
c03011
Unknown: It fails
c03012
DM: So it is stunned
c03013
Kenzo: Great. And now I can...
c03014
DM: I mean, you can flurry your blows, so s- grappling is an unarmed attack.
c03015
Unknown: Yeah.
c03016
DM: So just make an unarmed attack.
c03017
DM: You have advantage on the attack roll.
c03018
Unknown: Oh, shit.
c03019
Unknown: Uh...
c03020
Unknown: Uh, oh.
c03021
Delwath: Don't you have a plus 14 now?
c03022
Unknown: Uh, 19?
c03023
DM: 19 hits.
c03024
Unknown: Okay.
c03025
DM: So you grapple it, and then just as a, because it's stunned, as a free object interaction, you can rip a piece off.
c03026
Kenzo: Perfect. Great, and now I will, uh, disengage and run.
c03027
Unknown: But you don't have any actions.
c03028
Unknown: No.
c03029
DM: You used your bonus action. You can just run, but it's stunned, so it can't do anything to you.
c03030
Kenzo: Okay, perfect. I get out of there.
c03031
DM: Okay. Well done
c03032
Unknown: Nice
c03033
DM: Good job
c03034
Delwath: See, you didn't really need to break it
c03035
Unknown: off
c03036
DM: So you run
c03037
Kenzo: We didn't all have to go
c03038
DM: There's this-
c03039
Unknown: [laughs] Right
c03040
DM: ... this. So as you pull the piece of ooze off, it hardens into crystal
c03041
Wellby: Ooh.
c03042
Unknown: Crystal.
c03043
Unknown: That's cool.
c03044
Unknown: Okay, great.
c03045
DM: And then you flee back up the tunnel, or the collapsed well, away from the-
c03046
Unknown: Yes
c03047
DM: ... ruined cistern.
c03048
Kenzo: And then I hop back on Wellby's back, and then we fly back to the, where everybody else is.
c03049
DM: Yeah.
c03050
Wellby: Yeah.
c03051
Kenzo: And then the dispel does not work, and Wellby stays a green dragon forever.
c03052
Wellby: [laughs]
c03053
Unknown: The end
c03054
Unknown: [laughs]
c03055
Unknown: Well, I mean-
c03056
Wellby: Has it been an hour?
c03057
DM: Oh, it's been more than an hour.
c03058
Unknown: How's it feel, Wellby? It's been-
c03059
Wellby: I've got some real life choices right now
c03060
Kenzo: Well, Wellby, what, are, what, like, what's, uh, what do you think now that you've had the experience?
c03061
Wellby: Uh, I mean, the flying part feels pretty normal.
c03062
Wellby: It's the, uh... it's just the size.
c03063
Wellby: Like, I, I should be able to fit through things and I can't.
c03064
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Pretty different, right?
c03065
Wellby: Like, I can touch both sides of the deck at the same time.
c03066
Wellby: I'm confused by that.
c03067
Unknown: I, I know what you're talking about.
c03068
Unknown: Look at this. Look at this.
c03069
Wellby: Pretty great.
c03070
Unknown: I just-
c03071
Wellby: I'm touching both
c03072
Seeker: ... I just had that yesterday and it was so weird.
c03073
Kenzo: Pretty great. Yeah. I mean...
c03074
Unknown: [sighs] If only we all could feel that.
c03075
Unknown: Ow, it feels like a new dragon.
c03076
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
c03077
Unknown: Totally.
c03078
Unknown: Yeah.
c03079
Seeker: Well, I guess there's no way.
c03080
Wellby: It's been a good run, though. I feel ready to go back to being-
c03081
Unknown: Halfling
c03082
Wellby: ... a halfling again.
c03083
Unknown: All right.
c03084
Kenzo: Can you cast a spell magic, or was that it?
c03085
Seeker: Well, I can still-
c03086
Unknown: I mean-
c03087
DM: Anybody can
c03088
Wellby: ... have some real, like, like, dysphoria.
c03089
Unknown: Hmm.
c03090
Unknown: Right?
c03091
Wellby: Yeah.
c03092
DM: Um-
c03093
Seeker: Wing dysphoria
c03094
Delwath: ... dis- to dispel an nth level spell though, you have to roll a 14 or higher.
c03095
Delwath: Just assuming, assuming you have a plus 5.
c03096
DM: Yeah, you have, you'd have to roll a 14 or higher with dispel magic.
c03097
Seeker: And there's just this one
c03098
Unknown: chance every-
c03099
Unknown: No.
c03100
DM: Oh, no, you add half your...
c03101
DM: Oh, no, yeah, 14 or higher
c03102
DM: Right.
c03103
Delwath: I mean, I could auto succeed by casting glyph it
c03104
DM: You can just... I mean, it's a third level slot.
c03105
DM: You can just try a few times, and if it doesn't work you can use a fourth level slot and then a fifth level s-
c03106
Unknown: Oh.
c03107
DM: I mean, you're planning on resting, right?
c03108
Unknown: Yeah.
c03109
DM: So.
c03110
Delwath: Yeah. But if we're planning on resting, I should just do glob this.
c03111
DM: Do glob this. Yeah.
c03112
Delwath: I'll just, I'll just...
c03113
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c03114
Delwath: Delwath will just dispel it. Well-
c03115
DM: Okay
c03116
Delwath: ... I'll try... Nah, I'll just do that.
c03117
Wellby: You auto, you auto succeed.
c03118
Unknown: I'll just do that.
c03119
DM: Yeah.
c03120
Delwath: Okay. I'll auto succeed.
c03121
Unknown: We show the, uh, uh-
c03122
Wellby: Ooh
c03123
Unknown: ... ooze to Beryl.
c03124
DM: Okay.
c03125
Wellby: Yeah.
c03126
Unknown: Amazing.
c03127
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
c03128
Seeker: Now what's our question?
c03129
DM: What's your question?
c03130
Delwath: Um, wait, wait. First, is it a creature of Limbo?
c03131
Delwath: My sword can detect creatures of Limbo.
c03132
DM: Oh, yeah. Uh...
c03133
Unknown: Sword
c03134
DM: N- no
c03135
Unknown: No
c03136
DM: Well, hmm.
c03137
DM: No, it is not a creature.
c03138
Unknown: But-
c03139
DM: It is not a native, it is not native to Limbo.
c03140
Unknown: That-
c03141
Seeker: That it turned into crystal is very interesting, because that's the antithesis of Limbo.
c03142
Seeker: Crystal is the kind of epitome of order, isn't it?
c03143
DM: True.
c03144
Seeker: So maybe it's a corrupted creature from...
c03145
Seeker: What's the plane of order called?
c03146
Unknown: Machinus?
c03147
Unknown: Machanis.
c03148
c03149
Seeker: Maybe it's a sort of, like, imprisoned victim of the war against Machanis thousands of years ago.
c03150
DM: Hmm
c03151
Unknown: That has been limbo-fied.
c03152
Seeker: Anyway, why would it turn into crystal?
c03153
Unknown: It's odd.
c03154
Wellby: That is odd.
c03155
Delwath: It is odd.
c03156
Seeker: Or maybe that's just a collapsed state of limbo entities where
c03157
Wellby: [coughs]
c03158
Seeker: ... organized life from the material plane
c03159
Seeker: turns into Ooze when it dies,
c03160
Seeker: and Ooze when it dies turns into something perfectly organized.
c03161
Unknown: That's the reverse-
c03162
Wellby: There's something to that
c03163
Seeker: ... right, reverse entropy state from its living state.
c03164
Kenzo: Tim, uh, once I pull the piece of Ooze off, is the piece of Ooze I have now kind of inoperculous?
c03165
DM: In your hand? No.
c03166
Kenzo: It's, it's like dead
c03167
DM: Dead, yeah.
c03168
Wellby: Look.
c03169
Seeker: Is it a black opaque crystal or...?
c03170
DM: It's more like sort of purple gray.
c03171
DM: Like purpley with grayer swirly streaks.
c03172
Unknown: Amethyst-y
c03173
DM: Sort of amethyst-y, but dull.
c03174
DM: It doesn't have that, it doesn't...
c03175
DM: It's not like-
c03176
Unknown: It's not magical?
c03177
DM: Well, not only that it's not magical, it's that it, it feels a little, it looks a little desaturated.
c03178
Unknown: Yeah.
c03179
DM: Like it's not, it's not the sort of vibrant sort of bright gemstone.
c03180
DM: It's a
c03181
DM: grayish purple sort of desaturated hue.
c03182
Seeker: Is there any arcane meaning to
c03183
Seeker: grayish purple desaturated crystal?
c03184
DM: N- no.
c03185
Kenzo: All right. Let's show it to the mirror.
c03186
Wellby: Yep.
c03187
DM: Okay.
c03188
Kenzo: And we ask it, um,
c03189
Kenzo: we ask it what it, what's its story?
c03190
Seeker: How to defeat it?
c03191
Kenzo: What are your, what's its weaknesses?
c03192
Wellby: How, like how did it come to being and grow?
c03193
Wellby: Like...
c03194
Delwath: I mean, the story of its growth?
c03195
Kenzo: Well, we kind of wanna know two things. I mean, we wanna know its story just for fun and just for plot, but we also really wanna know how to kill it.
c03196
Wellby: Well, but I'm thinking that too, like maybe knowing how it came into being offers some-
c03197
Unknown: Yeah
c03198
Wellby: ... clues as to-
c03199
Delwath: I think its origins will offer clues
c03200
Wellby: ... undoing.
c03201
Delwath: 'Cause the mirror doesn't tell us, like...
c03202
Unknown: Yeah.
c03203
Unknown: Strategies.
c03204
DM: Strategies.
c03205
Unknown: Right. Yeah.
c03206
Seeker: Okay. All right. I, I think the story of, uh, its life.
c03207
Kenzo: Tell us how you came to be. Tell, tell us how you came to be.
c03208
Unknown: Yeah.
c03209
DM: Make a wisdom check.
c03210
Unknown: Yes.
c03211
DM: Plus six.
c03212
Seeker: And the most exciting-
c03213
Wellby: Wait, what's this?
c03214
Unknown: ...
c03215
Unknown: attack on the sky ship that he's ever heard.
c03216
Wellby: Is it a plus a billion?
c03217
Wellby: [laughs]
c03218
DM: No, it's just a straight wisdom check, just wisdom plus your wisdom mod, so plus six.
c03219
DM: 19.
c03220
Unknown: 19.
c03221
DM: Okay, that's good. Um, so you hold it up to the mirror.
c03222
Wellby: Yo.
c03223
DM: And you watch as the
c03224
DM: image in the mirror turns briefly black, and then
c03225
DM: you see
c03226
DM: below you,
c03227
DM: uh, sort of looking up just one sort of, uh, circle of light above, the sun shining down into a, uh, dark-
c03228
Unknown: Which sun?
c03229
c03230
DM: The, the material plane sun.
c03231
Unknown: Okay.
c03232
DM: Shining down into a, um,
c03233
DM: y- you can see like ripples in the water, right?
c03234
DM: So you're... It's like looking down into this cistern below Isingue, uh, but when it is less ruined.
c03235
DM: And then there's a
c03236
DM: viol- like the, everything starts shaking like an earthquake and, but instead of things falling down, there's like
c03237
DM: things that jut out that are shooting out from the ground, like pieces of stone.
c03238
DM: Water is like solidifying and shooting up as a spike of solid water.
c03239
DM: The s- some of the stones are beginning to like decay at the bottom and melt and like flow out across, like liquid stone across the surface.
c03240
Kenzo: Sounds pretty, sounds, sounds pretty limbo.
c03241
Wellby: This is the ruination.
c03242
Seeker: Yeah, this is good.
c03243
Unknown: Yeah.
c03244
DM: And then, um, there's a,
c03245
DM: uh...
c03246
DM: the wa- the water itself in the...
c03247
DM: Oh, that's a detail I forgot to mention.
c03248
DM: So there's, there was essentially, you saw essentially no water in the cistern.
c03249
Wellby: Mm. Mm. Mm.
c03250
DM: You didn't actually see any water down below.
c03251
Wellby: Mm. Mm. Mm. Oh, shit.
c03252
DM: The wa- you see, you see like a,
c03253
DM: a dark,
c03254
DM: uh, swirling mass of s- like liquid stone and,
c03255
DM: uh,
c03256
c03257
DM: I don't know how to describe it. Like threads.
c03258
DM: Like, like if you took, if you took a, if you took like a bunch of gummy bears and, or sorry, gummy worms and microwaved them slightly so they're all like-
c03259
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
c03260
DM: ... stuck together into a-
c03261
Wellby: Gelatinous mass
c03262
DM: ... gelatinous mass.
c03263
DM: Be- nucleates in the center of the water underneath the cistern.
c03264
DM: [phone ringing]
c03265
Kenzo: This is so crazy. I haven't heard a phone ring in like
c03266
Unknown: 20 years.
c03267
DM: Um.
c03268
Unknown: You guys sh-
c03269
DM: No.
c03270
Unknown: I don't think we can answer that.
c03271
DM: It's always spam.
c03272
Kenzo: Oh, okay. Okay. [laughs] Yeah.
c03273
Delwath: If it was like somebody who needs to reach David Kong or something.
c03274
DM: Right. Um, and then this gelatinous mass, uh,
c03275
DM: hardens into solid stone.
c03276
DM: Yeah, it's all spam. And then, and then like, um,
c03277
DM: it... The, like, nearest bit of the water begins to, like, solidify into jelly, and you watch over time as more and more bits of the water underneath
c03278
DM: Isengay, like little filaments will form, stretching out across the water and, like, solidify and crystallize and nucleate along that filament, emerging from this,
c03279
DM: this mass at the center which then begins to spin and actually splits into two that are connected by some wire, like orb- orbiting
c03280
DM: around each other with like, as they spin s- throwing off more and more little filaments that land further in the water, and then a line of like gelatinous mass
c03281
DM: like nucleates along the line.
c03282
Unknown: Oh, boy. So wait, this is two...
c03283
DM: There's two of these like solid masses of microwaved gummy worms-
c03284
Unknown: Right
c03285
DM: ... that have solidified and turned into some kind of weird s-
c03286
Delwath: What is that muttering about?
c03287
Wellby: I don't know.
c03288
DM: Um.
c03289
Unknown: Still talking.
c03290
DM: The, um... They're spinning around each other, and as they spin, they're throwing off more little bits that nucleate into another...
c03291
Kenzo: So yeah, so th- this is totally gonna, like, like...
c03292
Kenzo: Th- this is literally, um, the fucking...
c03293
Kenzo: It's the great, it's the great use.
c03294
Kenzo: The, the, the, uh, nanotechnology dude-
c03295
Unknown: Oh, yeah
c03296
Unknown: ... the thing.
c03297
DM: Oh, yeah
c03298
Unknown: The great use.
c03299
DM: Yeah.
c03300
Unknown: This is literally the-
c03301
Delwath: But we only detected one...
c03302
DM: Well,
c03303
DM: I mean-
c03304
Delwath: It could have c- collapsed together, yeah
c03305
DM: ... yeah, or like there's two, there's two nodules orbiting around each other but they're one-
c03306
Unknown: Spot, spot, right
c03307
DM: ... spot, right. Like-
c03308
Kenzo: But the, but the thing that it's, it's, it's, it's, it's water that's like causing it to...
c03309
Kenzo: It's like infecting water and then-
c03310
DM: Yeah, it's infecting all of the water underneath Isengai.
c03311
Unknown: Yeah
c03312
DM: And then all of that is like solidifying and drawing in, and you watch...
c03313
DM: Like time is sped up in the mirror, right?
c03314
DM: So you watch over time-
c03315
Unknown: Mm-hmm
c03316
DM: ... as more and more of these...
c03317
DM: And then the first like maybe years later there's the first like little...
c03318
DM: It's slow. It's a slow process.
c03319
DM: The, you know... Uh, the first little tendril creeps up out of a-
c03320
Unknown: Yeah
c03321
DM: ... out of a well and like begins to feel around.
c03322
Unknown: Yeah.
c03323
DM: Right? And at this point that you can see in the mirror, right?
c03324
DM: Isengai is much more intact, but over time it begins to corrode and destroy all of the...
c03325
DM: It seems to actually eat the stone somehow.
c03326
DM: It's like acidically corroding all of the stone in the city as it slowly grows over years.
c03327
DM: I mean, it's been growing for a quite a long time.
c03328
Unknown: Okay. All right.
c03329
DM: And that's what you see.
c03330
Unknown: So-
c03331
Wellby: What does that suggest for how to destroy it?
c03332
Delwath: Find that little nodule thing, right?
c03333
Wellby: Right.
c03334
Delwath: I mean, it's the plan Kenzo suggested at the very beginning.
c03335
Delwath: Find its center and then-
c03336
Wellby: Starting point.
c03337
Unknown: I mean...
c03338
Delwath: Like we know where it is, we just have to fight our way...
c03339
Delwath: I mean, the naive thing is we fight our way to the nodule and then we
c03340
Delwath: do something clever.
c03341
Unknown: Well, what would be cool is if there was a way to like...
c03342
Kenzo: If there was like an antidote.
c03343
Kenzo: Like what's the anti-limbo antidote to like kind of decontaminate it, like the bioremediation strategy.
c03344
Unknown: Right.
c03345
Unknown: But like-
c03346
Delwath: To like, like cause it to shrink and draw back and-
c03347
Unknown: Yeah
c03348
Delwath: ... retreat out of the city somehow.
c03349
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. Exactly.
c03350
Kenzo: That would be cool.
c03351
Kenzo: The dumber thing feels like we just like go and drop a nuke.
c03352
Delwath: But like do we try and,
c03353
Delwath: do we try and like
c03354
Delwath: make it withdraw into itself and get smaller, and smaller, and smaller, or do we just go kill the brain?
c03355
Kenzo: Uh, yeah, 'cause it's like how do we get down to the bottom of the...
c03356
Kenzo: Where the, the third, the, the third one thing.
c03357
Kenzo: That, that... The, it's the one at the, the very bottom that's like the, you know-
c03358
Unknown: Right
c03359
Kenzo: ... probably the main one.
c03360
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c03361
DM: I mean...
c03362
Wellby: It grew up in the sewer?
c03363
DM: Well, the cistern.
c03364
Unknown: The cistern.
c03365
Wellby: The cistern. Maybe it doesn't like light.
c03366
Unknown: Oh.
c03367
Wellby: Like maybe it wants to be in the dark.
c03368
Delwath: I think it, I think it likes the water.
c03369
Delwath: It's more water. Yeah.
c03370
Delwath: I think it's more that it spread...
c03371
Delwath: This may be slightly cheating, but I...
c03372
Delwath: The water of, of
c03373
Delwath: Isingue, I think it spread along.
c03374
DM: Yeah, no, you knew that from the Heartroot.
c03375
Delwath: Right. Okay, wait. We knew the water was magical.
c03376
Wellby: Yeah. So can like we starve it of its water somehow?
c03377
Seeker: Or, or desiccate it in that idea?
c03378
Wellby: Yeah.
c03379
Seeker: Like maybe with heat we can dry it out.
c03380
Delwath: I think it's...
c03381
Delwath: Doesn't it... Isn't the water all gone now?
c03382
DM: The water's all gone, but there's clear...
c03383
DM: There was a... Kenza sensed a concentration in the river.
c03384
DM: The river is not dry.
c03385
Delwath: Oh, maybe we go kill the river one.
c03386
Seeker: And then it, and then it will no longer have a source of water.
c03387
Delwath: It disconnects it from the magic.
c03388
Delwath: Maybe that's how we bioremediate it, right?
c03389
Delwath: In other words, if it's-
c03390
Kenzo: Mm, yeah. All right, let's do that
c03391
Delwath: ... if it's growing from the...
c03392
Delwath: And the nice thing about the water one-
c03393
Unknown: Outside
c03394
Delwath: ... outside, and also like, I mean, I don't want to copy Seeker, but two leviathans?
c03395
Unknown: [laughs]
c03396
DM: [laughs]
c03397
Seeker: Two leviathans.
c03398
Delwath: Water creatures?
c03399
Seeker: Good movement speed in the, in the river.
c03400
Seeker: Interesting point you're making.
c03401
Kenzo: Let's do it. Let's go kill the river one.
c03402
Delwath: Like there's a certain appeal in like let's...
c03403
Delwath: Like we could like go after it in the river and then-
c03404
Kenzo: Let's do it. Long rest and then what are we doing?
c03405
Kenzo: Are you making another Seeker? Are we doing a Hero's Feast?
c03406
Wellby: Yeah. Load up all the things.
c03407
Delwath: Load up all... You can only do one.
c03408
Seeker: Probably Hero's Feast.
c03409
Unknown: Oh.
c03410
Unknown: Oh, no.
c03411
Delwath: Oh, no, 'cause you can't take Hero's Feast as a spell.
c03412
DM: Right.
c03413
Seeker: So what did I end up taking?
c03414
Unknown: I think I-
c03415
Delwath: You took Demiplane
c03416
Unknown: ... Oh.
c03417
Delwath: So you can only Hero's Feast by casting Wish.
c03418
Unknown: So...
c03419
Delwath: You can still cast Hero's Feast as Wish.
c03420
Unknown: [mumbles]
c03421
Unknown: Okay. Yeah
c03422
Delwath: Didn't you take Demiplane?
c03423
Unknown: Um...
c03424
Unknown: That's what we talked about. We talked about-
c03425
Unknown: Yeah
c03426
Delwath: ... taking Demiplane.
c03427
DM: Yeah.
c03428
Seeker: Yeah, you're right.
c03429
Kenzo: Well, that, that's what we all suggested, but I don't know.
c03430
Kenzo: Eric chose it.
c03431
Seeker: Quickly not happening.
c03432
Unknown: [laughs]
c03433
Delwath: But, I mean, if you had Hero's Feast you could do a Simakrum and Hero's Feast.
c03434
Unknown: But-
c03435
DM: Well, the down- the biggest downside to a Simakrum is it takes 12 hours to cast which means that-
c03436
Delwath: Not unless you cast it with Wish
c03437
DM: ... unless you cast it with Wish.
c03438
Wellby: And then that's the Wish.
c03439
Seeker: Is there some reason to think that would be especially helpful?
c03440
Unknown: Simakrum?
c03441
Unknown: Oh.
c03442
Delwath: No, only like
c03443
Delwath: it's, it's a good... It's your last opportunity for a Seeker 7.
c03444
Delwath: Well, Seeker 7 can come with us and Frank.
c03445
DM: Seeker, Seeker 7 can come with you to the Plane of Fire.
c03446
Unknown: Yeah.
c03447
Delwath: I, I think Hero's Feast.
c03448
DM: It's gonna be tough if you're all constantly poisoned.
c03449
Delwath: It... Hero's Feast is definitely-
c03450
DM: Poison gives you disadvantage on all attacks
c03451
Unknown: ... yeah.
c03452
Seeker: So I, I use Wish to cast Hero's Feast and then you're immune to poison.
c03453
Wellby: Yeah.
c03454
DM: Then you're immune to poison for 24 hours.
c03455
DM: So you cast it right before you go to bed, so then you're impun- immune to poison all the next day.
c03456
Unknown: Right
c03457
Seeker: And I get my Wish slot back
c03458
DM: And you get your Wish slot back, yeah.
c03459
Delwath: Let's do that. Perfect. And I mean, I guess if you didn't want to use Wish, but I don't think Seeker 7 is your best option for...
c03460
Delwath: Like you're probably better are using Wish to turn into a leviathan or something like that, or sorry, using Shape Shift to turn into a leviathan.
c03461
Seeker: That's what I'm gonna do the next day, yeah.
c03462
DM: Yeah
c03463
Delwath: But I mean, I'm, I'm pretty tempted to do the same thing.
c03464
Unknown: Yeah.
c03465
DM: Okay.
c03466
Delwath: If we're going in the river-
c03467
Unknown: Yeah, we're going in the river
c03468
Delwath: ... there, there's something to be said for...
c03469
Delwath: Especially it's not, if there's no creatures of limbo here so I don't get 4d8 damage, I only get 2d8 damage.
c03470
DM: Right.
c03471
Delwath: It makes, uh...
c03472
DM: So
c03473
DM: here Seeker...
c03474
DM: As the sun sets you set up camp.
c03475
DM: Seeker creates a feast for you
c03476
DM: and you
c03477
DM: consume the feast. Roll 2d10, everybody gets 2d10 added to your hit point maximum.
c03478
Unknown: Nice.
c03479
Delwath: Can you stack that with Aid, by the way?
c03480
DM: There's, yeah, no reason not.
c03481
DM: They're different spells.
c03482
Unknown: Okay.
c03483
DM: No, Seeker rolls 2d10-
c03484
Unknown: Oh.
c03485
DM: ... for everybody. Everybody gets the same amount.
c03486
Unknown: Right.
c03487
Unknown: 11.
c03488
Unknown: Solid.
c03489
DM: So everybody adds 11 to their hit point maximum.
c03490
DM: [coughs]
c03491
DM: We're not in Vindrasharna though, right?
c03492
DM: You're not in Vinasharna.
c03493
Delwath: We could be though, right?
c03494
Seeker: Wait, where, where is it?
c03495
Unknown: Where is it?
c03496
Kenzo: Seeker has two teleports Is this temporary hit points or is this like when you create increase the maximum?
c03497
DM: No, it's if you go to the, um,
c03498
DM: the-
c03499
Unknown: Because if we-
c03500
Delwath: Override max, I see it. Got it
c03501
Delwath: ... if we long rest in Vinasharana we can get a billion and a half.
c03502
Seeker: [coughs] It's the max HP modifier, right?
c03503
DM: But that's, if you're planning on polymorphing-
c03504
Unknown: There's probably more stuff over on Max HP
c03505
DM: ... that's mostly useless usually because they go away the minute you polymorph.
c03506
Unknown: Oh, that's true. [coughs]
c03507
Seeker: It must be the max HP modifier.
c03508
DM: Max H- set max HP modifier to 11.
c03509
Unknown: To 11. [keyboard clacking]
c03510
Unknown: Okay.
c03511
Delwath: And then actually set it to everybody-
c03512
Unknown: You get 20 more?
c03513
Delwath: Gets 20 more except somebody.
c03514
Unknown: I guess Seeker normally doesn't get the extras from Aid.
c03515
DM: So
c03516
Unknown: Okay
c03517
DM: Wellby and Kenzo-
c03518
Unknown: So 30
c03519
DM: ... set it to 31.
c03520
Delwath: And Delwath.
c03521
DM: And Delwath.
c03522
Unknown: Nice. Nice.
c03523
Unknown: Nice.
c03524
DM: Nice.
c03525
DM: And you are-
c03526
Seeker: Do you still like it? Okay, I said that on the character sheet.
c03527
Wellby: Yep, I'll get there in a minute.
c03528
DM: You are immune to the frightened and poisoned conditions.
c03529
DM: You have resistance to poison damage.
c03530
Unknown: Okay.
c03531
Seeker: I think we did the right thing.
c03532
Unknown: And now we-
c03533
DM: Are you changing your sword?
c03534
Delwath: ... fish. Oh, yes I am changing my sword.
c03535
Unknown: Um,
c03536
Delwath: probably to
c03537
Unknown: Arborea.
c03538
DM: Okay.
c03539
Delwath: I think, I think,
c03540
Unknown: um-
c03541
DM: Mechanist and Arborea
c03542
Delwath: ... I think Mechanist and Arborea 'cause Pandemonium is not likely to be useful.
c03543
DM: Pandemonium gives you-
c03544
Unknown: Psychic damage
c03545
DM: ... no, immune, ignore resistance to slash damage.
c03546
Delwath: Oh, that could be useful actually.
c03547
Delwath: Um, actually
c03548
Delwath: I might do that instead.
c03549
Delwath: I'm gonna do that.
c03550
DM: Okay.
c03551
Delwath: It also gives me advantage on saving throws against possession, so that's not way off base.
c03552
DM: [coughs] Yes. [coughs] Okay.
c03553
DM: So
c03554
DM: the morning comes.
c03555
DM: Uh, the a- you've, you set up camp about a mile from the ash storm, and it's now spread
c03556
DM: so that the edges of the storm are l- are lapping up against your tents.
c03557
Unknown: Oh boy.
c03558
DM: As you wake from the, a nice rest, refreshed with your hero's feast.
c03559
Delwath: Everybody gets hero points of inspiration.
c03560
Unknown: With your inspiration, your extra hit points, everything.
c03561
Unknown: Sweet.
c03562
DM: So you're now, you are now maybe 15, f- 15 miles from the
c03563
DM: plaza as the storm has grown slightly.
c03564
DM: Grew a, a couple miles over the course of the night.
c03565
DM: [gentle music] And where are you heading?
c03566
Unknown: River.
c03567
Seeker: Up river, outside the storm.
c03568
DM: Well, the river's the... Oh, go to the river outside the storm and then travel up river till you get to-
c03569
Seeker: Yeah, that's what I was thinking.
c03570
DM: Yeah.
c03571
Kenzo: He has a return to Leviathan. That's cool.
c03572
DM: Yeah, I think, yeah.
c03573
Unknown: Sweet.
c03574
Delwath: I feel a little derivative here, but I think it's the right choice.
c03575
Seeker: I mean, it's a team effort.
c03576
DM: Yeah.
c03577
c03578
Seeker: There you go. [paper rustling] Two leviathan is better than one leviathan.
c03579
Unknown: That's true.
c03580
DM: That is a true statement.
c03581
Wellby: As the saying goes.
c03582
Unknown: [laughs] Um, can-
c03583
Kenzo: Can, can there be three leviathans?
c03584
Unknown: No.
c03585
DM: No, not in a fight.
c03586
Unknown: It's not powerful though.
c03587
Wellby: Three leviathans are not better than two.
c03588
Unknown: Oh, I never found out what that was.
c03589
Kenzo: I don't know where the stat block-
c03590
Wellby: As the saying goes.
c03591
DM: You do have a scroll of wish.
c03592
Kenzo: [laughs] There could be three leviathans.
c03593
Unknown: There could be three Leviathans.
c03594
DM: But you can't use wish to cast a ninth level spell.
c03595
Unknown: Correct.
c03596
Unknown: Yeah.
c03597
DM: Um-
c03598
Seeker: 341 HP. [paper rustling] Wait, this must be a different leviathan 'cause it has a 40-foot swim.
c03599
Unknown: [paper rustling]
c03600
Wellby: Is it the old, uh...
c03601
Seeker: I don't know, man. Where, where do I, where should I find the stat block?
c03602
Delwath: Tim's gonna send it to you.
c03603
DM: Yeah, let me find it.
c03604
Delwath: It has 120 foot swim, 328 hit points.
c03605
Wellby: It's coming.
c03606
Delwath: AC 17, good wisdom and charisma saves, good strength.
c03607
DM: Yeah.
c03608
Delwath: Really good con, plus 10 con.
c03609
Wellby: I don't know exactly.
c03610
Unknown: Dining room?
c03611
Wellby: It's gonna be-
c03612
Delwath: Actually, in general, pretty good saves except INT saves are terrible.
c03613
Wellby: It's gonna be-
c03614
Delwath: Wait, can you keep your metal boots?
c03615
Kenzo: I guess when we host big twists and stuff it's probably on the top floor.
c03616
DM: With a shape change, yes.
c03617
Kenzo: Maybe this is like the, uh-
c03618
Wellby: This is, this is like the family room.
c03619
Kenzo: Exactly. Yeah, yeah.
c03620
Unknown: This is our own-
c03621
DM: All right, I texted it to you.
c03622
DM: [gentle music] [keyboard clacking]
c03623
Seeker: Thank you. [keyboard clacking] All right, now I got it.
c03624
Unknown: [laughs] [objects thudding]
c03625
Wellby: Yeah. [keyboard clacking]
c03626
Seeker: Oh, it did acid damage. Oh, well.
c03627
Kenzo: [laughs] So this is the whole wanna make a slight change, you have to do all the moves.
c03628
Unknown: [laughs]
c03629
Wellby: Yes. [laughs] Exactly.
c03630
Wellby: This is the-
c03631
DM: Right. In the-
c03632
Wellby: ... idea to be your own contractor
c03633
DM: ... true, true polymorph is, is worse than shape change because you can't,
c03634
DM: um,
c03635
DM: you can't speak or cast spells unless-
c03636
Unknown: Slightly
c03637
DM: ... you can speak only if the anatomy of its new form lets you speak-
c03638
Unknown: Wait, where is it?
c03639
DM: ... and you can't cast spells And you can't benefit from equipment, and you only retain your alignment and personality.
c03640
DM: So like you, you retain your,
c03641
DM: you retain your,
c03642
DM: like, mental ability to plan for those purposes.
c03643
DM: But you do not retain your mental ability scores for saving throws-
c03644
Unknown: Right
c03645
DM: ... or skills.
c03646
Delwath: And, and if the Levi- since the leviathan can't talk, I wouldn't be able to talk.
c03647
DM: You would not be able to talk, yes.
c03648
Unknown: Okay.
c03649
Wellby: [laughs] You know, pros and cons I guess.
c03650
Delwath: No, that's fine. I mean,
c03651
Delwath: Delwath is more the will animating.
c03652
DM: [coughs]
c03653
Delwath: It's probably more, if I would imagine, it's more like Delwath's will is still animating the creature.
c03654
DM: Right.
c03655
Delwath: So it's not like it's just gonna run amuck, but it's really a force of nature.
c03656
DM: Yeah.
c03657
Unknown: It's like Delwath-
c03658
DM: Oh, yeah
c03659
Delwath: ... Pass force of nature, not
c03660
Unknown: Delwath-
c03661
DM: Where, where Seeker is just a Seeker leviathan.
c03662
Unknown: Right.
c03663
DM: 'Cause you retain your mental ability scores.
c03664
Unknown: But that's okay.
c03665
Unknown: And beard.
c03666
DM: Yeah, and beard.
c03667
Unknown: [laughs]
c03668
DM: Obviously. Oh, we need an...
c03669
Unknown: Okay, here.
c03670
Unknown: Im- important.
c03671
DM: Mike can be a crab leviathan if you want.
c03672
Kenzo: Also, what time did we wanna try to go watch the sunset?
c03673
Unknown: Although it's pretty cloudy now.
c03674
Unknown: Um
c03675
Delwath: Um, it is pretty cloudy, but the sunset's like at 5:45, so we should-
c03676
Unknown: Be like an hour and a half
c03677
Delwath: ... we should like give ourselves...
c03678
Unknown: All right
c03679
Delwath: We should meet at 4:45.
c03680
Delwath: Maybe a few, like 4:30.
c03681
Delwath: Like an hour and a half maybe we sort of, we sorta-
c03682
Unknown: Yeah
c03683
Delwath: ... take a break or...
c03684
DM: Yeah. That was, yeah, 4:30 is what I wanna stop so we can-
c03685
Unknown: Awesome
c03686
DM: ... we can drive down.
c03687
Unknown: All right.
c03688
Unknown: Oh, wow.
c03689
DM: Okay.
c03690
DM: So we're not, I don't think we're gonna quite finish this before, but that's okay.
c03691
Unknown: No, that's-
c03692
DM: We'll do a little dinner.
c03693
Delwath: Maybe we can at least, hopefully we can at least, uh, kill the one in the river.
c03694
Unknown: Yeah, exactly.
c03695
Delwath: Then see what happens.
c03696
DM: Okay.
c03697
Kenzo: Kenzo's ready.
c03698
DM: So you pass through the...
c03699
DM: Nobody has to bother making saves because-
c03700
Unknown: [laughs]
c03701
DM: ... um, the,
c03702
DM: uh... So you're just, you're just going upriver basically, right?
c03703
Delwath: No, that's not gonna work. You can't really make it bigger.
c03704
Unknown: Oh, you can. [laughs]
c03705
Unknown: [laughs]
c03706
DM: [laughs]
c03707
Delwath: I've given you a challenge.
c03708
Kenzo: Well, before this is done, we'll, [laughs] we'll see how much bigger I can actually...
c03709
Kenzo: 'Cause I can see you've already pulled out some of the things that make it bigger.
c03710
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
c03711
Unknown: I love it.
c03712
DM: Okay, so let me-
c03713
Delwath: Just a little bit
c03714
DM: ... uh... So I'll put the river like this.
c03715
DM: Yeah.
c03716
DM: You gotta-
c03717
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. I'm moving it all.
c03718
DM: We don't need this guy.
c03719
DM: So here's like where the riverbank runs roughly.
c03720
DM: And, you know, there's a few like
c03721
DM: still remaining...
c03722
Delwath: Wait, which, um, can...
c03723
DM: This is river.
c03724
Delwath: Uh, this, the, this is the river and this is the bank.
c03725
DM: Yeah.
c03726
Unknown: Okay.
c03727
DM: And you're coming, you come upriver.
c03728
Unknown: Okay. That's good.
c03729
DM: And
c03730
DM: as you approach-
c03731
Unknown: Okay. [laughs]
c03732
DM: ... so you're, you're limited to
c03733
DM: roughly-
c03734
Unknown: [laughs]
c03735
c03736
DM: [laughs]
c03737
Unknown: Sorry. [laughs] It's silly.
c03738
Unknown: [laughs]
c03739
Unknown: What do you even... No.
c03740
Kenzo: It's an accurate representation of Kenzo.
c03741
Unknown: Okay.
c03742
Unknown: [laughs]
c03743
Unknown: [laughs] Okay.
c03744
DM: Um,
c03745
DM: so
c03746
DM: you... The visibility is only 30 feet.
c03747
DM: And as you begin to go,
c03748
DM: go upriver, um,
c03749
DM: you sense,
c03750
DM: uh,
c03751
DM: you know, Kenzo, I'm just gonna let you be sort of attuned to this condensation.
c03752
DM: And you sense that it is, it is retreating as you move until you get close to the plaza.
c03753
Kenzo: Oh, what the fuck is this?
c03754
Kenzo: Oh, my God.
c03755
Unknown: [laughs]
c03756
Kenzo: What is happening?
c03757
Unknown: Uh...
c03758
Kenzo: No way.
c03759
DM: Uh, when, um,
c03760
DM: lunging from
c03761
DM: the shore into the river, you see this massive shape
c03762
DM: emerging in the distance, kind of-
c03763
Delwath: Wait, where was the thing in the river?
c03764
DM: It vanished.
c03765
Unknown: Okay.
c03766
DM: They are temporary condensations in the morning.
c03767
Unknown: Okay.
c03768
DM: As you fly up, it re-
c03769
Unknown: Oh
c03770
DM: ... it's retreating from the river, pulling back, and then
c03771
DM: leaps out at you,
c03772
DM: just condensing on the ground, rushing across the terrain here.
c03773
DM: Um-
c03774
Kenzo: Wait, are we fighting this or is this the terrain?
c03775
DM: That, that's the ooze.
c03776
Unknown: What?
c03777
DM: So it's-
c03778
Seeker: Hold on a second. Were, were we already leviathaned up?
c03779
Unknown: Well, presumably-
c03780
DM: You have plenty of time to do whatever you want to do here.
c03781
Unknown: Right.
c03782
Seeker: So where, where are we supposed to be?
c03783
DM: Well, you're coming up the river from here.
c03784
Unknown: Okay.
c03785
DM: [laughs]
c03786
Unknown: Oh, my God.
c03787
DM: I don't know how you're traveling.
c03788
Unknown: Well-
c03789
Unknown: Careful.
c03790
Delwath: ... Wellby and Kenzo are presumably...
c03791
Delwath: Wellby can fly, right?
c03792
Unknown: Yep.
c03793
Delwath: So I assume at some point we get into the river.
c03794
DM: You leviathan, you fly.
c03795
Unknown: Right. And we're just swimming in the river.
c03796
DM: So the two leviathans are swimming in the river.
c03797
Delwath: I mean, we might be a little further over.
c03798
Seeker: All right. So what am I gonna
c03799
Unknown: do?
c03800
DM: The-
c03801
Delwath: Where do I put all this stuff?
c03802
DM: Wellby and Kenzo...
c03803
DM: [laughs]
c03804
Kenzo: Just be careful. [laughs]
c03805
Unknown: [laughs]
c03806
Unknown: Watch your step.
c03807
Unknown: Yeah.
c03808
DM: If you f- if this falls over, Kenzo also falls prone.
c03809
DM: No.
c03810
Delwath: No, he's astral. He can't fall prone.
c03811
Unknown: Yeah.
c03812
DM: Right. Kenzo is astral form already.
c03813
Unknown: Yeah.
c03814
DM: Um, Wellby is-
c03815
Unknown: Wellby form
c03816
DM: ... Wellby form, but flying with your wings out from your- And you can see, you see this, your visibility is only 30 feet, so, um,
c03817
DM: uh, because of the intensity of the ash storm.
c03818
DM: So you can't actually see all of the ooze.
c03819
DM: You just see this, like, amorphous shape.
c03820
DM: You can see little bits of stone mixed into it.
c03821
DM: There's like sort of greenish tendrils coming out on the edges.
c03822
Wellby: I think, can we, like, gust of wind it or otherwise, like...
c03823
Wellby: I guess it doesn't matter.
c03824
Seeker: Well, the leviathans have a tidal wave attack.
c03825
DM: Yeah.
c03826
Wellby: [laughs] Awesome.
c03827
Seeker: Which is 250 feet.
c03828
DM: And it's-
c03829
Unknown: No.
c03830
DM: You can, like, it's-
c03831
Seeker: 250, 250 feet long
c03832
DM: ... this is, this is, like, just a massive thing that's, like, creeping.
c03833
DM: It seems like it's creeping along
c03834
Delwath: Right, so like I'm trying to figure out, can we...
c03835
Delwath: Like the leviathan tidal wave attack is 120 feet and then goes for 250 feet.
c03836
Seeker: So we could do it from far, far away.
c03837
DM: Except you can only see 30 feet away from it.
c03838
Unknown: Oh.
c03839
Delwath: So you can only do it from 30 feet away.
c03840
DM: Your visibility is 30 feet because of the ash.
c03841
Seeker: Right, but we can just retreat pretty far and then send out multiple tidal waves.
c03842
Delwath: Well, it only recharges on a six, so-
c03843
Unknown: Oh
c03844
Delwath: ... you're probably not gonna get that many unless you get lucky.
c03845
Delwath: We get two. We get two. [laughs]
c03846
Delwath: But we also have to... It can only be created,
c03847
Unknown: uh...
c03848
Delwath: Right, okay. So it,
c03849
Delwath: would probably be hard to target it until we can see the point.
c03850
Unknown: Also-
c03851
Delwath: I think it's Tim's point
c03852
Seeker: ... also there's no way for
c03853
Seeker: the humanoids to escape from it unless they're in the air, I guess.
c03854
DM: They're flying.
c03855
Unknown: They're flying in the air.
c03856
Delwath: It's up to 250 feet tall, which generally in D&D terms means you don't have to make it that big.
c03857
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c03858
DM: Right?
c03859
Seeker: We can make a two-dimensional tidal wave.
c03860
DM: Yeah, it could just be narrow.
c03861
Unknown: [laughs]
c03862
Delwath: Right? It's up to 250 feet long and up to 250 feet wide.
c03863
Unknown: [laughs]
c03864
Delwath: It can just be, it can just be 50 by 50.
c03865
Seeker: It's a little tidal wave bullet.
c03866
Unknown: It's very strong.
c03867
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
c03868
DM: Right?
c03869
Delwath: It's gonna have a good strength saving throw.
c03870
Unknown: Yeah.
c03871
DM: But that's okay.
c03872
DM: So
c03873
DM: what are you gonna do?
c03874
Kenzo: We, we gotta go for it.
c03875
DM: I mean, I guess you better roll initiative-
c03876
Unknown: Yeah
c03877
DM: ... because you, you can't see it until you're within 30 feet of it anyway.
c03878
DM: The massive ooze lurking on the shore
c03879
DM: in wait.
c03880
Delwath: What is the leviathan's initiative?
c03881
Seeker: Oh, wait, so do I use my-
c03882
Delwath: Use the leviathan
c03883
DM: The leviathans.
c03884
Unknown: 12. [dice rolling]
c03885
Unknown: 23.
c03886
Unknown: 18. [dice rolling]
c03887
Wellby: Oh.
c03888
DM: Sorry, 18... Who rolled an 18?
c03889
DM: Seeker?
c03890
Unknown: Yeah.
c03891
DM: 23?
c03892
Kenzo: 23 for Kenzo.
c03893
Unknown: 22 for Wellby.
c03894
DM: Mike, what did you roll as well? Uh, 12.
c03895
Delwath: 13. No, 12.
c03896
Delwath: Can't do math.
c03897
DM: Okay. So the ooze goes first
c03898
DM: and it is going to turn, seeing you approach,
c03899
DM: slip into the water.
c03900
Unknown: We're flying.
c03901
DM: Um,
c03902
DM: yes. And then,
c03903
DM: uh,
c03904
DM: the first thing it's going to do,
c03905
DM: uh, is send
c03906
DM: pseudopod attacks
c03907
DM: against...
c03908
DM: Go, uh, the two flying creatures.
c03909
DM: So two against Kenzo. [dice rolling]
c03910
Unknown: Ooh.
c03911
DM: That's a
c03912
DM: 21 and a 25.
c03913
Kenzo: Uh, only one hits.
c03914
DM: So, uh, you take 18 points of bludgeoning.
c03915
Kenzo: Uh, deflect attack.
c03916
DM: Plus nine points of, or 11 points of acid.
c03917
DM: Go ahead and deflect.
c03918
Kenzo: And so how much is that total?
c03919
Unknown: Leviathan is so good against this.
c03920
Delwath: It's doing bludgeoning and acid.
c03921
DM: Yeah.
c03922
Delwath: I'm resistant to bludgeoning and immune to acid.
c03923
DM: Yeah.
c03924
Delwath: I assume it's immune to acid.
c03925
DM: Yes.
c03926
Delwath: Because leviathan
c03927
Kenzo: does acid damage.
c03928
Unknown: Acid damage to that one?
c03929
Seeker: Yeah, but we're not gonna use that.
c03930
Unknown: Yeah.
c03931
DM: 18 and...
c03932
Unknown: So it's like 32 total.
c03933
Kenzo: 32 total. [dice rolling] Uh, I did not cover it.
c03934
Kenzo: So I just reduce the damage by
c03935
Kenzo: 13 plus 7, 20.
c03936
Kenzo: I reduce it by 20.
c03937
DM: N- no. I don't think that's right.
c03938
DM: Don't you reduce the damage by it, plus your level?
c03939
Kenzo: Oh, a 1d10-
c03940
Unknown: 1d10 plus-
c03941
Unknown: Plus 27
c03942
Kenzo: ... 27. Ah.
c03943
Unknown: Oh,
c03944
Kenzo: that's way better. Oh, yeah, so 37.
c03945
DM: No, that damage you rolled is the damage you do when you deflect the attack.
c03946
Kenzo: Got it. Okay, yeah, so 37.
c03947
Kenzo: I, I deflected it all. Hell yeah.
c03948
Unknown: Great.
c03949
DM: Okay. So it...
c03950
DM: Are you... You're deflecting I assume.
c03951
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c03952
DM: So it has to make a dex saving throw.
c03953
Unknown: Yeah, DC 20.
c03954
DM: Fails.
c03955
Kenzo: Sweet. So I just did-
c03956
DM: So what was that?
c03957
DM: What did you roll for the-
c03958
Unknown: 13.
c03959
Unknown: 20.
c03960
DM: 20 damage, okay.
c03961
DM: So
c03962
Unknown: Oh my God
c03963
DM: it takes 20 damage,
c03964
DM: uh, except it's deflects...
c03965
DM: When you deflect, it does the same
c03966
DM: damage as it did, right? So it doesn't take the acid damage from its own attack.
c03967
Unknown: Okay.
c03968
Delwath: Oh, no, wait. No, no, no, it's new damage.
c03969
DM: But what does it say?
c03970
Kenzo: Of the same type dealt by the attack.
c03971
DM: Yeah, so half of it is bludgeoning, half of it's acid.
c03972
Unknown: Right.
c03973
DM: So it only takes half. It only takes 10 damage.
c03974
Kenzo: [laughs] I'm, I'm tracking my key, Tim.
c03975
Unknown: Okay.
c03976
Unknown: Um...
c03977
DM: So then it's gonna make a pseudopod attack on Wellby.
c03978
DM: That's a 20 to hit.
c03979
Wellby: That just barely hits me. Yes.
c03980
DM: So you take,
c03981
DM: uh, 20 points of bludgeoning plus eight points of acid, so 28 total.
c03982
Wellby: Uh, I'll uncannily dodge that.
c03983
DM: Okay.
c03984
Unknown: Is this 14?
c03985
DM: Yep.
c03986
DM: Uh, and that's gonna end his turn.
c03987
Delwath: Okay. I'm gonna take a legendary action to move my move.
c03988
DM: Okay.
c03989
DM: Seeker, do you want to take a legendary action too?
c03990
Unknown: Oh, so-
c03991
Unknown: Oh my God, [laughs] this is gonna be ridiculous.
c03992
Seeker: Is there an advantage to...
c03993
Seeker: I say telepathically to my other leviathan friend, to us spreading out?
c03994
DM: Water good. [laughs]
c03995
Unknown: [laughs]
c03996
c03997
DM: Ooze bad.
c03998
Unknown: Okay.
c03999
DM: Kill it. Delwath only has like two intelligence right now.
c04000
Unknown: Sorry I asked.
c04001
DM: [laughs]
c04002
Unknown: I'll, uh,
c04003
Seeker: I'll just go right over here.
c04004
DM: So also a legendary.
c04005
Unknown: Aw.
c04006
DM: Uh, so Kenzo's up now.
c04007
DM: You are 30 feet away from the ooze, up in the air.
c04008
DM: So-
c04009
Seeker: I have a 20-foot reach.
c04010
DM: Yeah.
c04011
Kenzo: Which would be like...
c04012
Seeker: Yeah, I'm like, you know, I'm...
c04013
Kenzo: Uh, I think I'm gonna-
c04014
DM: I assume you're like under water at the moment.
c04015
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Swimming in the water.
c04016
DM: Yeah.
c04017
Unknown: Yeah, swimming.
c04018
Kenzo: Is this, is this in the water right now as well?
c04019
DM: It's half in the water, half out of the water.
c04020
Kenzo: Okay, cool. Yeah, I'll attack the part that's not in the water with my-
c04021
DM: Yeah, I mean, it's like 50 feet or like 80 feet across or something, so there's a lot of space you can hit.
c04022
Kenzo: Sul side first, then.
c04023
DM: Um-
c04024
Wellby: Yeah
c04025
DM: ... okay.
c04026
Seeker: I might want to be further away because...
c04027
DM: So it's immune to acid damage as expected.
c04028
DM: Um, charmed, exhausted, frightened-
c04029
Unknown: Yeah
c04030
DM: ... grappled, poisoned, prone, restrained.
c04031
Unknown: Yeah, we get all that from-
c04032
DM: You got all that. Um-
c04033
Unknown: Resistances?
c04034
DM: Uh, no resistances.
c04035
Unknown: Okay.
c04036
DM: It's good at...
c04037
DM: S- strength is its best save.
c04038
DM: INT-
c04039
Unknown: [laughs] Strength
c04040
DM: ... is its worst save.
c04041
Kenzo: Int is its worst?
c04042
DM: Yeah.
c04043
DM: Um-
c04044
Unknown: [laughs]
c04045
Seeker: INT is its worst save, interesting.
c04046
DM: What else? What else you learn?
c04047
Unknown: [coughs]
c04048
DM: I never actually... This is... I never actually calculated a CR for this.
c04049
Unknown: It doesn't matter.
c04050
DM: It's a high CR.
c04051
Delwath: So it's basically immune to all conditions.
c04052
Delwath: It's, it's actually quite similar to a leviathan.
c04053
DM: It is, yeah.
c04054
Delwath: [laughs] Uh, immune to what?
c04055
Delwath: Acid and poison?
c04056
DM: Yeah.
c04057
Wellby: Acid and poison.
c04058
Delwath: But no resistances.
c04059
DM: No, no additional resistances-
c04060
Unknown: Yeah
c04061
DM: ... beyond the damage immunities.
c04062
Unknown: Okay. Kenzo's flying up to punch it.
c04063
Delwath: [coughs] You should, um, you should bring up your half dam- half resistance.
c04064
Unknown: Yeah, um-
c04065
DM: Your damage resistance, I mean.
c04066
Kenzo: Yeah, so T- Kenzo will spend three ki on superior defense.
c04067
Kenzo: And then, um, I think it's worth it to do the, the, the langau's claw.
c04068
Delwath: It adds a D6.
c04069
Unknown: Adds your D6, yeah.
c04070
Delwath: This could... Actually, this could stretch for a while.
c04071
Delwath: It is probably worth it.
c04072
Kenzo: All right. So I'll bonus action langsoos claw.
c04073
DM: How long does it last?
c04074
Unknown: Uh-
c04075
DM: It lasts for an hour, right? Or does it last for...
c04076
Kenzo: I think it lasts for a minute. Is it an hour?
c04077
Kenzo: Yeah, I think it's more like a minute.
c04078
DM: Okay. Yeah, yeah.
c04079
Unknown: One minute.
c04080
DM: Yeah, but that's 10 rounds. That's worth it.
c04081
Kenzo: Okay. All right. I'll do that.
c04082
DM: And then you make your staff attacks.
c04083
Kenzo: So two s- two staff attacks.
c04084
Kenzo: Uh, no, no advantage or anything, right?
c04085
DM: Nope.
c04086
Kenzo: Uh, 21 and something really high.
c04087
DM: 21 just hits.
c04088
DM: Something really high obviously hits.
c04089
Unknown: All right. So those both hit, and then
c04090
Kenzo: I do... Oh, wow, D12 plus 9.
c04091
Kenzo: Okay, so now I do 3 D12.
c04092
DM: 3 D12 plus 18.
c04093
Kenzo: Plus 18, yeah.
c04094
Kenzo: Where are the D12s? [paper rustling] Uh, 18-
c04095
Unknown: Plus 18, 36.
c04096
Unknown: 36.
c04097
DM: There we go.
c04098
Unknown: Cool.
c04099
DM: Uh, at the end of your turn, it will use a legendary action.
c04100
Unknown: Oh, boy.
c04101
DM: Um-
c04102
Delwath: How do you resolve two creatures trying to use a legendary action at the same time?
c04103
Unknown: [laughs]
c04104
DM: [laughs] Um, initiative order.
c04105
Unknown: Initiative order.
c04106
Unknown: I guess initiative order. I think it's gateways.
c04107
DM: So the ooze, ooze always beats you.
c04108
DM: Um-
c04109
Unknown: 'Cause I'm also using a legendary action
c04110
DM: ... so again, it hasn't noticed the two leviathans yet.
c04111
Delwath: Has Ken, uh... Kenzo hasn't gone yet.
c04112
Unknown: I mean-
c04113
DM: Kenzo just went. Wellby's next.
c04114
Delwath: Sorry. Okay, no, I'm gonna hold my action.
c04115
DM: Uh, you... Both, uh, Kenzo and Delwath make dexterity saving-
c04116
Unknown: Wellby and Wellby.
c04117
DM: Sorry, Wellby and, and Kenzo make dexterity saving throws as a globule of acid shoots off his back and then explodes at a point in the air right about there.
c04118
Unknown: Uh-
c04119
Unknown: Reroll. Key
c04120
Kenzo: ... I rolled a one, but I, I'm gonna...
c04121
Kenzo: I, I can spend a ki to re-roll it.
c04122
DM: Yeah.
c04123
Wellby: 28 for me.
c04124
Unknown: Uh,
c04125
Unknown: 18.
c04126
DM: That does not succeed.
c04127
Kenzo: Uh, I will use a-
c04128
Unknown: Bardic inspiration
c04129
Unknown: ... bardic inspiration.
c04130
Unknown: Do we have-
c04131
DM: You don't have any
c04132
Delwath: ... do we have...
c04133
Delwath: Did we give out bardics? You probably should have given everybody a bardic.
c04134
Unknown: Yeah.
c04135
Delwath: We always give everybody a bardic.
c04136
DM: Okay, okay. Everybody has...
c04137
DM: You all have bardics.
c04138
Unknown: 'Cause you have, what, six total?
c04139
Unknown: I do.
c04140
DM: Yeah, so that's half.
c04141
Delwath: So everybody, each of us has one, and then-
c04142
Kenzo: Is this like roll two and then pick the highest?
c04143
DM: No, roll one.
c04144
Kenzo: No, no, it's roll one.
c04145
Unknown: Okay. Uh, 26.
c04146
DM: Okay, that succeeds.
c04147
DM: So both of you dodge out of the way of the massive burst of acid that explodes, avoiding getting drenched in dripping acidic poison ooze.
c04148
Kenzo: That sounds like a good thing that we did.
c04149
DM: And that ends its legendary action.
c04150
DM: Any other legendary actions?
c04151
Delwath: No, I'm very glad because you'll give us advantage on attacks, right?
c04152
Delwath: Wait, no, no. Uh, Eric,
c04153
Delwath: once Wellby attacks, we both should do our legendaries to do a slam attack.
c04154
DM: Oh, okay.
c04155
Delwath: Because we'll have advantage from Wellby's-
c04156
Unknown: Ah.
c04157
DM: Okay.
c04158
Unknown: Great.
c04159
DM: So Wellby, you're up.
c04160
Seeker: And that costs two anyway. That's okay.
c04161
DM: Correct. Um-
c04162
Wellby: The entire creature counts as one creature for the purposes of a second sneak attack.
c04163
Wellby: It's not like-
c04164
DM: Yeah, yeah, the whole-
c04165
Unknown: Kenzo is a different-
c04166
DM: Right. Yeah, no, it counts as one creature.
c04167
Wellby: Uh, reroll one.
c04168
Wellby: That's a 28 or something like that.
c04169
DM: That hits. The 21 from Kenzo hit, so.
c04170
Unknown: 21 hits.
c04171
Wellby: I think it is resistant to every single special thing that I can do.
c04172
DM: I think it is too.
c04173
Wellby: Um, so I'm just gonna...
c04174
Wellby: 3, 6, 9,
c04175
Wellby: 10.
c04176
Wellby: [dice rattling] [die rolling] Uh, 5, 10, 20, 30, uh, 35, 43.
c04177
Wellby: 43.
c04178
Unknown: Uh-
c04179
DM: Okay
c04180
Wellby: ... is it resistant to lightning?
c04181
DM: Uh, nope. It's just immune to acid and poison and has no additional damage resistances.
c04182
Wellby: Uh, I may as well use the lightning arrow then in a second at- [die rolling] tack, which I have.
c04183
DM: You didn't use your bonus action for anything, so...
c04184
Wellby: Yeah.
c04185
Wellby: Uh, that's high 20s again.
c04186
DM: Yep.
c04187
DM: That's a dex save.
c04188
Wellby: Uh, these are 19 dex.
c04189
DM: Uh, it succeeds then.
c04190
Wellby: Uh...
c04191
DM: Oh wait, no
c04192
Wellby: Oh wait, wait. It's not a save for the target
c04193
DM: ... it doesn't... It's just the target-
c04194
Wellby: Yeah
c04195
DM: So it doesn't, it takes the...
c04196
DM: So it's-
c04197
Wellby: So it's nine regular damage
c04198
DM: ... and 4d6 lightning.
c04199
Wellby: Yep.
c04200
Wellby: Uh, 8, 10, 15 lightning.
c04201
DM: Okay.
c04202
DM: Got it.
c04203
DM: Is that the end of your turn?
c04204
Unknown: That is the end of my turn.
c04205
Delwath: Okay. Tim, there's no point in rolling the acid damage, right?
c04206
Unknown: 'Cause it's immune.
c04207
DM: Yeah, it's immune to acid.
c04208
Wellby: Oh, actually, uh, I'm also...
c04209
Wellby: I'm gonna move to a place that's, like, 100 feet away from-
c04210
DM: Okay. So now you can't see it, though
c04211
Unknown: ... the ooze.
c04212
Unknown: Your visibility is only 30 feet because of the-
c04213
Wellby: Well, I'm gonna stay 30 feet...
c04214
Wellby: Oh, shit. Do we wanna stay within visual, seeing each other?
c04215
DM: I don't know if that matters.
c04216
Wellby: So I'm gonna stay 30 feet above it, but go, like, way to another part of it so that a single effect couldn't hit both Kenzo and I, hopefully.
c04217
Delwath: Okay. So, so you like-
c04218
DM: A huge-
c04219
DM: ... fly around towards the back?
c04220
Unknown: Exactly.
c04221
DM: All right. A huge
c04222
Delwath: fist materializes from the water
c04223
Delwath: and slam, punches into the ooze.
c04224
DM: [die rolling]
c04225
Seeker: Wait, how are you doing that?
c04226
DM: That's your action.
c04227
Delwath: Oh, but a 19 might miss.
c04228
DM: A 19 misses.
c04229
Unknown: No.
c04230
Seeker: Wait, that's its slam attack?
c04231
DM: Yeah.
c04232
Unknown: Oh.
c04233
DM: You can do one, too.
c04234
Seeker: Uh, I'm doing that.
c04235
DM: Oh, so slam attack. Okay.
c04236
Unknown: Um-
c04237
DM: So now it knows you're here 'cause you're-
c04238
Unknown: Yeah
c04239
DM: ... slamming it.
c04240
Seeker: What do, what do I roll?
c04241
Delwath: It's... Well, you have advantage, so 2d20 and then add 14.
c04242
DM: So sorry, this is after Wellby's turn.
c04243
Seeker: Yep. 30.
c04244
DM: 30.
c04245
DM: Nice.
c04246
Delwath: So that hit, so it's 2d12,
c04247
Unknown: 2d12 plus 8 damage.
c04248
Wellby: I have a thing at the end of your turn I just wanna remember.
c04249
Delwath: So at the end of this turn. [die rolling]
c04250
Delwath: So 26.
c04251
Unknown: Yeah.
c04252
DM: 26 damage?
c04253
Unknown: 26.
c04254
DM: And you're not rolling the acid, right?
c04255
Unknown: Correct.
c04256
DM: This is just the-
c04257
Delwath: Yeah, that's, that's bludgeoning.
c04258
Seeker: Just the 2d12.
c04259
Delwath: It's 4d12, including acid-
c04260
DM: Okay
c04261
Delwath: ... we're, we're rolling bludgeoning. [die rolling]
c04262
DM: Okay.
c04263
DM: Uh... [clears throat]
c04264
Unknown: Sweet
c04265
DM: Wait, did it use its le-
c04266
Kenzo: It, it did. It used legendary.
c04267
DM: It used the le- it used legendary.
c04268
Delwath: It used a legendary action.
c04269
DM: Yeah. Got it.
c04270
Unknown: I don't know the-
c04271
Wellby: Wellby will say telepathically to the rest of us, "There's this tendril in back that's heading back towards the central plaza, like a,
c04272
Wellby: like a thing that's connecting it back to the center again."
c04273
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Let's stop that.
c04274
Wellby: Should we try and-
c04275
Unknown: Yeah
c04276
Wellby: ... cut it off?
c04277
Unknown: Yeah.
c04278
DM: Yeah.
c04279
Kenzo: Let's, let's, let's stop that.
c04280
Seeker: What does Del, with Leviathan say to that, say to that?
c04281
Unknown: Gargle and raw. [laughs]
c04282
Delwath: Ooze bad.
c04283
DM: Kill ooze.
c04284
Delwath: Hurting water. Ooze hurting water.
c04285
Unknown: Kill ooze.
c04286
DM: Uh, it's Seeker's turn now, your actual turn, not your legendary.
c04287
Unknown: Pretty smart.
c04288
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Um, uh, maybe I go after that.
c04289
Seeker: I'm gonna cast a-
c04290
DM: Wellby?
c04291
Delwath: Oh, right. You can cast.
c04292
DM: Yeah.
c04293
Unknown: Yeah.
c04294
DM: Right.
c04295
Unknown: Pretty fast.
c04296
DM: Oh, yeah. I have to choose between-
c04297
Unknown: Oh, is this the tendril?
c04298
Wellby: I think so
c04299
Seeker: ... it's basi- it's gonna be Rune of Psychic Destruction,
c04300
Seeker: which I will cast at...
c04301
Kenzo: This looks like a weird, like, sea urchin.
c04302
DM: Wait, you're up in the air, right?
c04303
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
c04304
DM: And we're both, like-
c04305
Wellby: Like 30 or 40 feet up
c04306
Seeker: ... I will cast at,
c04307
Seeker: let's say
c04308
Seeker: seventh level.
c04309
Kenzo: Each one of these squares is how many?
c04310
DM: Five.
c04311
Wellby: Five.
c04312
Unknown: Oh, five.
c04313
Unknown: Um,
c04314
Seeker: so that's a DC 19 int save.
c04315
DM: Int is its worst save.
c04316
DM: [die rolling] But it rolled a natural 20.
c04317
Unknown: Aw.
c04318
Unknown: So
c04319
Seeker: it's not incapacitated and then half-
c04320
DM: It's probably half damage
c04321
Seeker: ... so it's 10d6.
c04322
DM: Divided by two.
c04323
Seeker: ... um, I'll just do that here.
c04324
DM: Yeah, and that's faster. [pens scribbling]
c04325
Unknown: Yeah.
c04326
Seeker: 35 divided by 2.
c04327
Unknown: 18.
c04328
DM: Okay.
c04329
Kenzo: 17. 17.
c04330
DM: It's razed down to 17.
c04331
Unknown: Okay. [dice rolling]
c04332
DM: Uh, that, is that end of your turn?
c04333
Delwath: Uh, you get two attacks. Or no, that's a five.
c04334
Seeker: I could probably move also.
c04335
Unknown: So if I move right... Yeah,
c04336
Unknown: I'm done.
c04337
DM: Okay. Uh, it's going to now use a legendary action.
c04338
DM: Um,
c04339
DM: so it is going to drop a,
c04340
DM: uh, falling around...
c04341
DM: Well, the rest of you can't see this.
c04342
DM: Kenzo, make a dexterity saving throw.
c04343
Kenzo: Wait, Kenzo or Wellby?
c04344
Unknown: That's Wellby.
c04345
Unknown: Oh, Wellby in the back. [die rolling]
c04346
Unknown: 16.
c04347
DM: That fails.
c04348
Kenzo: Grog? Or, or, uh, Barik?
c04349
Wellby: Uh, I'll still only take half damage, so I'll...
c04350
Wellby: I'm gonna see how this is.
c04351
DM: Um,
c04352
DM: a, another globule of, of acid sprays,
c04353
DM: sprays towards you like a, like a fine, uh,
c04354
DM: string of nets-
c04355
Wellby: Mm
c04356
DM: ... wrapping around you
c04357
DM: and you are now restrained.
c04358
Wellby: Ah.
c04359
DM: And you take, uh...
c04360
DM: The damage is poison, so you take no damage.
c04361
DM: Oh, you take a quarter damage because you are re-
c04362
Wellby: Resistant
c04363
DM: ... e- evasion plus resistance, so...
c04364
Kenzo: I feel like it's good to avoid these things, 'cause yeah, they're restraining, getting grappled-
c04365
DM: So you take eight points-
c04366
Unknown: ... getting knocked out
c04367
DM: ... of damage, but you are restrained-
c04368
Wellby: Which sets-
c04369
DM: ... which sets your move to zero and, um, you have disadvantage on all attacks, and all attacks against you have advantage
c04370
Wellby: Is restrained the same or different from grappled?
c04371
DM: It is different from grappled
c04372
Wellby: So the advantage that I have to escape from grappled is not the same as-
c04373
DM: Does not the same as advantage or restrained
c04374
Wellby: Yeah.
c04375
DM: Um, you get a save-
c04376
Kenzo: Yeah, because the g- you get knocked out, and then we have to spend-
c04377
DM: You get a new save at the end of every turn
c04378
Unknown: Yeah
c04379
DM: So at the end of your next turn, you can save to escape automatically.
c04380
DM: Who's up?
c04381
DM: Um, Delwath is up.
c04382
DM: That was the ooze's legendary, unless-
c04383
Unknown: No
c04384
DM: ... unless you want to take a... Oh, you're out of legendaries.
c04385
Delwath: Yeah, I got them back. Seeker can take a legendary.
c04386
DM: You can take a legendary after your own turn
c04387
Unknown: Oh.
c04388
Unknown: right. Yeah, yeah,
c04389
Unknown: yeah
c04390
DM: So it's very complicated with the number of legendary actions [laughs].
c04391
Unknown: Yeah, it's insane. Yeah.
c04392
Unknown: Um...
c04393
DM: [laughs]
c04394
Seeker: Oh, so I think the pseudo-
c04395
Seeker: So I had to do some memory reset.
c04396
Delwath: Do we think the pseudopod can be broken?
c04397
Kenzo: Yeah. You think the what?
c04398
DM: You have no idea.
c04399
Delwath: Well, I'm gonna try
c04400
Kenzo: Yeah, Ken- Kenzo's gonna fly over here too and try to break this thing off
c04401
Delwath: Right. I'm, I'm gonna send a tidal wave right here.
c04402
Delwath: Originate a tidal wave like here, and just go this way
c04403
DM: Okay
c04404
Delwath: Trying to wash away the-
c04405
DM: That's a strength saving throw?
c04406
Delwath: D- yeah, it's a DC 24 strength
c04407
DM: [dice rolling] Ah, that's a 25.
c04408
DM: So it takes half damage or what happened when it-
c04409
Unknown: No
c04410
Unknown: I'll save it takes-
c04411
DM: Can you, can you grab a bowl over there for me so I can put some chips in it?
c04412
Unknown: I sure can.
c04413
Kenzo: You want these chips?
c04414
DM: Yeah.
c04415
Delwath: It's a crappy, crappy, crappy roll.
c04416
Unknown: 10-
c04417
DM: And this is Bludgeoning?
c04418
Unknown: Yeah.
c04419
Delwath: Uh, 10,
c04420
Delwath: mm, uh, 21.
c04421
Delwath: [laughs] Man, that's like minimum damage.
c04422
Unknown: 22.
c04423
DM: So 11 'cause it made the save?
c04424
Unknown: Yep
c04425
DM: Okay. Geez.
c04426
Unknown: That's three ones.
c04427
DM: That's certainly not enough. Whether or not the pseudo pod thing-
c04428
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
c04429
DM: ... can be destroyed-
c04430
Unknown: Yeah
c04431
DM: ... that's certainly enough damage to do anything to it.
c04432
Kenzo: Dude, it should be Delwath. Delwath can like smite and do stuff
c04433
Delwath: I know. Wow, I rolled like three ones.
c04434
Unknown: Yeah
c04435
Delwath: 7d12 is actually pretty good
c04436
DM: Yeah.
c04437
Wellby: It's solid.
c04438
DM: Um,
c04439
DM: at the end of Delwath's turn it's gonna use its last legendary action to just make a pseudopod attack against Wellby with advantage
c04440
DM: I mean-
c04441
DM: That's a 20-something
c04442
Kenzo: ... legendary actions are good too
c04443
Delwath: I might be calling Delwath. I'm trying to get it to like attack me-
c04444
Unknown: Yeah
c04445
Delwath: ... do 300 points of damage, and then I'll turn back into Delwath-
c04446
DM: Um-
c04447
Delwath: ... with full hit points
c04448
DM: ... 4 plus 18, so 22 total damage
c04449
Delwath: That'll do it. I mean...
c04450
Unknown: Yep.
c04451
DM: So that is after Delwath's turn.
c04452
DM: Now we're back up to the start. It's, it's turn again.
c04453
Kenzo: You have a legendary?
c04454
Seeker: I actually could do a legendary now, yeah
c04455
DM: Yes, you could do a legendary as Delwath
c04456
Unknown: Slam it
c04457
Seeker: I'll do my slam again.
c04458
Seeker: [dice rolling] Oh, five and a four.
c04459
Delwath: Um, do we still have advantage?
c04460
Delwath: Yes, until Wellby's turn now
c04461
DM: Until Wellby's turn you have advantage
c04462
Delwath: That's gonna miss though. 19 misses.
c04463
DM: Yeah, 19 misses.
c04464
Kenzo: Okay. So that's just one attack.
c04465
Delwath: We only get one attack as legendary.
c04466
DM: All right.
c04467
Kenzo: Ah, yes.
c04468
DM: Yeah. Okay.
c04469
Seeker: Oh, and this is weird.
c04470
Seeker: It has water form. The leviathan can enter a hostile creature's space and stop there.
c04471
DM: Yeah.
c04472
Seeker: So I could like go on top of it-
c04473
DM: Mm-hmm
c04474
Seeker: ... and I could actually kind of go as far as I want, 'cause 120-
c04475
DM: Yeah
c04476
Unknown: ... in the water
c04477
Kenzo: Well, let's, we're trying to snap this tendril off-
c04478
DM: Mm-hmm
c04479
Kenzo: ... so try to do something here to...
c04480
DM: Oh, that's a good idea. Well, the water ends about in the middle of it.
c04481
DM: It's like half into the water
c04482
Seeker: But I still have 20 feet move
c04483
Seeker: on land.
c04484
DM: Yeah, so you can-
c04485
Seeker: I'll just end my move and go here
c04486
DM: Okay.
c04487
DM: So this massive leviathan crawls through the ooze-
c04488
Unknown: [laughs]
c04489
DM: ... and then settles
c04490
DM: as a like a water, pure water sort of on top, which it writhes and struggles against.
c04491
DM: And then is going to
c04492
DM: blast-
c04493
Delwath: Wait, who's... Oh, Kenzo's next, right?
c04494
DM: It's, its turn. It's gonna blast a line of acid that hits
c04495
DM: that, that hits Seeker Leviathan and Delwath.
c04496
DM: Uh, so-
c04497
Delwath: We're immune to acid damage
c04498
Unknown: Is that Wellby? It's your...
c04499
Kenzo: Seeker Leviathan and Wellby?
c04500
DM: And Wellby, yeah. Sorry
c04501
Delwath: And it's acid damage?
c04502
DM: It is acid damage
c04503
Delwath: Okay. Ha ha ha ha ha.
c04504
DM: Dexterity saving throw.
c04505
Delwath: We're immune to acid damage
c04506
DM: ... for Wellby
c04507
Unknown: Oh
c04508
DM: With disadvantage 'cause you're restrained.
c04509
DM: Yeah,
c04510
DM: S- not doing... It's not great against a levi- a leviathan [laughs].
c04511
Unknown: Uh, 18?
c04512
DM: Uh, that fails.
c04513
Delwath: Uh, Bardic.
c04514
Wellby: There you go.
c04515
Wellby: Uh, 26.
c04516
DM: 26 succeeds.
c04517
Wellby: There we go.
c04518
Delwath: That was a very hesitant succeeds on 26 [laughs].
c04519
Unknown: [laughs] You take no damage
c04520
Unknown: Wow
c04521
DM: That's the end of its turn?
c04522
DM: No, that's just the first thing it did this turn
c04523
DM: Oh, right. Okay. It's gonna make two attacks now.
c04524
Delwath: All right, can I just...
c04525
Delwath: The initiative order is-
c04526
DM: Kenzo-
c04527
Delwath: ... Kenzo, Wellby, Seeker, Delweth
c04528
Delwath: ... I just wanna do a legendary.
c04529
Delwath: Kenzo, Wellby-
c04530
DM: You can do a legendary after its turn-
c04531
Unknown: It's, after Kenzo
c04532
DM: ... after Kenzo's turn.
c04533
Unknown: Okay.
c04534
DM: Yeah.
c04535
Unknown: Uh, so it's gonna make two...
c04536
DM: It's clearly, um, angry at
c04537
DM: Wellby,
c04538
DM: so make two-
c04539
Delwath: You're like, it's not your weekend
c04540
DM: It's gonna make two attacks against Wellby, both with advantage.
c04541
DM: One hits, the other is a 21.
c04542
DM: Does 21 hit?
c04543
Wellby: Indeed it does.
c04544
Kenzo: What the fuck, man?
c04545
Kenzo: We've got these two huge ass leviathans.
c04546
Kenzo: I'm resistant to everything. Why are they fucking going after you, dude?
c04547
Unknown: Wellby.
c04548
Delwath: Possibly because [laughs] we're all resistant to its damage.
c04549
Kenzo: No, but it's in ooze. How does it know?
c04550
DM: I know, it shouldn't know. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
c04551
DM: Uh, sorry, that's 15 plus
c04552
DM: 9.
c04553
Wellby: Awesome.
c04554
DM: ... so 24 for the first hit-
c04555
Wellby: That's not bad.
c04556
DM: ... and then 15 plus- ...
c04557
DM: nine I rolled the exact same thing twice.
c04558
DM: Um, I mean, you might stop to think for like a second about why it might be, again, going against Wellby.
c04559
Delwath: Yeah, 'cause he's the tongue of the pseudopod.
c04560
Wellby: Yes.
c04561
DM: Um-
c04562
Wellby: All right, I just lost half my hit points-
c04563
DM: That ends its turn
c04564
Wellby: ... in the course of one round.
c04565
Delwath: Okay. Legendary action, move 140 feet to join my friend.
c04566
Unknown: Nice.
c04567
DM: [laughs] Okay.
c04568
DM: Uh, I don't know what it's gonna do about this.
c04569
Delwath: Leviathan friends
c04570
Delwath: be together.
c04571
DM: Yes.
c04572
Unknown: Bite tail.
c04573
Delwath: Yeah, you get like a fri- like, Delwath is radiating a sense of real anger about this thing 'cause, like, Delwath is identifying as the Leviathan protector of nature here.
c04574
Delwath: Um, coming out of the water, this is an intrusion of the water.
c04575
Unknown: Yeah.
c04576
Unknown: We have to destroy it.
c04577
Delwath: And he's like, "This is my buddy, Smart Leviathan, who knows what to do, so I'm just gonna follow him."
c04578
DM: [laughs] Right.
c04579
Seeker: [laughs] I'm the l- I'm the nerd Leviathan.
c04580
DM: Exactly.
c04581
Unknown: It's really obvious which one I am.
c04582
Delwath: Well, that was a legendary action.
c04583
DM: [laughs]
c04584
Unknown: [laughs]
c04585
DM: All right, uh, is Seeker doing any legendary actions?
c04586
Seeker: I think I burned mine all since my last turn, yeah.
c04587
DM: Oh, okay.
c04588
Wellby: Yeah, you used all your
c04589
DM: So you need to wait till your turn.
c04590
Unknown: I just went with the move, so
c04591
Wellby: You used your...
c04592
DM: Okay, so now it's Kenzo's turn.
c04593
Kenzo: All right, Kenzo will, uh, move.
c04594
Kenzo: Uh, I, I've got 70 move, so I can easily get over here 'cause I'm gonna get into the action over on this side.
c04595
Unknown: Uh-huh.
c04596
Kenzo: And then, yeah, I'm, I'm gonna try to, uh, break, snap the tendril.
c04597
Kenzo: All right.
c04598
Kenzo: And now I get, uh, two staff attacks.
c04599
Kenzo: Is this advantage now or no? Just normal attacks?
c04600
DM: Until Wellby's turn-
c04601
Unknown: Let me check
c04602
DM: ... advantage... till Wellby's turn, so advantage
c04603
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Okay, great. So this is my first staff attack.
c04604
Kenzo: Uh, that hits and that, the...
c04605
Kenzo: well, actually, let me, let me roll the two staff attacks.
c04606
Kenzo: [dice rolling] Uh, okay, definitely they both hit and then I do...
c04607
Unknown: 3d 12 plus...
c04608
DM: Plus 12
c04609
Kenzo: ... d t- no, plus 2d6.
c04610
DM: Oh, the d6.
c04611
DM: No, the d6 is only for your punches, not your staff.
c04612
Kenzo: No, no, no, it's for any melee attacks.
c04613
DM: Oh, okay.
c04614
Kenzo: Yeah. Uh, so it's this plus
c04615
Unknown: 16,
c04616
Delwath: Right? Or 18. 18.
c04617
Kenzo: Hold on. That's the wrong number still, which I started.
c04618
DM: It's some... It's 19 I think.
c04619
DM: No, it has to be an even number.
c04620
Kenzo: Okay. Yeah, 18, plus 18.
c04621
Delwath: That was 'cause I thought last turn was 18.
c04622
DM: 18.
c04623
Kenzo: These are just the staff attacks.
c04624
Unknown: Yep.
c04625
Kenzo: So is this...
c04626
Kenzo: Ooh, this is good.
c04627
Delwath: That's a good roll.
c04628
Kenzo: Oh, this is very good.
c04629
Unknown: Wow.
c04630
Kenzo: Uh, 22, 32, 37 plus 18 is 47, 55.
c04631
DM: So as Kenzo-
c04632
Unknown: 55
c04633
DM: ... swings down with the staff like three, twice, like hammering on the pseudopod, like part of its,
c04634
DM: part of its-
c04635
Wellby: Does it break off a piece of this?
c04636
DM: No, no. Part of its body-
c04637
Unknown: Oh, no
c04638
Unknown: ... flows out from here-
c04639
Delwath: What? It's reinforcing
c04640
DM: ... and reinforces.
c04641
Unknown: Oh.
c04642
Delwath: Yeah, that's a cool mechanic.
c04643
Seeker: That's awesome. It's like rebuilding itself.
c04644
Unknown: Uh-oh.
c04645
Delwath: It can flow hit points from itself to the pseudopod.
c04646
Unknown: Oh, boy. Okay.
c04647
Delwath: This thing probably has 1,000 hit points.
c04648
Kenzo: Oh, boy. Fun, fun, fun. All right, so I'm gonna do-
c04649
Delwath: Hold on, how much damage did you do?
c04650
Unknown: 55.
c04651
Kenzo: Um, now I'm gonna do my three punch attacks.
c04652
DM: Yeah.
c04653
Kenzo: So, uh, first attack, that definitely hits.
c04654
Kenzo: Second attack, ooh, natural 20.
c04655
DM: Nat 20.
c04656
Kenzo: And then third attack,
c04657
Kenzo: That still hits.
c04658
Kenzo: 20, 21, 21.
c04659
DM: 21 hits, yep.
c04660
Kenzo: Yeah. Okay, that, that still hits. All right. So now I do...
c04661
Unknown: How much do-
c04662
Delwath: You do 4-
c04663
Unknown: Natural
c04664
DM: ... 40 12 plus 46 'cause they all hit.
c04665
Unknown: Yes.
c04666
Delwath: 40 12 plus 46.
c04667
Unknown: Plus 46.
c04668
DM: You get an extra d12 and an extra d6.
c04669
Delwath: Plus, um, and you do plus 7 instead of plus 9, right?
c04670
Kenzo: Correct. Plus 7 times 2.
c04671
Unknown: So plus 21.
c04672
Unknown: Plus 21.
c04673
Delwath: So 4d 12 plus 4d 6 plus 21.
c04674
DM: Holy shit.
c04675
Kenzo: Doing a lot of damage now.
c04676
DM: Yeah.
c04677
Kenzo: Double 20s is pretty sweet.
c04678
Wellby: 46.
c04679
Delwath: Nah, you need one more d12.
c04680
Unknown: Here.
c04681
Kenzo: 46 plus 4d 12 plus what?
c04682
Unknown: 21.
c04683
Kenzo: Plus 21.
c04684
Unknown: Ooh.
c04685
Unknown: Yeah, plus 21. Cool.
c04686
Delwath: Man, you're doing good on the damage rolls today.
c04687
Kenzo: I'm getting all the 20s.
c04688
Unknown: 15, 20,
c04689
Kenzo: uh, 30, 40.
c04690
Unknown: 40.
c04691
Unknown: Holy fuck.
c04692
DM: And move some stone back.
c04693
Kenzo: 40... Uh, what the fuck is this?
c04694
Unknown: Hardening.
c04695
Unknown: That's, um, 6 plus-
c04696
Kenzo: 50, 54
c04697
Kenzo: ... 54 plus-
c04698
Delwath: Plus 21. 60,
c04699
Unknown: 75.
c04700
DM: Wow.
c04701
Unknown: Holy shit.
c04702
Kenzo: Holy shit, that's the most damage I've ever done in a turn.
c04703
DM: So a-
c04704
Unknown: Damn.
c04705
DM: Sorry. Okay. After Kenzo...
c04706
Unknown: Holy shit
c04707
Unknown: Uh...
c04708
Kenzo: Ad- Advantage Kenzo at 20 level monk is pretty nasty.
c04709
Unknown: Holy shit.
c04710
DM: So after Kenzo-
c04711
Unknown: I'm doing a ton of damage
c04712
DM: ... punches, a bunch of the stone
c04713
DM: in its body
c04714
DM: goes back and you find...
c04715
DM: and it's forming a s- like a stone barrier along this pseudopod.
c04716
Delwath: I'm gonna use a legendary action to...
c04717
Delwath: Another fist of water appears and slams into it, like right...
c04718
Delwath: 13. That'll hit. 25.
c04719
DM: Okay. Is this bludgeoning damage?
c04720
Unknown: Yeah.
c04721
Unknown: Oh, is it resistant to bludgeoning damage now?
c04722
Seeker: Is this the kind of thing where the more damage we do to this thing, the stronger it gets?
c04723
Kenzo: I don't think so.
c04724
Unknown: 13.
c04725
DM: Um, the fist of water-
c04726
Kenzo: And if that was the case, I don't know if there's a way to, like-
c04727
DM: ... hits into the stone-
c04728
Unknown: ... do the opposite of that
c04729
DM: ... and the energy is partially dissipated-
c04730
DM: We, uh, damage ourselves
c04731
DM: ... along the line of the pseudopod. Sorry, how much was that?
c04732
Unknown: Heal damage or something.
c04733
Unknown: 13.
c04734
DM: So like a half.
c04735
Wellby: Like a desecrate spell or something like that.
c04736
Unknown: Okay, 6. [dice rolling]
c04737
Kenzo: Guys, I did 120 damage on like a regular attack.
c04738
Delwath: Ha. That, uh, if it gains resistance to bludgeoning damage, that it's now like gonna be hard for us to actually hurt it.
c04739
Unknown: Yeah.
c04740
Kenzo: Is it resistant to bludgeoning?
c04741
DM: Yeah.
c04742
DM: It's reinforced the pseudopod with-
c04743
Unknown: It's reinforced
c04744
DM: ... see all the stone?
c04745
Delwath: But you, you also do... Oh, no, you can do force damage.
c04746
Wellby: Why don't we just go further down?
c04747
Unknown: I can do force damage.
c04748
Wellby: I mean, if the pseudopod goes all the way back to the main square, why don't we just go down another
c04749
Wellby: 50 feet?
c04750
Delwath: And it's probably reinforcing the whole...
c04751
DM: Uh, yeah, the stone is filling out as far as you can see.
c04752
Unknown: Is it, is that the idea?
c04753
DM: But it's only 30 feet.
c04754
Unknown: Sure.
c04755
DM: Um, sorry, I'm losing track.
c04756
Unknown: Yeah.
c04757
DM: That was...
c04758
DM: uh, it wants to do a legendary action.
c04759
DM: Wait, did you already do a legendary action?
c04760
Delwath: That damage was just my legendary action.
c04761
DM: Okay, well, that's fine. It's gonna do a legendary now before Seeker does a legendary action.
c04762
DM: Um-
c04763
Delwath: [laughs] This is a little ridiculous.
c04764
DM: It is. Uh, and- Man, immune to acid is really tough for it to do much against.
c04765
Unknown: That's why the devil-
c04766
DM: Oh, wait. Are you immune to poison?
c04767
Unknown: Yep.
c04768
DM: Oh, wait. You are immune to poison.
c04769
Unknown: Yeah.
c04770
Unknown: God damn it. Okay. [laughs]
c04771
Unknown: It can't really hurt us.
c04772
Kenzo: [laughs] Well- Outwitting the DM
c04773
Wellby: ... th- th- there's 25% of us.
c04774
Unknown: [laughs]
c04775
Delwath: Can't really hurt half of us.
c04776
Delwath: But this is really good for Seeker 'cause you can just cast your spells.
c04777
DM: Yeah.
c04778
Delwath: But actually,
c04779
Delwath: my attacks are getting less and less effective, 'cause it's all blun- it's all damage it's also resistant to.
c04780
Unknown: Mm.
c04781
Delwath: So we're like two giants trading ineffective hits against each other.
c04782
Unknown: Yeah.
c04783
DM: Which is not-
c04784
Kenzo: I mean, not bad. I mean, I'm kind of okay with it
c04785
Delwath: If I could get it to attack me, that would be great.
c04786
Kenzo: That would be great.
c04787
DM: [sighs] Kenzo is the l- Kenzo just did a ton of damage along this pseudopod.
c04788
DM: So Kenzo, make a dexterity saving throw,
c04789
DM: as more of this acid net flies out towards you.
c04790
Unknown: Uh-oh.
c04791
DM: You-
c04792
Kenzo: Uh, I, I spent a ki earlier
c04793
DM: ... that fails. Okay.
c04794
Unknown: Oh.
c04795
Unknown: Oh my gosh.
c04796
DM: [coughs] So you are now...
c04797
DM: You take-
c04798
Unknown: 16.
c04799
DM: Yeah, that fails.
c04800
Unknown: Okay.
c04801
DM: You take, um,
c04802
DM: 44 reduced by...
c04803
DM: Oh, double reduced, because-
c04804
Unknown: Yeah
c04805
DM: ... you're-
c04806
Kenzo: Both immune and resistant
c04807
DM: ... right. So you take-
c04808
Unknown: 11
c04809
DM: ... 11 points of
c04810
DM: damage, but you are now also restrained.
c04811
Unknown: Ah.
c04812
Kenzo: So annoying.
c04813
DM: B- same as Wellby. So speed is zero, attacks against you have advantage.
c04814
DM: Um, your attacks have disadvantage.
c04815
DM: At the end of your turn, you can make another save to escape.
c04816
Kenzo: Dude, how did I fail two fucking dex saves?
c04817
DM: That's... It's legendary.
c04818
Seeker: Are you fucking serious?
c04819
DM: Okay, Wellby's turn. Uh, unless Seeker wants to...
c04820
DM: Oh, no, Seeker's out of legendaries till his turn.
c04821
Unknown: That's right.
c04822
DM: So Wellby's up.
c04823
Unknown: Ugh.
c04824
DM: So your attacks have disadvantage until, uh...
c04825
DM: Oh, well, advantage.
c04826
Unknown: Advantage.
c04827
DM: So it cancels out, so straight one.
c04828
Wellby: Sure. Well, do I still get sneak attack because there's an ally within 5?
c04829
DM: Yes. Yeah.
c04830
Unknown: Okay.
c04831
DM: Are you aiming for the main body or the tail?
c04832
Wellby: Uh, tail is not yet resistant to piercing damage.
c04833
DM: No.
c04834
Unknown: Okay.
c04835
DM: You think it's only resistant to bludgeoning.
c04836
DM: It probably can't be resistant to multiple things at once.
c04837
Wellby: Uh, is it the same day as it was yesterday, or is this...
c04838
Wellby: Do we long... We long rested.
c04839
DM: Yeah.
c04840
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah.
c04841
Wellby: I'll use the clockwork amulet to roll a 24.
c04842
DM: That hits.
c04843
Wellby: And I will get some more dice.
c04844
Delwath: Um, is Delwath next?
c04845
Unknown: No, Seeker's next.
c04846
DM: Seeker's next, then Delwath.
c04847
Unknown: All right.
c04848
Unknown: Five, uh,
c04849
Wellby: 22, 25, 30-
c04850
DM: Sorry, you are a- you are shooting at the t- at the pseudopod
c04851
Wellby: ... 35. Yep. Uh, 39 plus 8 is 47.
c04852
DM: Nice.
c04853
Wellby: Can I get more bardic inspiration?
c04854
Wellby: Is that a... That's not a thing you can do in this form?
c04855
DM: Not as a leviathan, you can't.
c04856
DM: Uh-
c04857
Wellby: Uh, and then save to escape grapple?
c04858
DM: Yeah.
c04859
Unknown: Great.
c04860
DM: Dex save to escape the restraints.
c04861
Unknown: Okay.
c04862
Kenzo: You can only do it at the end of the turn.
c04863
DM: End of your turn. Yeah.
c04864
Unknown: Dex save?
c04865
DM: Dex save.
c04866
Unknown: Yeah.
c04867
DM: Seeker, you're up.
c04868
Wellby: Restrain... Yeah. That's weird that restrain is...
c04869
Wellby: No, it's not weird. Uh.
c04870
Seeker: I'm thinking about just psychic disruption again.
c04871
Wellby: 15 probably doesn't do it.
c04872
DM: Nope.
c04873
Wellby: Should I use my heroic?
c04874
Kenzo: Probably, man. You want to get the fuck out of this shit.
c04875
DM: Yeah.
c04876
Wellby: Yeah, 'cause it can keep hitting me.
c04877
Kenzo: This is like one of those, like, I feel like saves are just important to spend, you know, if you can get out of them.
c04878
Wellby: Mm-hmm. Uh, 20?
c04879
DM: Nope.
c04880
Unknown: What?
c04881
Wellby: Oh, no. [laughs]
c04882
DM: Hey, their DC is 24.
c04883
DM: Why should its be any le- worse?
c04884
Wellby: Oh.
c04885
DM: That's rough.
c04886
Wellby: Uh, uh, because I rolled poorly, is the answer.
c04887
DM: Yeah, yeah. [laughs]
c04888
Unknown: [laughs]
c04889
Wellby: Damn.
c04890
Kenzo: It is very annoying.
c04891
DM: Um, but as your arrow strikes, um, the...
c04892
DM: Well, actually, wait.
c04893
DM: Uh, that was at the end of your turn, so now it's gonna use its legendary.
c04894
DM: Um-
c04895
Wellby: Will you release me from the restraints?
c04896
DM: Nope. To attack you.
c04897
Wellby: Oh, neat.
c04898
DM: You, you're noticing a pattern.
c04899
Wellby: Oh. Oh.
c04900
DM: ... it basically is just attacking whoever was the last one to do damage to its tail.
c04901
Wellby: Hold up. I'm gonna use my bonus action to get my second wind.
c04902
DM: Oh.
c04903
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c04904
Wellby: And regain three hit points.
c04905
Wellby: [laughs]
c04906
DM: [laughs]
c04907
Delwath: That's still more than zero hit points.
c04908
Wellby: That's right.
c04909
DM: So it has advantage on you.
c04910
DM: Um,
c04911
DM: two natural ones.
c04912
Unknown: Wow.
c04913
c04914
DM: So with your second wind-
c04915
Unknown: [laughs]
c04916
DM: ... you dodge out of the way.
c04917
DM: That's its legendary. Anybody else want to do legendaries?
c04918
Unknown: I'm out.
c04919
DM: Same. Okay. So-
c04920
Seeker: 'Cause it's about to be my turn
c04921
DM: ... so Seeker's up.
c04922
Seeker: I will try again another psychic disruption, this time at sixth level.
c04923
Unknown: Um,
c04924
Seeker: it's like, uh, DC 19 and save.
c04925
DM: Uh, okay.
c04926
DM: Whoops.
c04927
DM: Um,
c04928
DM: it's gonna burn a legendary resistance.
c04929
Unknown: All right.
c04930
DM: And it hardens slightly, reducing its speed
c04931
DM: as it uses its legendary resistance, which seems like it may have no effect because everybody's crowded around it.
c04932
DM: Um-
c04933
Seeker: So I'll roll the 9d6 and we'll take half?
c04934
DM: Uh, yep.
c04935
Unknown: So that's-
c04936
DM: That's its first legendary that it's burned
c04937
Seeker: ... 23 over two is
c04938
Unknown: 11.
c04939
Unknown: Yeah.
c04940
DM: Okay. And that's on the...
c04941
DM: That was your turn.
c04942
Unknown: Um, I c- I guess I could also move if I wanted to, but-
c04943
Unknown: I'm not sure the point.
c04944
DM: Yeah. Right. Okay.
c04945
Unknown: Can you cast spells?
c04946
Unknown: Yeah.
c04947
DM: Seeker can cast spells as a leviathan.
c04948
Unknown: Yeah.
c04949
DM: Delwath can't.
c04950
Unknown: 'Cause it's a shape changed version of a leviathan.
c04951
DM: Um,
c04952
DM: okay. Now it's gonna use, uh...
c04953
DM: It used, it's used two legendaries.
c04954
DM: It's actually gonna use its last legendary-
c04955
Kenzo: To attack Seeker
c04956
DM: No, 'cause it doesn't really recognize that spells are attacks.
c04957
Unknown: No.
c04958
DM: It can't tell where the spell comes from.
c04959
Unknown: Is it gonna go for Wellby again?
c04960
DM: Yeah, 'cause Wellby's the last one that damaged it.
c04961
Kenzo: Damn it.
c04962
Wellby: Yeah, but I got those big three HP.
c04963
Kenzo: Ah, you did get that, that, that, that big three.
c04964
DM: Right?
c04965
Seeker: What's your total HP?
c04966
Wellby: I'm on 86 right now.
c04967
Unknown: Oh, you're fine.
c04968
DM: Well, that was a one.
c04969
DM: [dice clatter] Uh, that was a 20, a 15, so it's...
c04970
DM: Sorry, an 8 plus 15 is 23.
c04971
Wellby: That's a hit.
c04972
DM: Okay. So
c04973
DM: that's gonna do
c04974
Unknown: Hit there
c04975
DM: 20 bludgeoning plus five acid, so 25 total.
c04976
Wellby: Whoa. Awesome.
c04977
Wellby: Yep. Good.
c04978
DM: That's its legendary. Seeker's turn is over.
c04979
DM: Delwath is up.
c04980
Seeker: Okay. Oh, I can do my legendary.
c04981
DM: After my... After Delwath.
c04982
Delwath: Delwath is gonna, like-
c04983
DM: You can't do legends after your own turn after, only after somebody else's turn.
c04984
Seeker: But wasn't it just its turn?
c04985
DM: No, no.
c04986
DM: It was, it was its legendary.
c04987
DM: You were its legendary. [laughs]
c04988
Unknown: Oh. [laughs]
c04989
Unknown: You were its legendary.
c04990
Unknown: Thank you. Great.
c04991
DM: You are its legendary. [laughs]
c04992
Delwath: Right. Delwath will, like-
c04993
Unknown: So it's just legendary attacks all the way
c04994
Delwath: ... will, like, roar at it in anger-
c04995
Unknown: Yeah
c04996
Delwath: ... like, like, you know, "You're a terrible thing," like, and form a sort of whirlwind of, um, of water that swirls around and just slams into it twice.
c04997
DM: The tail or the main body?
c04998
Delwath: The tail.
c04999
DM: Okay.
c05000
DM: But misses the first time.
c05001
DM: That misses. [dice clatter]
c05002
Delwath: Uh, does 21 hit?
c05003
DM: 21 hits, yep.
c05004
Delwath: Hits the second time.
c05005
Delwath: Uh, so hits with the tail, which is less good but...
c05006
Delwath: oh my God.
c05007
DM: [scoffs]
c05008
Delwath: For, for 11 points of bludgeoning damage.
c05009
Seeker: We're doing peanuts for damage right now.
c05010
DM: Okay.
c05011
Seeker: We need Kenzo to hit again.
c05012
Seeker: [laughs] Or 10 times that.
c05013
DM: Um, 11. Okay, so-
c05014
Unknown: Six, five.
c05015
DM: Yeah.
c05016
DM: Six. I forget if you round up or down.
c05017
DM: You round down.
c05018
Kenzo: I'm doing a lot of damage.
c05019
DM: Um, the... Even so, with that hit, even though it was weak, you can see cracks starting to form in the tail.
c05020
Seeker: All right.
c05021
DM: Uh, that's gonna be its turn.
c05022
DM: It now turns in anger at Delwath.
c05023
Unknown: Yay.
c05024
Unknown: [laughs]
c05025
DM: Oh, nice one.
c05026
Unknown: Finally.
c05027
DM: That was the goal.
c05028
Kenzo: Finally. Geez.
c05029
DM: And it's going to make, uh,
c05030
DM: three pseudo pod attacks.
c05031
Kenzo: Yep. Let's go.
c05032
DM: Uh, a one.
c05033
Unknown: Okay.
c05034
DM: The first one misses as it's-
c05035
Kenzo: Oh, that's only a one
c05036
DM: ... distracted by-
c05037
Kenzo: That means they roll this
c05038
DM: ... the second one is a 30 something.
c05039
Delwath: Yeah, AC is only 17.
c05040
DM: And the third is a 21.
c05041
Unknown: Okay.
c05042
DM: So two hit.
c05043
Unknown: Okay.
c05044
DM: You're immune to acid?
c05045
Delwath: Yep, immune to acid, immune to poison, resistance to bludgeoning, piercing and slashing.
c05046
DM: Uh, okay. So you take 20,
c05047
DM: 35 reduced by half.
c05048
Delwath: That's two hits.
c05049
DM: That's two hits.
c05050
Delwath: Yeah. I do have to make con saves.
c05051
DM: Yeah.
c05052
Delwath: I mean, I have to make...
c05053
Delwath: So 35 reduced by 12.
c05054
Unknown: Well done.
c05055
DM: Sorry, that was... That's,
c05056
Unknown: that was the fir- that was the first hit, 35.
c05057
Delwath: The first hit was 35?
c05058
DM: 35 reduced by two.
c05059
Unknown: Okay. So what is that?
c05060
Unknown: 15-
c05061
Seeker: Oh, so we should be adding the temporary hit points of 328.
c05062
DM: Um, the second hit is 27.
c05063
DM: [dice clatter]
c05064
Delwath: 15, that's okay.
c05065
DM: Yep.
c05066
Delwath: And the second hit is 27-
c05067
DM: 27, so it's 13
c05068
Unknown: ... so 13.
c05069
Seeker: So I have over 500 total now.
c05070
Unknown: Yeah.
c05071
DM: Yeah. [dice clatter] [laughs]
c05072
Unknown: That's okay.
c05073
DM: That's okay.
c05074
Kenzo: It's just, like, massive, like, hit point...
c05075
DM: Um, and then it is going to, uh,
c05076
DM: shoot another
c05077
DM: w- a line of acid can actually hit all four of you right now.
c05078
DM: So a line of acid is gonna erupt from right here and just fly out, like [gurgling] in a straight line hitting all four of you.
c05079
DM: Everybody has to make a dex saving throw, Wellby and Kenzo with disadvantage.
c05080
DM: Wait, did you s- you didn't succeed, did you?
c05081
Wellby: No, I did not.
c05082
DM: Okay, so Wellby and Kenzo with disadvantage.
c05083
Delwath: Do I have to... Is this... Does that erase it?
c05084
DM: No. It's also immune to restraint.
c05085
Kenzo: I'm also immune to restraint.
c05086
DM: [laughs]
c05087
Unknown: 19?
c05088
DM: What?
c05089
Unknown: 19?
c05090
DM: 19 fails.
c05091
Unknown: 18.
c05092
DM: Fails.
c05093
Unknown: Fails.
c05094
Delwath: Is that the end of its turn?
c05095
DM: That's the end of its turn.
c05096
Unknown: Wait, do I, do I have to roll? No.
c05097
DM: No, 'cause it's acid damage.
c05098
DM: [laughs] You're immune to acid damage.
c05099
Unknown: Acid and restraint. You're immune to acid and restraint.
c05100
DM: So you two both take 33 points of acid damage.
c05101
Kenzo: Yeah, but also I'm resistant to it.
c05102
DM: Oh, you take half of that.
c05103
DM: So you take 16 points of acid damage.
c05104
Unknown: I will punch it again as a legendary.
c05105
Wellby: Uh, 33 is the half already?
c05106
DM: Yeah.
c05107
Unknown: Okay.
c05108
Seeker: Well, I'm also gonna do my legendary.
c05109
DM: Okay, so that's the end of the...
c05110
Unknown: Um, so-
c05111
DM: Okay
c05112
Delwath: ... 23 hits, right?
c05113
Wellby: [laughs] I'm at 28 hit points.
c05114
Delwath: I'm trying here.
c05115
Delwath: Uh, 23 hits?
c05116
DM: 23 hits, yep.
c05117
Unknown: 2D12.
c05118
Delwath: That's better. 15, uh, plus 8, so 23.
c05119
Unknown: And then-
c05120
DM: Okay
c05121
Seeker: ... in my slam attack.
c05122
Unknown: [dice clatter] What is this?
c05123
Unknown: 20.
c05124
Seeker: ... 20. Misses.
c05125
DM: Uh, 20 mi- t- uh, 20 misses.
c05126
DM: No, 20 just hits.
c05127
Unknown: Okay. I thought it was a miss.
c05128
DM: Uh, 20 hits. You, nobody's rolled a 20 yet.
c05129
Unknown: Right.
c05130
DM: You've only rolled a 19.
c05131
Delwath: 2D12 plus 8 bludgeoning.
c05132
Delwath: Uh, 13 plus 8, 21.
c05133
DM: So 21, and what was yours?
c05134
DM: I didn't write it down. I'm sorry.
c05135
Unknown: It was also 21.
c05136
DM: Okay. So,
c05137
DM: um, more cracks begin to run along this, this tendril.
c05138
DM: [dice clatter]
c05139
Delwath: Wait, uh, y- you know, you should bonus action Healing Word on your next turn.
c05140
Wellby: That would be great.
c05141
DM: So Kenzo's up.
c05142
Delwath: You only got it on your last turn.
c05143
Delwath: Oh, you can't cast two level spells.
c05144
Kenzo: What's my deal again now? 'Cause I'm restrained.
c05145
DM: So disadvantage on all attacks.
c05146
Unknown: Fuck.
c05147
DM: Your move is zero.
c05148
Kenzo: That's fine. And then I can try to-
c05149
DM: At the end of your turn, you get another dex save to escape.
c05150
Seeker: That would be great. Hang on. All right.
c05151
DM: And remember, it attacks whoever attacked it last.
c05152
Kenzo: That's fine. I want it to attack me.
c05153
DM: Okay.
c05154
Seeker: All right. Uh, so just initiative-
c05155
Delwath: Wait, where is it? I-
c05156
DM: Losing track of the initiative order
c05157
DM: Kenzo, Wellby, Seeker, Delwath, then it.
c05158
DM: It's first.
c05159
Kenzo: Oh man, I rolled a 20 and a 2, so that misses, right?
c05160
DM: That misses, yeah.
c05161
Kenzo: 17 misses. [dice clatter] Fuck, I rolled a 1.
c05162
DM: Misses.
c05163
Unknown: Damn it.
c05164
DM: Your... As you try and get it with your staff, the, like, acid net around you is holding you back.
c05165
Kenzo: First arm strike.
c05166
Unknown: Uh-
c05167
Delwath: It's at 20 AC. You don't have a plus 16, do you?
c05168
Kenzo: I do not. Fuck.
c05169
DM: That misses.
c05170
Kenzo: Disadvantage sucks.
c05171
Unknown: It does.
c05172
Unknown: Man.
c05173
Unknown: All right, that hits.
c05174
DM: That hits.
c05175
Unknown: All right.
c05176
DM: You're right, you gotta beat these saves.
c05177
Kenzo: Hold on, that... Hold on. And then the last one, um, [dice clatter] that also hits.
c05178
Kenzo: All right, so two hit.
c05179
DM: Yeah.
c05180
Unknown: So I do-
c05181
DM: So 2D12 plus 2D6.
c05182
Kenzo: No, uh, 3D12.
c05183
DM: No, the, you have-
c05184
Kenzo: I, I get to spend an extra D12 on any of them.
c05185
DM: He gets an extra D12 on any-
c05186
Unknown: Oh
c05187
DM: ... first attack that hits.
c05188
Kenzo: Right. Right, right, right. 3D12, 2D6 plus 10.
c05189
DM: And this is force damage?
c05190
Kenzo: Force damage, yeah.
c05191
DM: Okay.
c05192
Kenzo: I can, I can make it force damage.
c05193
DM: And there's no way it can be resistant to force damage.
c05194
Kenzo: Oh, pl- uh, plus 14.
c05195
DM: Okay.
c05196
Unknown: Plus 14.
c05197
Unknown: [dice clatter] Oh, that's good.
c05198
Kenzo: 22, 25,
c05199
Kenzo: 29 plus 14.
c05200
DM: Kenzo's really, like...
c05201
DM: How much?
c05202
Kenzo: Uh.
c05203
Unknown: 29 plus 14.
c05204
Unknown: 43.
c05205
DM: And that's all force?
c05206
Kenzo: Yep, all force. Yeah.
c05207
Kenzo: That's only with two hits.
c05208
DM: Like, four big cracks spread along
c05209
DM: this
c05210
DM: tendril here.
c05211
DM: It's not, it's not quite, you know,
c05212
DM: broken but...
c05213
DM: It's still resistant to bludgeoning.
c05214
DM: [dice clatter]
c05215
Unknown: [laughs]
c05216
DM: That, uh... So make your dex save to try and break free.
c05217
Unknown: Bitch.
c05218
Unknown: Ah.
c05219
DM: Nope.
c05220
Kenzo: It's finicky.
c05221
Unknown: Reroll.
c05222
DM: Okay.
c05223
Kenzo: Thank you. That's gotta, that's gotta work.
c05224
Unknown: 25.
c05225
DM: That works. [dice clatter] It is still gonna attack you though, without advantage this time, with its legendary at the end of your turn.
c05226
DM: That, [sighs] that's a one.
c05227
Delwath: The big giant monsters are really rolling poorly.
c05228
DM: I know. [laughs]
c05229
Unknown: [laughs]
c05230
DM: Ken's, Ken's-
c05231
Delwath: All of, all of us, yeah
c05232
DM: So it is Wellby's turn.
c05233
Unknown: [sighs]
c05234
Unknown: Ugh.
c05235
DM: Or unless anybody wants legendaries.
c05236
Delwath: I used them up. Well, I can move.
c05237
Unknown: I-
c05238
Wellby: I'm, I'm done too.
c05239
Delwath: Okay. 'Cause the slam is two legendaries.
c05240
DM: I see.
c05241
Delwath: So we can only do one slam.
c05242
DM: One slam per.
c05243
Delwath: And there's not really a point in moving.
c05244
DM: Right.
c05245
Wellby: I can probably survive one more hit.
c05246
Wellby: Uh, I will shoot its-
c05247
DM: Have you been rolling to see if your tidal wave recharges on your turns?
c05248
Delwath: Oh, I'd forgotten. I don't...
c05249
Unknown: Actually,
c05250
Unknown: no.
c05251
Delwath: Roll a D6 to see if your tidal wave...
c05252
Unknown: Well, you haven't used it yet.
c05253
Unknown: Right.
c05254
DM: Yeah.
c05255
Wellby: Is this one of three of these we have to beat, or is this the one we have to beat?
c05256
DM: We don't know.
c05257
Kenzo: I think this is one of three. Well, for sure we're gonna have to fight something in the well.
c05258
Kenzo: This is, this is... We may be able to avoid the other one, but...
c05259
Kenzo: This is the small one. Yeah, yeah.
c05260
DM: [laughs]
c05261
Wellby: Uh, okay. Well, I will shoot it then.
c05262
Wellby: Um, that's a
c05263
Wellby: 23 or something like that.
c05264
DM: Yes. Yeah, it is a 20, I see.
c05265
Unknown: 4,
c05266
Unknown: 8,
c05267
Unknown: 9.
c05268
Delwath: It's, it's next, right?
c05269
Unknown: Uh...
c05270
Wellby: Doesn't really the D6 go here?
c05271
DM: No. Seeker and Delwath are next.
c05272
Unknown: Oh, we're next.
c05273
DM: It's Wellby's turn. It is very difficult to keep track of the turn order-
c05274
Unknown: I know
c05275
Wellby: ... with this many [laughs] legendary actions.
c05276
Wellby: 10, 15, 22, 31 damage and then I will bonus action drink my last potion of
c05277
Wellby: s- a small amount of heal- of greater healing.
c05278
Unknown: 2d4s.
c05279
Wellby: Yep.
c05280
DM: Uh, that ends your turn?
c05281
Unknown: Yep.
c05282
DM: Okay.
c05283
Wellby: Is that that... Oh, and I roll, uh...
c05284
DM: To escape.
c05285
Wellby: Nope.
c05286
DM: It's going to attack you
c05287
DM: with its legendary action.
c05288
DM: Uh, that's a...
c05289
DM: That hits.
c05290
Wellby: Awesome. Oops.
c05291
DM: So you take 18 bludgeoning plus 8 acid.
c05292
Delwath: Can't you uncanny dodge that?
c05293
Wellby: No, 'cause I'm restrained.
c05294
DM: Oh.
c05295
Wellby: I assume I can't uncanny dodge when I'm restrained.
c05296
DM: Uh...
c05297
Wellby: Unless I can.
c05298
DM: I think... I mean, yeah, you...
c05299
DM: There's nothing that says... You just have, you have disadvantage on dex saving throws.
c05300
Delwath: Unless uncanny dodge requires you to have speed.
c05301
DM: I don't think uncann- Does uncanny dodge say you can't use it if your speed is zero?
c05302
Unknown: Let me look.
c05303
DM: I know that Ken's, the, the dodge action is you can't use it if your speed is zero.
c05304
Unknown: [laughs] Uncanny dodge.
c05305
Unknown: [laughs]
c05306
Kenzo: Dude, Kenzo's really unkillable.
c05307
Unknown: Yeah.
c05308
Kenzo: I also have, like, my, my, my, uh-
c05309
DM: Okay. So yeah, you can use that.
c05310
Wellby: All right. So that's n- uh, what is the total damage?
c05311
DM: The... It was 18 and 6, so 20...
c05312
Unknown: 24.
c05313
Unknown: So 12.
c05314
DM: 24, so 12. [pen clatter] Uh, that's its le- [laughs] legendary action.
c05315
DM: You're still restrained.
c05316
DM: You should actually be rolling all these...
c05317
DM: I forgot 'cause you're restrained, you have disadvantage on dex, so you should be rolling the saves to escape with disadvantage.
c05318
Unknown: Oh, that's rough.
c05319
Wellby: Really?
c05320
DM: Yeah.
c05321
Kenzo: Did I have disadvantage to escape?
c05322
DM: Yeah.
c05323
DM: It's pretty nasty to be restrained because...
c05324
DM: I mean, you might have ways to get out of...
c05325
DM: I mean,
c05326
DM: Delwath has, like, 10 ways to get out of restraints.
c05327
Wellby: Yeah, all sorts of magical ways.
c05328
Delwath: But also is currently, uh, in water element form.
c05329
Unknown: And immune to restraints [laughs].
c05330
DM: And immune to restraint.
c05331
Wellby: Uh, it doesn't really matter 'cause I've failed them all.
c05332
DM: Yeah, exactly. It's Seeker's turn.
c05333
DM: Uh...
c05334
Delwath: You might just Leviathan smash it and heal Wellby.
c05335
DM: Oh.
c05336
Wellby: Sure.
c05337
Unknown: That's a good idea.
c05338
DM: Of course.
c05339
Kenzo: That very first save. [laughs]
c05340
DM: As Kong said... [laughs]
c05341
Unknown: [laughs]
c05342
DM: [laughs] It's true.
c05343
Kenzo: Yeah. You're like, "Well, just, just see what happens."
c05344
Unknown: [laughs]
c05345
Wellby: I assumed it was just damage.
c05346
Unknown: [laughs]
c05347
Unknown: Yeah.
c05348
Unknown: [laughs]
c05349
Seeker: Um, I cast a healing word at
c05350
Seeker: fifth level.
c05351
DM: So that's 1d-
c05352
Kenzo: It's so crazy how, like, like, saving throws are just, like, the most important thing actually.
c05353
DM: Yes.
c05354
Seeker: 10d4 plus 5.
c05355
Delwath: Just roll that on there.
c05356
Unknown: Um...
c05357
Kenzo: 10d4 plus 5.
c05358
Kenzo: Oh, that's a lot of d4s.
c05359
DM: Yeah.
c05360
Seeker: Uh, it's 29.
c05361
Unknown: Nice.
c05362
Unknown: Awesome.
c05363
Unknown: Yeah.
c05364
Wellby: That more than doubles my hit points.
c05365
Seeker: Amazing. And then, uh-
c05366
Delwath: I mean, you can take your full attacks.
c05367
Delwath: You can attack twice if you-
c05368
Seeker: So, like, the multi-attack is a slam and a tail?
c05369
Delwath: A slam and a tail, yeah.
c05370
Unknown: Yeah, they're both plus 14 to hit.
c05371
Delwath: Both plus 14. One gets slightly discounted.
c05372
DM: Uh, main body or tail? The tail has, like, four large cracks in it.
c05373
Unknown: Tail.
c05374
DM: Tail.
c05375
Unknown: Tail.
c05376
DM: Okay.
c05377
Kenzo: Oh, nice.
c05378
DM: Okay.
c05379
Seeker: 18 and an 18.
c05380
DM: Okay.
c05381
Delwath: So 32 and 33.
c05382
Delwath: 2d10, 2d10 plus 2d12.
c05383
Unknown: [coughs]
c05384
DM: Plus 16.
c05385
Kenzo: Nice. We love this.
c05386
Seeker: Now we're talk- now we're talking, Levi.
c05387
Unknown: Love this.
c05388
Unknown: Oh, wow. Not a good roll.
c05389
DM: Oh my God.
c05390
Seeker: Oh, kind of good. You know what I'm saying?
c05391
Seeker: 14 plus 7 is 21 plus...
c05392
Delwath: Plus 16.
c05393
DM: Is 37.
c05394
Unknown: 37.
c05395
Unknown: Nice. Nice roll.
c05396
Delwath: 37 bludgeoning from two big fists.
c05397
Unknown: Okay.
c05398
DM: A fist and a tail.
c05399
Delwath: A fist and a tail.
c05400
Delwath: Oh, Delwath's tidal breath recharges.
c05401
DM: Uh [laughs]
c05402
Unknown: I'm just gonna sit tight.
c05403
DM: Well [laughs]
c05404
Unknown: [laughs]
c05405
DM: Um, two more big cracks appear, and it
c05406
DM: f- roars up and launches a massive punch at Seeker.
c05407
Unknown: Yay.
c05408
DM: That's a 19, so that...
c05409
DM: Uh, sorry, a 19 on the die, so that hits.
c05410
Delwath: Yeah, it's a 14. These guys don't have great AC.
c05411
DM: Um, and-
c05412
Unknown: 14 AC, yeah
c05413
DM: You take 14 points of bludgeoning and zero points of acid from the pseudopod.
c05414
Seeker: So with, with resistance to bludgeoning?
c05415
Delwath: It's 14 already after now.
c05416
Unknown: No.
c05417
Unknown: So seven.
c05418
DM: So
c05419
DM: seven.
c05420
Seeker: Ah. So I take seven off of my 328.
c05421
Unknown: [laughs]
c05422
Delwath: [laughs] Yeah. So you, but you do have to make a con save.
c05423
Unknown: [coughs] Oh, shit, yeah.
c05424
Delwath: That's okay. You only have to roll a...
c05425
DM: You actually-
c05426
Delwath: Actually, you can't fail
c05427
DM: Do they have... What do they have, plus?
c05428
Unknown: 10.
c05429
DM: So you can't fail. You don't have to make a con save.
c05430
Unknown: Wait, why did I-
c05431
DM: 'Cause if you roll a one, it's 11, and you only have to beat a 10.
c05432
Seeker: Because of the constitution-
c05433
Delwath: The con is plus 10
c05434
Seeker: ... of the leviathan.
c05435
Delwath: Of the leviathan. It has to do-
c05436
Unknown: See, that seems critical [laughs].
c05437
Delwath: It has to do more-
c05438
DM: That's very true
c05439
Delwath: ... oh, that's a good point. It has to do more than 22 damage for you to have to roll a con save.
c05440
DM: 20, which is tough when you're resistant.
c05441
Delwath: With resistance.
c05442
DM: Yes.
c05443
Delwath: Yeah. Okay, uh.
c05444
Unknown: That's a good combo.
c05445
DM: That was a legendary, so Delwath is up.
c05446
Unknown: Yeah, it's great.
c05447
Delwath: Okay, Delwath's turn. I'm gonna, I'm gonna tidal wave again.
c05448
Unknown: Now-
c05449
Kenzo: Why aren't you tidal waving?
c05450
Unknown: Well-
c05451
DM: Spells are better.
c05452
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c05453
Delwath: Delweth can't cast spells. I can cast spells.
c05454
Unknown: Ah, got it, got it.
c05455
Seeker: And it's, and it's a strength save, and also it's gonna hit everybody.
c05456
DM: It's very good at strength saves.
c05457
Delwath: No, I just make it right he- the- they're still flying, right?
c05458
Kenzo: I don't know if we're still flying.
c05459
Delwath: Well, I'll make the-
c05460
Unknown: I'm gonna do-
c05461
Delwath: I'll make the tidal wave appear here and go that way.
c05462
Delwath: There we go. That's great.
c05463
DM: That you can do.
c05464
Unknown: Great.
c05465
Seeker: Oh, right. I think I misread it at first.
c05466
Seeker: You can make it small if you want to.
c05467
DM: Yeah.
c05468
Seeker: So, so it's not too big.
c05469
Unknown: Right.
c05470
Unknown: Tidal wave.
c05471
DM: So that's a strength save?
c05472
Delwath: Yeah, DC 24 strength save.
c05473
Delwath: I mean, DC 24 is a little bit tough, even if it's a plus 10.
c05474
Unknown: [laughs]
c05475
DM: Uh, yeah, it rolled a two.
c05476
Unknown: Okay.
c05477
DM: So that's only a 16.
c05478
Kenzo: I'm still not getting super, super psyched about the, uh, because of his face and that, so that's not great.
c05479
Unknown: That's fair. I mean, it's...
c05480
DM: Yeah. So 7d12.
c05481
Seeker: It popped his collar and it's...
c05482
Unknown: [laughs]
c05483
Unknown: [laughs] I didn't do that for this, this character.
c05484
DM: That's five as well.
c05485
Kenzo: When he's attacking, he switches his face and it pops his collar.
c05486
DM: 10, 22, 32-
c05487
Unknown: He's angry
c05488
DM: ...
c05489
DM: 38 plus
c05490
Delwath: eight is, uh, 46.
c05491
DM: Oh, wait, sorry. It's gonna use a legendary resistance.
c05492
DM: So half of 46.
c05493
DM: Ugh.
c05494
Unknown: Uh...
c05495
Wellby: What's the pseudopod situation?
c05496
Delwath: Does it like wash away in the tidal wave?
c05497
Unknown: Yes.
c05498
DM: Yes.
c05499
Unknown: Great.
c05500
DM: And the ooze
c05501
DM: begins to bubble
c05502
DM: and split apart. [slimy sounds]
c05503
Kenzo: I like the sound effects.
c05504
DM: As
c05505
DM: with that blast...
c05506
DM: I made it too strong.
c05507
Unknown: [laughs]
c05508
c05509
DM: It falls to pieces and begins to drain away, crystallizing and hardening as you hit it.
c05510
Unknown: Oh, nice.
c05511
Unknown: Awesome.
c05512
DM: And there is a rumbling sound.
c05513
Unknown: No.
c05514
Wellby: Rumbling.
c05515
Kenzo: No rumbling.
c05516
DM: And the earth begins to shake.
c05517
Unknown: What?
c05518
Seeker: And we, we, uh-
c05519
DM: And what do you do?
c05520
Wellby: We go take a long rest [laughs].
c05521
Unknown: [laughs] Uh...
c05522
Seeker: Do you Leviathan?
c05523
Wellby: Well, uh, can I get out of the...
c05524
Wellby: I assume the-
c05525
DM: You're not restrained anymore. Yeah, it, uh...
c05526
Wellby: Oh.
c05527
DM: Um, actual- wow, [laughs] it actually hardens into crystal.
c05528
Wellby: Oh.
c05529
Kenzo: Kenzo goes over and breaks out-
c05530
Unknown: Well, well, well
c05531
Kenzo: ... breaks out the, the-
c05532
DM: Uh, yeah, but that's...
c05533
DM: Let me keep track of how long these things take you.
c05534
Delwath: Um-
c05535
DM: So anybody can free either one of them with a, with automatically with a help action, or you can break out as an action.
c05536
Delwath: Well, can I use a wedger action to break them out?
c05537
DM: Mm-hmm. Sure, you can wash it away.
c05538
Delwath: I have, I have a 27 strength.
c05539
DM: Yes. Yes, yes, yes.
c05540
Delwath: A big, the, the, the w- river comes and swooshes across you.
c05541
DM: Swooshes it away.
c05542
Delwath: Dissolving the acid with it.
c05543
DM: Yes.
c05544
Delwath: Ah. The crystal, taking the crystal.
c05545
Wellby: Refreshing.
c05546
Seeker: With a swish of your giant flipper.
c05547
Unknown: Yes.
c05548
Wellby: Wait, could you have done that when it was acid?
c05549
DM: No.
c05550
Wellby: That would've been nice.
c05551
Unknown: No.
c05552
DM: It... This is just a, this is just a color.
c05553
Wellby: All right.
c05554
DM: There's no mechanism for somebody to help you break out of-
c05555
Wellby: Got it
c05556
DM: ... restraint in this case.
c05557
DM: Sometimes there are-
c05558
Wellby: Right
c05559
DM: ... but this particular one, no.
c05560
Wellby: Yeah.
c05561
DM: So, um, you can, you can hear in the distance, like a faint cracking, crumbling sound, like stones and earth falling.
c05562
Delwath: Go towards it.
c05563
Delwath: I don't know. I'm not very smart.
c05564
Unknown: Uh...
c05565
Kenzo: How long does the leviathan last?
c05566
Unknown: It's an hour.
c05567
Unknown: Little bit of healing.
c05568
Delwath: No, but, but-
c05569
Unknown: Little bit of healing
c05570
Delwath: ... Delwath's going towards it [laughs].
c05571
Wellby: Healing?
c05572
Delwath: I guess I'll wait if every, if nobody is following.
c05573
Unknown: That would be-
c05574
Wellby: Healing, you don't have magic.
c05575
Unknown: No.
c05576
Wellby: More healing?
c05577
Seeker: I can cast another healing spell on you, yes.
c05578
Delwath: Uh, you used your ninth level slot.
c05579
Delwath: This is where, uh, power heal would sort of be helpful.
c05580
Seeker: Yeah, but I...
c05581
Delwath: But you're a leviathan.
c05582
Kenzo: Wish I could give you some, uh,
c05583
Kenzo: some healing stuff.
c05584
Wellby: Thanks. Thanks.
c05585
Kenzo: I gave you my p- my potion.
c05586
Wellby: Oh, you did. You did.
c05587
Seeker: I c- I could do another fifth level healing word.
c05588
Delwath: Do you have, you don't have a Q, you don't have any QRS, do you?
c05589
Wellby: I'm gaining a new appreciation for Kenzo's role as the person who just soaks up damage.
c05590
Unknown: [laughs]
c05591
Unknown: Yeah, right?
c05592
Wellby: Very different thing than he was doing.
c05593
Kenzo: I mean, dude, I'm so good at it now too, 'cause I have, I have the, the, that boon of healing thing I got.
c05594
Unknown: Right.
c05595
Kenzo: I have 10, I have 10 hit dice I can use as a bonus action.
c05596
Wellby: Wow.
c05597
Kenzo: 10, 10d10. I have a pool of 10d10s I can just roll whenever I want to gain more hit points.
c05598
Wellby: I have one more 10d10. It's like a win.
c05599
Delwath: Um, I'm wondering if I should turn back into Delwath.
c05600
Unknown: Eh.
c05601
c05602
Delwath: We'll see. I won't do it yet.
c05603
Kenzo: Well, the next thing is the, uh-
c05604
Seeker: All right. I'm gonna do the healing word, right?
c05605
Kenzo: I mean, we still got an hour.
c05606
Wellby: I can use another healing word.
c05607
Kenzo: 'Cause I... The ooze is still gonna be the same thing.
c05608
Wellby: It's gonna be a 10, four plus-
c05609
Kenzo: So this has been very useful from, uh-
c05610
Kenzo: 10, four plus five
c05611
Kenzo: ... yeah. Oh, I got a plus here.
c05612
Unknown: Yeah.
c05613
Unknown: 32.
c05614
Unknown: Yeah, that's, that is something.
c05615
Kenzo: Being, like, essentially immune to it.
c05616
DM: Cracked.
c05617
Kenzo: It's very useful Fuck.
c05618
Unknown: Uh,
c05619
Kenzo: well, 'cause the river connects into the cistern, right?
c05620
Kenzo: Does that close in there somehow?
c05621
Unknown: Yeah.
c05622
Kenzo: Can we follow the tendril?
c05623
Unknown: Wow.
c05624
DM: Well, you washed it away. It's-
c05625
Unknown: Well, I know, but the tendril-
c05626
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. It's crystal-
c05627
Kenzo: ... it's reaching in this, you know, it's crystallized.
c05628
DM: Yeah.
c05629
Unknown: Yeah.
c05630
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c05631
Kenzo: Let- let's follow the crystal tendril.
c05632
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c05633
Unknown: See where it leads.
c05634
Seeker: Are, are we still... Are we going into the ash storm?
c05635
DM: Yeah. You're, you're in the ash st- You're...
c05636
DM: Right now, you're in the ash storm. Your visibility is only 30 feet.
c05637
Kenzo: But everybody's immune to all the stuff.
c05638
Unknown: Yes.
c05639
DM: You're-
c05640
Seeker: As long as we s- We have to stay leviathan.
c05641
Unknown: No, no. Heroes' Feast makes you immune to poison.
c05642
Unknown: Heroes' Feast.
c05643
Seeker: Oh, Heroes' Feast makes you immune to poison.
c05644
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. Let's, uh, let's follow the river.
c05645
Kenzo: Let's stay in the river. Let's... 'Cause while you guys are still leviathans, let's, let's, let's flow, let's flow with the, with the-
c05646
Delwath: Is there like another connection from the river that this was feeding through?
c05647
Kenzo: Into the cistern.
c05648
Delwath: Into the cistern?
c05649
DM: Uh, wait, hold on.
c05650
DM: What do you mean?
c05651
DM: Like-
c05652
Kenzo: We- we're leaving at 4:30?
c05653
Unknown: Yeah.
c05654
DM: Yeah.
c05655
Unknown: Okay.
c05656
Unknown: Where...
c05657
Unknown: So along the river, was there...
c05658
Delwath: We're wondering where the cistern f- was fed from the river.
c05659
Delwath: Like, is there a spot along the river where the cistern would've been fed?
c05660
DM: Uh,
c05661
DM: at the moment, n- I mean, anything that w- did used to connect them has collapsed.
c05662
Delwath: But is there, like, a... So there's not really a,
c05663
Delwath: there's not really a spot. So to follow the tendril would be over land, follow the tendril close to the-
c05664
DM: It's over land, yeah, yeah.
c05665
Delwath: We're literally going to the well.
c05666
DM: That's the direction it's heading, yeah.
c05667
Kenzo: Let's just fucking go to the well.
c05668
Unknown: Yeah.
c05669
Kenzo: And that's where, that's where this has all gotta go anyways, right?
c05670
Kenzo: We gotta go down into the, into the well, down into the fucking-
c05671
Wellby: Yeah, but could conceivably if we go to the well, if there's still two of these out there and one of them's in the well-
c05672
Delwath: We might have to fight two
c05673
Wellby: ... we wanna fight the other one not in the well, so that we only have to fight one in the well.
c05674
Kenzo: Good point. Good point.
c05675
Delwath: Well, can Kenzo...
c05676
Kenzo: do his rogue action?
c05677
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Te- Tim, what's going on?
c05678
DM: Yeah, that's an action. Um, you have this...
c05679
DM: You've done it once before, so it takes a ki, but I think you have plenty of ki left.
c05680
Kenzo: I do. And, and next time we roll initiative-
c05681
DM: And roll initiative-
c05682
Unknown: ... you'll all get it back
c05683
DM: ... you'll get it all back. Um,
c05684
DM: so you... There never was three.
c05685
Kenzo: Yeah, but just, but just the, the concentration, is it, is it still those two?
c05686
DM: Um-
c05687
Kenzo: Is... Where, where are they basically?
c05688
DM: Uh, everything is centered on the well right now.
c05689
Kenzo: Great. Let's go to the well.
c05690
Wellby: Let's go to the well.
c05691
Unknown: Ugh.
c05692
Seeker: So it's sort of attracting.
c05693
Unknown: Yeah.
c05694
Kenzo: So it's gonna be like a fucking 2,000 hit point...
c05695
Unknown: Yep. [laughs]
c05696
Wellby: Do we have any more healing potions hanging around?
c05697
Kenzo: I'll give you whatever I have. Yeah.
c05698
Unknown: Oh, I have-
c05699
Wellby: I've used my other-
c05700
Seeker: I have one, but it's inside my blubber.
c05701
Unknown: [laughs] I have one, but it's also...
c05702
Kenzo: It's inside my blubber.
c05703
Unknown: We're not gonna... But no, we're made of water.
c05704
DM: Your... But your items are also all made of water.
c05705
Delwath: I know. The leviathan's a water elemental.
c05706
Unknown: I didn't know that.
c05707
Seeker: Oh, I have a four-
c05708
Delwath: That's why it can get, it, it can go through a space as small-
c05709
Unknown: I have four potions of greater healing
c05710
DM: ... as small as an inch 'cause it-
c05711
Wellby: Can I get two of those?
c05712
Unknown: Yeah, of course.
c05713
Unknown: Yeah
c05714
Delwath: ... because it's, it's a, it's a sea serpent, but it's shaped of wa-
c05715
Unknown: That's, uh-
c05716
Delwath: It's actually a water elemental, the leviathan
c05717
Kenzo: ... 4d4 plus 4. 4d4 plus 4, so it's 8d4 plus 8.
c05718
DM: [coughs]
c05719
Kenzo: 8d4 plus 8.
c05720
Wellby: All right, 27. Good.
c05721
Wellby: That gets me back.
c05722
Kenzo: I... Do you not actually take the last two?
c05723
Kenzo: We're not gonna rest again until-
c05724
Wellby: Yeah, but what if, like, uh-
c05725
Kenzo: Keep a couple for-
c05726
Wellby: Yeah. All right.
c05727
Unknown: For, for what?
c05728
DM: Oh, you can... I, I-
c05729
Delwath: Keep a couple, but maybe don't use them all.
c05730
DM: He can burn his action, roll a 1d10.
c05731
Delwath: Well, why not? I have no reason not to.
c05732
Wellby: Yeah. I keep one more just in case, like, I'm the last person surviving.
c05733
Unknown: Dude, I'll give you a-
c05734
Kenzo: Dude, I'll give you, I'll give you the other two that I have and you can drink 'em la- drink 'em whenever you want.
c05735
Wellby: All right.
c05736
Unknown: All right?
c05737
Wellby: I'm gonna drink one now and keep one.
c05738
Unknown: Okay.
c05739
DM: So you rush forward.
c05740
Unknown: Great. We're gonna
c05741
DM: Running towards the,
c05742
DM: uh, with these two water creatures following, running towards the,
c05743
DM: um,
c05744
DM: the center. You break out through the storm and you see that the center of this plaza has partially collapsed.
c05745
DM: And in the center
c05746
DM: is, like, a 400-foot-long ooze.
c05747
Unknown: What?
c05748
Unknown: Whoa.
c05749
Kenzo: Wait, th- this is not the well, this is, this is here.
c05750
DM: No, the cen- the plaza has collapsed.
c05751
Unknown: Oh.
c05752
DM: So it's a slope down.
c05753
Wellby: Into the cistern.
c05754
Delwath: Into the well.
c05755
DM: Into the cistern.
c05756
Unknown: Cool.
c05757
DM: And emerging out of it is this massive...
c05758
DM: Not sure actually that battle maps are gonna be that useful here.
c05759
Unknown: Come on.
c05760
DM: This thing, this is, like-
c05761
Kenzo: I'm into the Lego battle map
c05762
DM: ... 400 feet across.
c05763
Wellby: Are we in the eye of the storm right now?
c05764
DM: You've just emerged out from the eye of the storm.
c05765
DM: And it's, like, it's writhing, like-
c05766
Unknown: Hey, hey
c05767
DM: ... in anger.
c05768
Kenzo: Um, you, you took my staff.
c05769
DM: [laughs] Looming, like, bits of it looming up, grabbing, um...
c05770
Unknown: Watch the step
c05771
Wellby: Do you want to Counterbalance?
c05772
Unknown: Uh,
c05773
Seeker: I'm seeing if there's a way to add this in, in the...
c05774
Unknown: Put it at the b- You'd have to put it at the bottom.
c05775
DM: [coughs]
c05776
Unknown: Oh, that's true. That's true.
c05777
Delwath: [laughs] Yeah, you could print that, right?
c05778
Unknown: Yeah.
c05779
Wellby: Yeah.
c05780
Unknown: Nice.
c05781
DM: It's stuck. [laughs]
c05782
Kenzo: All right. Now we're talking.
c05783
Kenzo: [laughs] I've just got a new staff.
c05784
Seeker: [laughs] All right, all right, all right.
c05785
Kenzo: Okay. [laughs] Now we're, now we're getting somewhere.
c05786
Unknown: [laughs]
c05787
DM: Okay, so.
c05788
Unknown: Oh,
c05789
Unknown: shit.
c05790
DM: You rush forward, you emerge out of the storm of ash, and you see this,
c05791
DM: like, collops- collapsed plaza.
c05792
DM: So it, like, slopes down.
c05793
DM: There's like a gradient slope down to the bottom.
c05794
DM: And at the... So just the, like, ring of the plaza is still stable.
c05795
DM: You still see those columns and the, and the, like, partial cover of the fallen, um,
c05796
DM: [laughs] of the fallen,
c05797
DM: uh, of the fallen market.
c05798
DM: But this, towards the river, the entire ground is collapsed and it just slopes down to the bottom of the cistern At which there's this m- like, just utterly enormous roiling
c05799
DM: mass of multicolored ooze bubbling and raging and beginning to climb out and rush forwards towards you.
c05800
Delwath: Can we... Is there like, um,
c05801
Delwath: is there still like the
c05802
Delwath: center down there somewhere thing that we saw earlier?
c05803
Delwath: Can we tell?
c05804
DM: You can't see it.
c05805
Unknown: Oh.
c05806
DM: It's probably somewhere inside the ooze.
c05807
Delwath: So we have to fight our way through the ooze to that magical nodule.
c05808
Delwath: It probably has like basically infinite hit points.
c05809
Unknown: Oh.
c05810
DM: The nodule or this thing?
c05811
Delwath: Yeah, the nodule. We probably have to find the nodule.
c05812
Wellby: [coughs] Uh, c- uh, can Arrow discover the nodule?
c05813
DM: Okay.
c05814
DM: Uh, I think we should stop here though, because it's 4:15.
c05815
DM: We could take a few minutes to do a little bit of dinner prep and then go see the sunset.
c05816
Unknown: Sounds like a plan.
c05817
DM: Yeah, 'cause I don't wanna, like, just...
c05818
DM: I mean, you're gonna roll initiative as the first thing we do.
c05819
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c05820
DM: I don't wanna just start-
c05821
Kenzo: Totally, totally, totally.
c05822
Unknown: Yeah.
c05823
Seeker: How are we gonna fight something so large?
c05824
Seeker: This is ridiculous. I like it.
c05825
Delwath: I, I suspect our strategy has gotta be, it probably has effectively unlimited hit points.
c05826
Unknown: Yeah.
c05827
Delwath: So I doubt it's mechanically useful to just try and like kill the various little bits, right?
c05828
Delwath: We probably have to get to the,
c05829
Unknown: the-
c05830
Seeker: So as leviathans, we can swim through it.
c05831
Unknown: Yeah.
c05832
Seeker: I guess.
c05833
Unknown: [coughs] I mean...
c05834
Wellby: It's easier through water.
c05835
Seeker: Is the, is the nodule thing...
c05836
Wellby: Like, we could, I don't know, force cage it and then-
c05837
Unknown: The nodule?
c05838
Wellby: ... with ourselves on the inside with the nodule to keep the rest of the leviathan out maybe?
c05839
Unknown: How far down is the nodule?
c05840
DM: I mean-
c05841
Unknown: Through the rest of the ooze
c05842
DM: ... it's,
c05843
DM: it's like in the middle, like it's in the middle of this bubbling mass of ooze, right?
c05844
Kenzo: Of, it's in the middle of this?
c05845
DM: Yeah.
c05846
Unknown: This thing.
c05847
Kenzo: I, I, I think, I think we might just have to like do like a couple thousand points of damage.
c05848
Delwath: Well, I think, I think Seeker and I as leviathans should like head towards the nodule.
c05849
DM: [coughs]
c05850
Unknown: Yeah.
c05851
Unknown: Right?
c05852
Kenzo: I mean, sure. I can g- I can join you guys.
c05853
Kenzo: I'm an astral being.
c05854
Wellby: I can hang out at a safe distance [laughs].
c05855
DM: [laughs]
c05856
Seeker: You'll soak up the damage [laughs].
c05857
Unknown: Oh my God. Just soak up the damage.
c05858
Kenzo: Yeah. You stay, you stay up top.
c05859
Unknown: I'll take, I'll take the hits. I'll take the hits.
c05860
Kenzo: You, you shoot some arrows.
c05861
Kenzo: Yeah, just hit some arrows.
c05862
Seeker: [laughs] You're our tank today.
c05863
Delwath: Like, that seems like maybe the right move, is to try and move through the mass towards the nodule.
c05864
Seeker: But, um, what are we gonna do to the nodule once we find it?
c05865
Seeker: I don't know if this is cooperative activity.
c05866
Unknown: Well, I guess we'll decide when we get there.
c05867
DM: Yeah.
c05868
DM: Force cage is not a crazy idea.
c05869
DM: What would force cage accomplish?
c05870
DM: L- nothing whatsoever at all.
c05871
Unknown: We could-
c05872
DM: It would just make it harder for you to destroy it.
c05873
Wellby: If we were on the inside though, we could keep the rest of the leviathan...
c05874
Delwath: Yeah. No, that's true.
c05875
Unknown: Okay.
c05876
DM: But it's probably not that useful because...
c05877
Unknown: Yeah.
c05878
c05879
Seeker: But maybe we could... It would buy us time to do imprisonment or something like that.
c05880
Unknown: Oh, wow, this is gonna be good.
c05881
Delwath: Or we just destroy it somehow.
c05882
Unknown: Banish it.
c05883
Seeker: Or destroy it somehow.
c05884
Unknown: Right.
c05885
Delwath: I mean, maybe if we just attack it.
c05886
Unknown: [coughs]
c05887
Unknown: Sure.
c05888
Wellby: The nodule thing is a part of it.
c05889
Wellby: It's not, like, a...
c05890
Unknown: It's a part.
c05891
Wellby: It's not like something that's inside. It's like an organ or something.
c05892
Unknown: Yeah.
c05893
c05894
Delwath: So I mean, we could try and just cut our way to the...
c05895
Delwath: Like, cut a path to the nodule kind of.
c05896
Unknown: [laughs]
c05897
Unknown: [laughs] So
c05898
Kenzo: s- so don't... Keep talking. Don't pay attention to me [laughs].
c05899
Unknown: [laughs]
c05900
Kenzo: This, this is the group photo that we all, we all really wanted [laughs].
c05901
Unknown: Everybody on Kenzo's...
c05902
Unknown: [laughs] Okay.
c05903
Unknown: That's a little silly.
c05904
DM: Um, what was our dinner plans for tonight?
c05905
Kenzo: Stop being silly.
c05906
Unknown: We are being silly.
c05907
Unknown: Chicken,
c05908
Unknown: mushrooms-